Yoast: Do you know, the Yoast SEO,
plugin, the red, orange, and green
feedback buttons that help you
optimize your posts for the web.
It runs on millions of websites.
We tried to make SEO understandable
and accessible to everyone.
Nexcess: Oh great.
My website crashed.
I give up.
Don't give up on your dreams.
Jordan, who are you?
It's me.
You from the future.
Your professional website
is not at a breach.
You just need next with nexus managed
hosting, you get lightening pass load
times built-in performance monitoring
and updates, and always awesome support.
24 7 365 for all your projects.
Whoa.
Yeah.
Weglot: Discover Weglot the simple
translation solution for your website.
All you have to do is add Weglot to
your website, select the languages
that you need, and that's it.
Your website is now available
in multiple languages
Bluehost: Who says building an
online store has to be hard.
With Bluehost website
it's more than just easy.
It's tell us your thing and smart
AI will take it from there easy.
It's WooCommerce friendly.
So you can add one, of these,
or swap this for that easy.
It's set up shop in minutes
with unlimited products.
Easy.
Whether you sell boots, books
or bowls, it's create an online
store with Bluehost, easy build
beyond boundaries with Bluehost.
Tom Stinson: Good day WordFest.
I am absolutely thrilled to have the
opportunity to share with you today.
Whether you are watching live
or catching up at a later date,
I'm thrilled to be with you.
My name is Tom.
I live on the sunshine coast in
beautiful Australia with my wife,
Ellie, and we have three wonderful
children who drive us completely mad.
And adult called peanut who is
extremely lazy, even for a whip.
It, I also get the opportunity to
help shape and strive to create
an exceptional experience for the
community members of XWP today.
Uh, I want to share about a topic
that I'm really passionate about.
One that I hope everyone will be
able to connect with a topic that
I'm hopeful will encourage it.
To continue moving in a positive direction
with how we approach, define and handle
the term leadership in the remote space.
I've titled my talk today.
Remote leadership, how to lead humans in
a way that makes it okay to feel human.
I remember when I first stepped into a
leadership role at one of my first jobs,
not XWP, my manager pulled me aside.
Uh, just remember Tom, you're no
longer one of just, you know, only
one of the boys, unfortunately.
Yes, it was a very male dominant place.
But the comment I had it, a couple of
internal reactions to this, firstly, a
sense of understanding as in I understood
what they were trying to say that with
leadership, there is a new range of
responsibility with new expectations.
I couldn't just continue in the
same manner as I had previously,
there was a shift expected, but
then I had also another reaction.
And then this one was an ease about it.
Didn't really like the idea that
my relationships had to change,
that there was now an expected gap
between those who I once worked with
and who I was now expected to lead.
And this second reaction has stuck
with me for years since that moment.
Why do we have to have this
degree of separation between
people that we are working with?
The relational side of the
relationship is now irrelevant.
And the relationship is now solely based
on your position or your role, your title.
I wonder if you've been in a similar
situation where you find the dynamics
of relationships have been changed
because of a change to title or role
either to you or someone else say,
I think the problem is that we we've
lived in a world where unfortunately,
dominantly, titles and roles have been
the cornerstone of the work experience.
With the value of a person at work
is looped through the eyes of their
role, their KPIs and their outcomes.
And to be fair, like on paper,
I guess that makes sense.
But if there's one thing I hope we can
all agree on, there's a big difference
between the paper version of life in life.
My personal belief and hope is that
there is a real shift towards that.
Cornerstone becoming the makeup
and values of the individual.
I believe that with the rising prominence
of remote work, many, many businesses
organizations, startups, actioning
on the realization that people cannot
be looked at as just titles roles.
The cogs of a machine, but they
must be viewed and treated as
individuals that are human beings.
This is because the preexisting
blurred lines of work in
life are becoming clearer.
And then as I said, lines, plural,
because I don't think there is just
one line with work and then life.
And there's all the twined.
It's a mess.
The truth is.
Um, more than ever.
The toll of life is visibly affecting
work and that's not a negative.
There's been many moments throughout
history where the toll of life has
been overwhelmed, overwhelming, but
there is barely been a response.
The difference today, I believe is that
we are all seeing inside lives and homes.
Of everyone else during these
calls that are happening.
And we actually visibly
seen the tall in play.
So the natural effect, and this is
why it perhaps isn't all negative
is that the need to acknowledge
this, the effects of light.
And work.
So all out humanity is growing in further
in force and this shift will continue
to happen as more and more of us take
responsibility for it, just because we
may not have a leadership role within
the structure of an organization.
That doesn't mean we can't
be a leader for change.
Those of us that are, and have been
working in a remote freelance type of
arrangement for a while now, I'm hoping
we've been privileged to experience
being treated and seen as human beings.
I believe several remote companies
either began because of the notion
that we can be live, work, wherever
it makes sense for the individually.
Or either because a company sought
after the diverse contributions that
come from having team members all
around the world, bringing their
culture, their diverse outlook to
the team, both of these recognize and
celebrate the individuality of humans.
There are other reasons for
being in the remote space.
I know.
And even if initially the intentions
were good doesn't mean they still are.
Yeah.
In the remote space, we are well
positioned to lead in a way that
respects values and promotes being human.
And this is what I specifically
want to speak about today.
A leader's role is to make it
feel okay to be, and feel here.
And to clarify, I don't want to throw
the baby out with the bath water roles.
KPIs outcomes are vitally important.
Good leadership is connecting where
we want to go to the understanding
of the individual with that
individual's capabilities and
limitations are accounted for.
And that is the same as if you
were leading down, up or around.
So, what does it mean to be human?
Well, technically you don't need to do
anything to be human, but I think what
it means to be in, uh, an ecosystem with
humans to be working, living, supporting
celebrate together is to first acknowledge
and then learn to work with those.
That unite us and those things
that are unique to all of us.
Now that could be a whole list of things
that are unite or are unique to us.
But I just want to focus on two key points
for each and I'm going to be honest.
I feel these, these are pretty basic,
but I also feel they get forgotten a lot.
So I'm goona to start with
the things that united us.
And they are that we are emotional
and intelligent beings, emotions.
They drive us and lead us both
consciously and unconsciously.
There's so much wonderful research
and evidence today about the, how
the emotional side of us is one
of the leading factors in how we
make decisions, how we respond to
circumstances and how we live out.
So as a leader or team member,
we need to remind ourselves daily
that who we are working alongside
of people coming together with a
whole range of emotional statuses.
So our leaders response is that
they have to, and I repeat, they
have to take ownership of the
emotional atmosphere they created.
With all these emotions and
everybody bringing it in, we
need to take responsibility for
the atmosphere that we create.
And it's no longer acceptable
to expect the individuals leave
their emotions at the, at the
metaphorical door as they enter work.
It is no longer acceptable
to blame an individual for
the emotional response that.
A leader has to take ownership
and responsibility for the
emotional atmosphere they create.
And that needs to be a safe place
where individuals feel their
emotions are valid and respected
a few things.
I think we can do to put into
practice to help us with this.
The first thing is, um, learn about
empathy and going beyond that is
learning about the difference between
empathy and sympathy in the book.
Uh, practical empathy, the author
Indy young says empathy is about
understanding how another person thinks
and acknowledging their reasoning
and emotions as valid, even if they
differ from your own understanding.
Am I going to stand?
That can be tough to be able to
understand and acknowledge the
reasoning behind their emotions
and not just say, okay, that's on.
I get that, but understand
that they are valid.
And I said, that can be tough,
but a leader's job is to
step into where it's tough.
And make it easier path for the next
person by acknowledging someone's
current situation and their emotions,
it will help create and strengthen
a positive emotional atmosphere.
A few other things simply be nice.
Love people over the process.
Life is too short to fall
in love with the process.
Fall in love with people.
One thing I have learned through many,
many failed, uh, moments in my own
leadership is this is about that is
that generally when, uh, I lost my nerve
or my emotions have risen to the top.
It's barely been about that very moment
or what is taking place right there.
And then, but it's because something
else has been going on in the background
and this spark, or this moment has
brought out all the emotion and that poor
person on the receiving end has no idea.
What's just happened.
See, this is actually about that.
And it happens more than you think.
And for ourselves, as, as, as leaders,
we need to ask and investigate moments
like these to ensure we fully grasp
the situation, whether it's happening
to us or to somebody else so that
we can respond in the right way.
And we can only do that when emotions
are okay to be shared that they're
not all bottled up and then explode.
There is a positive atmosphere for
people to be who they are and feeling.
How they are.
We are all emotional beings as
leaders in the remote space.
We need to remind them focus on this
because with the disconnect of human
interaction, with being all around the
world with not physically seeing somebody
in the office, it is far too easy to
forget and to not learn about this.
So our response is to learn everything.
It's not natural.
That actually needs to be a step to
learn about it and put it into practice.
So that first thing is
that we are emotional.
The second thing that unites us is
that we are all intelligent beings.
This means that we are constantly
learning and taking on new aspects
to consider and apply to our work.
And.
As a leader, we need to remind
ourselves that those we serve our team,
uh, growing and expanding every day
from their wins and their failures.
They are building upon their knowledge
and how to apply themselves in the future.
A leader is responsible for their,
the ease of sharing knowledge and
its application within a team,
as well as a de identifying gaps.
And if needed where extra possible
outside support is needed.
So a few things to help us with this,
uh, li uh, remote leaders response.
I believe we should come with
the mindset that we want to raise
leaders as if, as a default, don't
give tasks, give responsibility.
Tasks mean stay in your lane.
The things that, you know, the things
that I've seen you be able to do,
I'm just wanting you to do that.
Do that task responsibility means explore.
Add your perspective to the solution.
Give the opportunity for people to
handle the responsibility of something
and learn what they can achieve.
Be on the confined expectations.
And you will raise leaders.
This will help close those gaps before
you have to look internally, externally,
look internally, and for this as
leaders, we need to learn about trust.
And again, in the remote space,
trust can be difficult because you
can't, you can't sneak over to their
desk to see how things are going.
You can't be just checking in and it's,
it's natural to fear what we can't see.
I remember when I, uh, I went
on a holiday to venowado.
And I went snorkeling on this coral
reef and it was, it was gorgeous.
It was beautiful, the colors
of the fish and the coral.
And it was the most amazing experience,
but I slammed to the edge and, and
it just dropped off into the depths.
And I remember peering over and watching
the water go that, that darker blue
down to deep, deep black and my chest
just seemed to, you know, contract.
It was like this, this field.
And it was because of the
unknown it's because I couldn't
see what was down there.
And when there is something that
is unknown on natural reaction
is to be fearful of it, fearful
of what could be done there.
And we generally go to
the worst case scenario.
And so when we can't see things, we fear.
That they will not work out.
And we can fear that the floors of,
of our people and we all have flaws.
We fear that they will be the defining
moment or aspect of that job or that
task or that project or responsibility.
And then not only hurts the person
that hurts us as well, but in that
regard, giving tasks can seem easier.
However, I wanted to share a few,
uh, quotes on the value of trusting
people by some individuals who
are far more qualified than I am.
Jim Collins quoting his, his close
mentor and co-author builders here.
He says, look.
Think of it as upside and downside.
Here's the wager, what's the upside.
If you to take the bit of mistrust,
well, you'll maybe prevent yourself from
having one of those hurtful experiences.
And what's the downside.
The downside is trustworthy people.
You will lose them.
And the upside to trusting people
is when you find the trustworthy
people, they will rise to.
If you've ever considered the possibility
that not everybody is one or the other,
but because you trust them at that
outset, they are more likely to become
trustworthy because you trust them.
I think it's a, it's a beautiful quote.
And every time I read it, I
think I want to give people
the opportunity to rise to it.
Simon Sinek.
One of the greatest voices on leadership
today, in my opinion, he says a team is
not a group of people who work together.
A team is a group of people
who trust each other.
It goes on to say, there are only
two ways to influence human behavior.
You can manipulate it
or you can inspire it.
See fear, suffocates creativity.
Honesty loyalty, wellbeing and
growth fear will suffocate the
collaboration of intelligent beings.
Yet trust is one of the core
principles of creating an environment
that is inspired and prepared to
rise to the challenge it faces.
And just on a side note,
I just want to say.
Nothing quite inspires and says,
I trust you like forcing screen
recording surveillance on your team.
And I hope that you're picking up
that I'm joking, strip it all back.
We are all emotional
and intelligent beings.
And as a leader, we need to not
only identify that within ourselves.
But recognize that within those
that we serve as leaders as well.
So we look at the things that unite
us more to look at a couple of
things that are unique to us as well.
And they are that we are diverse
and that we are at different
stages, looking at diverse.
We no longer just have multicultural
and diverse hubs within largest
towns or cities in the remote world.
We are multicultural and diverse.
There are no more boundaries to this.
We have a real opportunity to
lead the way in what work should
look like to be inclusive.
Provided quality.
Diverse to me to be human is to
embrace diversity, remote leaders,
response, and reminded that a
leader doesn't need a title.
But I think a leader's response to
this is, is to learn again, empathy.
Empathy is at the core of.
To learn about another person's point
of view to learn about how someone
reacts and why they're reacting
and why they feel the way they do.
And the actions we can take on is
firstly, to assess the things that
we are responsible for and ask
ourselves, how can I be an advocate
for diversity, equality and inclusion.
And that, that, that that's, I, I know
that doesn't sound like I'm answering
the question, but I feel like the first
thing we need to do is ask ourselves
that because it all starts with us.
And to be honest, I'm not going to pretend
that I'm an expert on this topic at all.
You know, I'm a white middle-class
male raised in a Western
country, however, I'm on a.
And I'm going to be asking questions
and exploring this topic so that I can
unlearn a whole lot of things and then
learn how I can be a better human.
And I believe that if you are a
human leader in the remote space, you
should, at the very least do likewise.
Secondly, what we can do is plan.
On how we're going to be an advocate
for change and lead up in this area,
because I can promise you if you
think that this is something that is
someone else's responsibility, then
you are hiding and lead is don't hide
in embracing the diversity
of your team is, is magic.
Allowing everyone, the chance to speak
into an ad, their perspectives only
multiplies the experience and to do
this, as I said, learn empathy, pause,
and listen to your fellow humans at SWP.
One of our most meaningful
initiatives, our home.
These are, uh, groups, uh,
designed to provide connection and
support to our community members.
Um, in a real casual setting, you
know, the, the groups vary in size
and it made up of team members in
similar time zones yet from varying
places, countries, backgrounds.
COVID.
And these home-based is they help our
community members to build friendships,
providing a network for them to,
uh, help each other in, in personal
and professional growth, but also
to learn about each other's cultures
and to strengthen our community
and our overall culture on vexed w.
It's a wonderful place to be able to
open up your life and to share your
stories and listen to other people,
to, to journey with them, to celebrate
with them, to mourn with them, to pick
each other up, to, to cheer them on.
And it impacts our whole
working environment.
A remote leader needs to embrace
and be an advocate for diversity.
We are in the box seats to show the world
how humans can and should work together.
The second point I want to talk about
the things that are unique to us
is that we're at different stages.
And I believe that this sign
that goes under the radar.
Not just working with different
experiences that are available, but
also with the different life stages.
I think typically with, at office work,
it would be quite common to find people
who are in the same stages of life, in
the same roles, with the same level of
experience, but with remote work, The
variety of stages can be vastly different.
A small example, you know, the team
I get to work with, we have two
highly skilled mothers who have young
children and are still breastfeeding.
A female who is new to the industry
after a career change, a father who
has spent the majority of the last two
years in hospital with his daughter, a
female who is a digital nomad with her.
A mother who has been navigating
a career change and, uh, doing
at-home learning with her teenagers,
a father who is homeschooling his
young children in the mountains.
And then another who've really
located near some ski fields with
his family, just within our team.
We have many different stages of
personal and work life records.
And I'm so thrilled that the life
choices and situations of my teammates
and not considered a hindrance to
their work or ability, but actually
it is an enriching benefit to
who we are and what we can offer.
So how can a remote leader
respond to this thing?
It is about embracing the different.
Of experiences equally and adjust your
expectations to allow for multiple stages.
It doesn't weaken, it enhances your team.
So again, it it's about learning
trust about saying, you know what?
I may not understand your stage.
I know may not be there.
I don't know about your experience,
but I'm going to place trust in
you to add to this community.
The diversity in different stages
that are on offer in the remote space
can allow us to lead in a new way
and break down some old irrelevant
walls that have been pulled up.
So tired.
I wanted to talk about that.
A leader's role is to make it feel okay.
To be human.
Okay.
And the things that unite us, but also in
the uniqueness that we bring, the things
that unite us were that were emotional.
And as a leader, ask yourself, how
can I create a positive emotional
atmosphere and learn about empathy?
The second thing is that we're in trouble.
Ask yourself, how can I
encourage collaboration?
And the application of
knowledge learn about trust?
The things that are unique
is that we are diverse.
Ask yourself, how can I be an advocate for
diversity, equality and inclusion, learn
empathy, and we're in different stages.
Uh, ask yourself, how do the
differences of the team bring new
perspectives and insights learn trust?
When my daughter was three months old,
um, we had to take her to hospital because
of an infection soon found out it was
meningitis, which is a serious infection.
The.
Which was going to resolve my
wife and Molly, having to stay
in hospital for six weeks.
And I would be at home without all
the two, while the nurses were doing
a routine check, they found a lump
in her abdomen, long story short
after tests and surgery, we found
that she had aggressive neuroblastoma
cancer and with treatment, she was
given a 50, 50 chance of surviving.
So four months old, she
started chemotherapy.
And a lot of other things I'm passionate
about treating and leading humans in a way
that makes it okay to feel human because
I was on the receiving end of this.
My work community offered all the
support that I and my family would need.
They allowed me space.
They allow me to talk.
They offered me support in so many
ways, but they also need that my
capacity was drastically reduced.
And the best way for me to work
was by give me lists of tasks
to do see responsibilities.
Weren't right.
For me at that time, the tasks were good.
I could come to work and
just work through them.
It felt like I was still contributing
back to my team, but then I was
able to be there for my family.
My daughter is now two
and a half years old.
The other month she was cleared
of all cancer and that we are so
excited as her parents to be at
lead her and love her in a life
that's going to be long and amazing.
But see, I, I was treated as a
human being where my emotions.
And stage work acknowledged,
accounted for and supported.
And all I wanted to do now is give back
so much to my community and workplace
because of how they treated me.
Do not think we need to focus just
on the processes and the outcomes.
Otherwise, the work you won't get done.
I, I promise you.
If you as a remote leader today,
if you create an environment that
respects and believes in humans, that
allows them to be okay with feeling
and being human, the work will get
done better than you had planned.
Thank you.
Cathy Tibbles: Thank you so much, Tom.
I had a whole bunch of questions.
All I was taking notes and then
you made me cry and then I'm really
glad that it was like a three
minute advertisement or sponsors.
How are you doing Misty?
Misty Combs: Very well.
Thank you.
Cathy Tibbles: Good Tom.
That was, um, amazing, I, I
feel like um, ok, I'm good.
Now.
ok bye, like, that was worth my 24 hour.
Like that's um, we just expanded
my team from like just me and two
friends that I've been working
with forever to seven of us.
And I feel like challenged to, to
do that and be the kind of place
where people can be themselves.
Tom Stinson: Yeah, it was, I think it's,
I think it's really powerful to, uh,
encourage everyone to be who they are
and to, to not have to be a different
person when they come online or step
into the office or wherever it is,
but, uh, to be validated and supported.
Cathy Tibbles: How often
have you given this message.
What is the response been?
Don't you get like, okay.
Millennial head, like,
Tom Stinson: uh, I mean, this
was the first time I've, I've
spoken at an event like this.
So, um, but this type of message.
I hope it's, it's a message that
I bring wherever I am and wherever
I interact with different people.
Yeah, I know that.
Yeah.
With the whole millennial, you
know, we talk about our, our
feelings and things like that.
And I guess that's why I wanted to share
at the end that, um, it doesn't weaken
us or we can our teams by acknowledging
and supporting and, and, uh, raising
awareness of the emotional side of us.
And I, it, rather than.
Creating an environment where people
are free to be who they are and,
uh, validated in how they are.
Uh, and that might change through
different seasons and different times.
Um, I think that strengthens it.
I truly do.
I think it just strengthens the team
and it strengthens that outcomes.
Um, where I, I mean, I know my,
my team a lot more now that I know
who they are, and I know how they
work in a better way because of.
Uh, more about them.
I know how I can encourage them.
I know how I can support them.
I know to how I, uh, I guess when looking
at them, I can see when they maybe
are stressed or how they are feeling
a moment and I can respond to that.
And I think it's just, you know, we
know that with our closest friends, you
know, we can see when, you know, uh, a
girlfriend or a boyfriend, uh, uh, not,
uh, not great and not in a great place.
And we, we can, we can be there for them.
Um, so I think, in work.
Yeah.
The home basis that we have.
Cathy Tibbles: Can you tell me
more about what that looks like?
Um, you zoom every night,
like is another meeting?
Tom Stinson: Yeah.
It's another meeting, another
meeting, which you'll love and hate.
Um, yeah, so we just create, um,
everyone that, uh, is in a home base.
They have essentially their own
slack channel, um, within our work.
And then they also can get to.
For about an hour a month, um, for on
a call and it's just a place to, to
connect so on slack, you know, often it's
sharing what they've been up to or, you
know, uh, cause we are remote company.
It's what our view is today.
Or if we're working from a different
location or going out, uh, walking
or, or seeing something, we just
sort of share these moments, um,
and interactions with these people.
Uh, on a, on a call it's, it's not
work-related, it's just a place to relax.
Maybe play a game together
or, or tell some stories or do
it some challenges together.
So just to, to build that connection
and to learn as I'm, as I mentioned, um,
uh, from, from different, uh, people's
different experiences and cultures.
So I I'm in Australia.
So one of my, the home-based Ironman,
um, also includes people throughout Asia.
Uh, so one of the greatest things
I had, uh, this last year was, was
really learning about how, uh, the
Wylie is celebrated in India, uh, and,
and the, the, the, what, what goes
on there and the meaning behind it.
And so it just sort of get a, a greater
depth of insight into the cultures
of the people who we work with.
And, uh, and I, I think that only string.
And helps us.
Cathy Tibbles: I think it's
really hard not to get lonely.
When you're a remote worker,
you work remote to Misty?
Misty Combs: I do.
I worked for a company
that has about 733 people.
Um, globally.
I believe we're in 34 countries
in 42 states in the United States.
We have had a lot of acquisitions.
Last few years.
So you have different work
environments, work cultures, things
that organizations felt were important.
And it's really important to
be one company and connected.
So just as Tom was saying that the things
that make us unique as individuals aren't
necessarily our work-related skillset.
So we have looked for opportunities to
help people connect on more of a personal.
We do leverage slack for, um,
common interests, like people who,
with a passion for photography
or cooking or their pets or.
And then we try to do things where
we really like to talk smack.
And we really like a bit of competition.
So online, um, card games, like, uh,
Euchre I'm from Michigan and, and
it's kind of a, uh, Michigan card
game that we are sharing that culture
with our friends around the world.
Um, we might have a couple of drinks.
Give each other a hard time while
we play cards or trivia, just
trying to build those relationships.
If you know somebody as a human being,
it's a lot easier to give them grace,
when something is going on at work.
Cathy Tibbles: I actually
just had a conversation this
week about how emotion like.
I want to just be more, I guess
it's my personality and firstborn.
I don't know.
I would just want to like, get
it done, like just do the things.
What's the emotion business.
And, and, um, but she said, you know,
when you're emotional or vulnerable, when
somebody meets you there and is accepting
and loving, it has a far bigger impact.
Like we can like each other's little
personas easily, but when you're actually
real with somebody in our accepted.
That has an impact.
And I don't think we're going to
have much of a choice anyway, because
millennials are taking over the world.
Tom Stinson: Yeah.
I think it's just about recognizing
that, that a huge part of us is that
we are emotional beings and, and,
and I think, and I'm not saying.
We're the first generation to, to
catch onto this or anything like that.
I think it's just about growing
and learning it as we move forward.
And rather than even, rather than
breaking it down into general,
this is, uh, the definition of one
generation to another generation.
I think it's now just that we are
moving forward and we're becoming
more and more aware that, uh,
our emotions, uh, cannot be.
As we enter in the workplace,
that they are a part of, how are
we going to interact at work?
How, or what type of work we're
going to produce, but also the,
the type of person that we are.
Uh, so I mean, and, and I'm not saying
that everybody has to, or needs to
open up about everything and all the
deepest, darkest secrets, but I think
it's just having that, um, for the leader
to have, create that environment where
it's safe for people to be vulnerable.
And it's okay.
And it's not going to be
like responsibility for that.
That was a really good, yeah.
Yeah, definitely.
We got environment last.
Was that in that book?
I like, I believe so.
I get, I get lost between
all the different books and
podcasts or sessions I've seen.
Uh, but he's, he's a
fantastic voice, I think.
Cathy Tibbles: Do I get to keep talking?
When are we done?
Oh, you know what we have,
uh, we have a community.
In the next 10 minutes.
Why don't you think are sponsors Misty?
Misty Combs: Our thanks to our
sponsors, Bluehost, Cloudways,
GoDaddy, Nexcess, Yoast, and Weglot.
Please be sure to visit our
tent and chat with them.
You may even win some prizes.
Don't forget to get your photo snapped or
the photo booth sponsored by Multicollab
and Dreamhost and tweeted out with a
hashtag WordFest live hashtags also.
Thanks.
Cathy Tibbles: Yep.
And Cloudways it has their launch
with words, uh, in the tent.
Yeah.
So you can go back to the tent
and it should be right where
you got the link to come in this
room and thank you so much, Tom.
Really, really enjoyed it.
So we'll see you back in 10 minutes.
Okay.