Nexcess: Oh, great.
My website crashed again.
I give up, don't give up on your
dreams, Jordan, who are you?
It's me.
You from the future.
Your professional website
is not out of reach.
You just need Nexcess with Nexcess
managed hosting, you get lightening
pass load times built-in performance
monitoring and updates, and always awesome
support 24 7 365 for all your plans.
Whoa.
Yeah.
Weglot: Discover Weglot the simple
translation solution for your website.
All you have to do is add Weglot to
your website, select the languages
that you need, and that's it.
Your website is now available
in multiple languages.
Yoast: Do you know, the Yoast SEO,
plugin, they're red, orange, and
green feedback bullets that help
you optimize your posts for the web.
It runs on millions of websites.
We try to make SEO understandable
and accessible to everyone.
Bluehost: Who says building
an online store has to be hard
with Bluehost website builder.
It's more than just easy.
It's tell us your thing in smart AI.
We'll take it from there.
Easy it's WooCommerce friendly.
So you can add one of these
or swap this for that easy.
It's set up shop in minutes
with unlimited products.
Easy.
Whether you sell boots, books
or bowls, it's create an online
store with Bluehost, easy build
beyond boundaries with Bluehost.
Cathy Tibbles: Hi, welcome back.
We are going to get to meet Michele,
one of our WordFest organizers.
Uh, we're going to take some time
with this round, this work fast,
to get to know our organizers.
They volunteered for a huge job,
and we just want to know why.
And we also want to know a
little bit more about that.
And, uh, who's contributing
to the Big Orange Heart.
Hi Michele.
Michele Butcher-Jones: Hello.
The first thing I thought of
when you're like, why, when you
said about why I'm choosing to
volunteer, I'm like a little crazy.
Cathy Tibbles: Oh, I'm glad you did.
So tell me about what you do.
Is it WordFest?
Do you volunteer with the
bigger, uh, orange hard as well?
Michele Butcher-Jones: Um, I haven't
really done that much with the Big
Orange Heart, but I've always been one
for promoting a better mental health,
um, better just, um, mental health
with working remotely and overall.
And anytime that I have seen
different things, uh, with Big
Orange Heart, um, Like promoting
them online and stuff like that.
I'm always like, yes,
these people are great.
And then, um, it came up to be a speaker
and I'm like, yeah, I'd like to do that.
Let me submit some things.
And then later I got a message saying
that they needed help in the volunteers
group, I guess, unfortunately,
um, previously had to back out
and I was like, sure, I can help.
Cathy Tibbles: Did you have any
idea what you were signing up for?
Oh,
Michele Butcher-Jones: not a clue.
Cathy Tibbles: So what is it, what's
your role that you're doing this time?
Michele Butcher-Jones: The volunteer lead.
Oh, yeah.
So wrangling, wrangling all the, uh,
all the volunteers, um, and making sure
that everything is covered or if not
covered the, one of the actual, uh,
volunteers team heads could jump in there.
And of course the way
I've been sick today.
So I'm not going to be able to help bye.
Cathy Tibbles: Your fired.
Mitsy Combs: I appreciate it.
And thank you.
Thank you for being understanding
of, I don't know what I'm doing.
Doing great
Michele Butcher-Jones: joked
around with a friend of mine.
I was like, this is not hurting cats.
This is hurting squirrels.
And they've all been part of it before.
Cathy Tibbles: How many of us are there?
Do you know the numbers
Michele Butcher-Jones: a lot?
Cathy Tibbles: It takes a
lot to put this event on.
Michele Butcher-Jones: See here, 1,
2, 3, 4, 5, 6, looking at a about.
60 volunteers like six, zero.
Yeah.
Mitsy Combs: Wow, bless you.
Cathy Tibbles: Yeah, it was quite bad.
When you look at all of the spreadsheets
that go into this, it's amazing,
Michele Butcher-Jones: especially why
there's not that many people who are
taking more than one shift and we've got.
Let's see, 18 different spots for
volunteers across six time periods.
And there's only four hours.
Yeah.
Well, and there's only, uh, about, I'd
say ten-ish that are doing more than one.
Cathy Tibbles: That's awesome.
More people to help.
And this is how I, um, heard of Big Orange
Heart actually, and getting involved.
So it's, it's a great opportunity
to get, to meet some more
people behind the scenes.
Michele Butcher-Jones: Yes.
People doing really good work.
It also gives one of the things
I like about with, um, WordFest
is it's it was such a more calmer
atmosphere in a way in it's a good.
Stepping stone in a way for people
wanting to get into public speaking,
helping volunteer, giving back, um, in the
WordPress and remote community, because
you, when you, if you are wanting it
in public speaking, you don't have that
standing in a room in front of hundreds,
or like if your first one's working for
us, thousands of people, it's just in
a way you and your computer at first.
Cathy Tibbles: Yeah.
It's a good stepping stone.
How do you find the speakers?
I guess that's not your area.
Michele Butcher-Jones: That was not
my area on this one, but a lot of
times it's, um, just you put out
the call for it, the website and
put it out through social media.
And nine times out of 10, I've done
a number of WordCamps, including
WordCamp US, um, being on the
speaker team and being speaker
leads at different ones of them.
And usually you'll end up getting
almost double it's sometimes not true.
The amount of people submitting
for the top slots you have.
Cathy Tibbles: Wow.
Well, I guess it's good publicity as well.
They get to get their name out.
And a lot of people like with
speaking, volunteer, organizing
any of it, it's a lot of times
just people like to give back.
What is your, when you're not
volunteering, what is your full-time job?
Michele Butcher-Jones: Um, my
full-time job is I am, um, the
support team, um, specialists lead.
Um, at Thrive Digital Marketing Agency,
which is based out of Dallas, Texas.
Um, I wrangle all of the support
specialists and, um, help assist with
the developers to make sure that our
developers have everything they need to
fix the sites to make the clients happy.
And then I also work a part-time job for
Cornell university doing content manage.
Cathy Tibbles: Wow.
You're a busy lady.
So do you spend any time at home?
Michele Butcher-Jones:
Oh yeah, I'm sleeping.
And then the weekends, and then I
also have a daughter who's a senior
in high school, this, so actually
next week we are going to visit the
college that she's, um, pick to go
to, which is university of Michigan.
Cathy Tibbles: I have
one in grade 12 as well.
It's very exciting.
Michele Butcher-Jones: I'm not ready
for all of this, graduation, you
just be pushed back another year.
I'm fine.
Cathy Tibbles: I know, I know.
It's really hard when
they grow up so fast.
We have, um, an interview with Bluehost.
Do you know.
If they're coming on?
Michele Butcher-Jones: They shouldn't be,
Cathy Tibbles: We get to
interview someone else.
Michele Butcher-Jones: Devon
Sears, who is a very fun guy.
If you've never met him.
Mitsy Combs: Okay.
Cathy Tibbles: So do you, can you
tell us how else we can get involved?
If we wanted to give back, like I've
heard there's a five, five and five.
What does that camp WordPress?
Right.
Michele Butcher-Jones: The word,
the press foundation is the ones
behind five, five, and five.
And what that does means is you give 5%.
Of your resources back to the WordPress
community, and that can be your individual
self, or your company, um, individual
self you're looking at only two hours
per week, and that could be spent, uh,
volunteering for, um, these types of.
Events that WordCamps,
WordFest, um, stuff like that.
It can be spending time in the, um,
support forums, helping people answer
questions on, um, plugins that you use
and, you know, the answers to it can be.
Cathy Tibbles: Uh, what's
the address for that?
Give us the link for
Michele Butcher-Jones:
make.wordpress.org is their main site.
Um, I can, I cannot remember
the actual URL for the five,
for five to sign up for it,
Cathy Tibbles: for the future.
Right.
Informative to me.
I keep saying five for five, five, right?
That sounds familiar.
Yeah.
Michele Butcher-Jones: And, um, Then for a
Big Orange Heart, you just, um, go online.
Um, um, you can do the monetary help out.
I know.
Oftentimes there is.
Options where Dan and co.
will message out saying we need
help with the actual organizing
team, whether that be in, um, social
media, helping out with that content.
I know they're always happy for, um, guest
writers to write a blog piece on like
their story for, um, how they got into
WordPress or story on mental health and
how they've overcome different things.
And I know for sure they're
looking for anything uplifting.
Cathy Tibbles: Who is
looking for those stories?
Michele Butcher-Jones:
Um, Big Orange Heart.
Cathy Tibbles: Okay.
Okay.
I just missed that.
Yeah.
And a guest posting there, and then
we can also sign in for an account at
wordpress.org and answer questions.
Like you don't need any special training.
You just answer the ones that you know of.
And there's people asking everything
from how to log in to yes.
How to
Michele Butcher-Jones: code.
If you're into doing training, there's
a group for that in make.Wordpress.org,
where they're building out all kinds of
trainings, um, for as simple as what's
the difference between a post and the
page all the way up to they're starting
to get into more developer stuff.
Um, you can help out with marketing,
um, really, uh, WordCamps,
um, for the speaker sponsor.
Um, volunteers there's, um, Meta, polygons
is one that they always need help with.
If you are someone who speaks
multiple languages, they're always
looking for people to help translate.
Cathy Tibbles: Yeah.
There's always, there's some
way that we can get involved.
Michele Butcher-Jones: Yes.
It's and the, one of the things is
though to keeping the mind is it is
so much fun and it's actually kind of
addicting for doing volunteer work and
giving your time to something is the
most precious commodity you can give.
However, make sure you are holding
boundaries with yourself and
being able to take those breaks.
Not let yourself get burned out on.
Cathy Tibbles: How do you maintain
boundaries with two jobs and want to have
the time to do the stuff that feels good,
volunteer volunteers or giving back?
Like there's stuff that we want to do.
Michele Butcher-Jones: Do
as I say , not as I do.
Cathy Tibbles: So it's
a really good reminder.
Michele Butcher-Jones: I'm one who
thrives more on the, always being on
the go, always having something to do,
um, type of personality when I'm awake.
I'm, you know, feet to the floor from
when I get up to when I go to bed.
Um, but I find a lot of joy and relaxation
in doing a lot of this kind of stuff.
We're it doesn't really feel like a job.
It does feel like a hobby, but when it
gets to be something that I've losing my
joy in, I do tend to take a step back.
Cathy Tibbles: Yeah.
That sounds smart.
Knowing who you are.
I have a daughter that's completely
opposite from me like this.
I enjoy doing, but it taxes me.
So then I'll need a break.
Well, she, if she's at home
all day, she's just go crazy.
Like she just needs to, to get back to.
Volunteering and all over the place.
And that gives her joy, builds her up.
So we have to understand ourselves
and the able to prioritize the
things that are important to us.
Michele Butcher-Jones: Very much so that's
like probably well I'll um, I paused on,
um, the volunteering about 4:00 AM central
us time, which is about halfway through.
And then, um, And who has an interview
later, we'll actually be taking over for
moderating all the volunteers and then
I'm passing out and then getting up.
And actually my husband and I have
to, um, stay up comedic concerts.
We're going to this week.
So after all the hustle and bustle of
getting the WordFest out and completed,
and with a very full workweek this past
two weeks, um, at both jobs, um, have
just been able to have that relaxed time.
Yeah.
Cathy Tibbles: Well, we really appreciate
your help and organizing all of us.
It's a bigger job than I think any of us
really realize until we're in your shoes.
So thank you so much.
It's a pleasure.