Yoast: Do you know, the Yoast SEO,
plugin, they're red, orange, and
green feedback bullets that help
you optimize your posts for the web.
It runs on millions of websites.
We tried to make SEO understandable
and accessible to everyone.
Bluehost: Who says building
an online store has to be hard
with Bluehost website builder.
It's more than just easy.
It's tell us your thing in smart AI.
We'll take it from there.
Easy it's WooCommerce friendly.
So you can add one of these
or swap this for that.
It's set up shop in minutes
with unlimited products.
Easy.
Whether you sell boots, books
or bowls, it's create an online
store with Bluehost, easy build
beyond boundaries with Bluehost.
Nexcess: Oh, great.
My website crashed again.
I give up, don't give up on your
dreams, Jordan, who are you?
It's me.
You from the future.
Your professional website
is not out of reach.
You just need the Nexcess.
With Nexcess managed hosting, you
get lightning load times built
and performance monitoring and
updates, and always awesome support.
24 7 365.
For all your projects.
Whoa.
Yeah.
Weglot: Discover Weglot the simple
translation solution for your website.
All you have to do is add
Weglot to your website, select
the languages that you need.
And that's it.
Your website is now available
in multiple languages.
Cathy Tibbles: Okay.
We have another Michelle
coming in to interview Devin.
Take it away michelle.
Michelle Frechette: Thanks.
Good to see you.
Thanks for thinking both were
emceeing and Hey, there he is.
You tell him that he was in hair
and makeup still, but there he is.
Okay.
I'm going back to here.
Thanks.
Devin Sears: It was great.
Sadly, this is all they're able to do.
Michelle Frechette: I was going to say, I
just had to sit in the backseat of my car.
I don't know.
Devin Sears: I know.
There
Michelle Frechette: you go.
Right, for sure.
Well, thanks for joining me.
Um, we, first of all, I was
so super excited to be able to
Bluehost as one of our sponsors.
But that meant that you and
I didn't have enough time to
actually prerecord our interview.
So we get to do it live, which is
actually, you know, kind of fun too.
So yeah.
Devin Sears: I'm doing good.
I'm doing good.
Uh, I'm based out of Austin.
Uh, I, I can never remember the UTC.
Uh, I think you and I share,
uh, Uh, difficulty with time
zones sometimes, but challenged.
Yeah, it's it.
Uh, the sun just went
down, but it was 75 today.
So it was a great day.
And, uh, I'm excited to be here happy
to be able to participate and to see
a lot of my friends across, across
the globe, even if it is virtual.
Michelle Frechette: Exactly it is nice.
And one of the nice things about, um,
what we can do with WordFest, because we
have the great sponsors, like Bluehost is
have those great community tents where you
can go in and like there's rooms already.
There are people kind of sitting,
waiting, and lots of opportunities
to talk to each other in between
sessions during the community time.
Um, and learn more, not only
about each other, but of course
our wonderful sponsors too.
So tell me a little bit about.
Was it, why did Bluehost
want to go ahead and sponsor?
Not just WordFest, but Big
Orange Heart for this year.
Tell me a little bit about your, um, your
desires to help out in the community.
Devin Sears: Yeah.
Um, I think that Bluehost has always had a
desire to really engage with the community
and participate within the community.
And I think when, when we saw a Big
Orange Heart, putting us together
and we also participated last
year, we knew that we wanted to.
To, um, maintain our sponsorship
and maintain that relationship.
I think that the community is great.
Uh, I'm a big fan.
I've been a part of the
community for a while.
Now, a few years, we don't need to
go into how many, but it's, uh, I've,
I've developed lifelong friendships
outside of even my role at Bluehost.
And so I think that that's just
one small thing that contributes
to how important it is to.
Find ways for us to interact with
each other, to learn from each
other, to help each other grow either
professionally or even personally.
I think, I think both of those
things are absolutely key.
So I think Bluehost participating
is, is one of the ways that we
can, we can help people connect.
Uh, I think one of the main Bluehost
missions is to help people tell
their story online, you know, We
try to implement as many tools as
possible to help people get their
site, their vision, their idea, their
e-commerce store, whatever it might be.
We try to help them get that online.
And I feel like that's a way that
people can contribute their voice.
And I think specifically now when it's
not quite as easy for us to all socially
interact with each other, I think
it's important for us to find moments
like this event where we can all come
together and all kind of contribute
to our voices and raise each other.
Michelle Frechette: Yeah,
I couldn't agree more.
It's been, um, to say it's been a
trying couple of years for the WordPress
community is an understatement.
It's going to trying a couple of
years for all of us, for sure.
Um, regardless of what community we're in.
And, but when we're used to seeing
regularly, um, you know, like at WordCamps
and meetups and things like that, it's,
um, it's definitely been challenging,
but what I've noticed is companies
like Bluehost have taken opportunity.
To turn it around if you will.
So I have participated in more than
one Bluehost chat, um, but y'all have
on Twitter and that's just brilliant.
I love the fact the way that you kind
of rally the whole community around a
topic, but with, with questions, specific
questions that you ask, could you tell
us a little bit about, you know, what is
the Bluehost chat and why do you not do
it and how does it help the community?
Devin Sears: For sure.
Um, first of all, I would love to take
credit for it, but I cannot, that was,
that was our social media manager.
So I want to give them credit.
Um, and second of all, thank you
so much for your participation.
I always am thrilled to see it.
When, when you participate, I do,
uh, sign into the Twitter handle and
I try to help reply when I can, um,
Twitter is not my forte, but, uh, I
do try to help out where I can, but
the, the idea behind the Twitter.
And the BHC hashtag BH chat is,
is the hashtag that we go with.
Um, it's, it's something that's short.
I feel like it's, it's very consumable.
You know, it only takes, I
don't know, 25 to 45 minutes,
usually on a Thursday afternoon.
Um, and I feel like we really wanted
to find a way to engage with the
community, bring the community together
and also have it be educational.
You know, we didn't.
As fun as it is.
And I know we all miss those hallway
conversations where we can catch
up and hear what Netflix shows were
bingeing, or, you know, how, how our
pets are doing or something like that.
Um, I think it's also important that we,
we maintain the ability to help each other
learn and to grow and to progress because
everyone in the WordPress community at
one point installed their first WordPress
site, you know, and some of us remember.
Really well, you know, the, the, the
different questions that might've popped
up or the apprehension, you know, and the
fear that you had when you were trying
to navigate building your first website.
And on the flip side of that coin, a
lot of us also can remember the joy
and the happiness that we felt when we
stumbled across the community, or when
we were introduced to the community.
And we found there was this whole army of
people that have this wealth of knowledge.
That I could really benefit from, and
they're all so friendly and they're also
willing to reach out and to help me.
And so we, we wanted to try to
find a way that we could share
our knowledge with each other.
And when I say our, I mean, our as
the community, not our, as Bluehost
share the community's knowledge with
each other, help people that might be
looking for a fun way to interact and.
My my role.
I usually try to be the person
that responds with gifts.
So if you ever participate and there's
a, a gift, that's usually my role.
I try to, I try to find fun ways
to respond and, and, uh, the,
the perfect gift as a response.
That's, that's my role in all
of that, but we've enjoyed it.
Michelle Frechette: I am the gif
queen when it comes to the BH chat.
Like I, don't not post an answer
without, without a gif because
there's so many really good ones, too.
Devin Sears: And, and I'm
a visual person as well.
So I think that's one of the reasons
why I'm not as good on Twitter.
Um, but replying with gifs.
And, and I feel like that really
brings a visual element in it.
I mean, to some degree it
tells like a small story.
Right.
And it just, I feel like it really, uh,
Really can convey the emotion or the,
or the point that you're trying to make.
And it always just makes it seem fun.
And it's always a little bit
of a goose chase to try to find
one that fits perfectly or is
relevant or is currently topical
or trending or something like that.
So there's a fine line.
You got to find that fine line.
Michelle Frechette: There are
some on there that are like a
little questionable, but I think
if you can make somebody smile.
In 280 characters or less plus a gif.
I mean, that's pretty awesome, right.
Especially if you're dropping some
knowledge that helps people, um,
move forward with their businesses
and with their websites for sure.
And that's one of the things I love
about the BH chats is it, isn't just
like, this is how you build a website.
These are what plugins are.
It's not like that, like the basic
building blocks of making a website.
It's the basic building blocks of
being successful with the website
that you build, which I think is.
Devin Sears: Yeah.
And we really try to crowdsource
our knowledge, which I think
kind of comes down to the heart
of the WordPress community.
In some degree, you know, it it's
crowdsourcing our knowledge and it's,
it's sharing it and receiving it.
And.
All at once.
You know, so I think, uh, I like to think
that that Bluehost has a few subject
matter experts within its ranks, but
I also definitely recognize that there
is a wide plethora of people out there
within the WordPress community that
truly are the subject matter experts.
And so I think it reminds me a little
bit of those, like, uh, Forbes, like we
asked 50, uh, business millionaires or
whatever, you know, how, how they became
entrepreneurs or to tell their story.
And so I, I like to think of it kind
of like that, where it's like, okay,
well we want to turn this over to the
community and like, tell your story.
Like we help.
We want to help amplify your story as well
as educating people that are following.
Michelle Frechette: And it's great because
you do reach out to certain people.
I don't know how many, um, and ask
them to participate in advance so
that you kind of get that pump primed.
But so many other people join
into the conversation too.
So it isn't just like, uh, these people
on stage and everybody has to watch.
It's like, oh wow, this is
a really great conversation.
And everybody can be included and
everybody can put their 2 cents in and
everybody can learn from one another.
So, yeah, it's brilliant.
You guys do a really great job with that.
Absolutely.
So what, what makes working at Bluehost,
um, a special place and how do you,
you know, as I've observed about
community and things like that, what
do you do for your own employees?
As far as mental wellbeing?
Devin Sears: Two-part question.
Um, let me go through the first one first.
Um, what makes working
at Bluehost special?
I'll answer for myself personally.
Um, I'm honestly going to say the
opportunity to participate and
engage with the WordPress community.
Um, if I'm completely honest, when I first
stepped into this role, I did not know
the friends I would make along the way.
I don't think any.
I could imagine that I didn't know
the different places it would take me.
I just kind of knew that I needed to get
some swag together and maybe a banner.
And I was going to go stand somewhere
in Miami by a table and try to make
some friends or, you know, try to
see if people were interested in
talking about Bluehost and little.
Did I know that that stepping into that
door, you know, I have friends all across
the country that you're just, just from
travel, some WordCamp US from WordCamp
Europe, all across the globe that, you
know, I'll pick up the phone and I'll
call someone and say, Hey, I just, I
haven't talked with you in a while.
I miss you.
And it's it's for me, it's, it's been
the friendship along the way, which I
know is, is kind of cliche, but it, but
it really is one of the main things that
I've loved about working at Bluehost's.
Not only the friends I've made within the
community, but the friends that I've made
among my coworkers and my peers as well.
The second part of the question
is what does Bluehost do about
remote working and mental health?
Was that was that
Michelle Frechette: Yeah, talk about
mental wellbeing with your employees?
Um,
Devin Sears: I think there's a, there's
a big push for people to take care of
themselves, uh, and their mental health.
Um, I know, kind of culturally, we, we
try to have a little bit of water cooler
chitchat, somewhere along the meeting.
I know that with zoom meetings and with
online virtual meetings, it's really,
really easy for people to come into
the meeting, talk about the business
and then hang up when you're done,
you know, there's you, you lose that.
Hey, as we're walking back to our
desks, like tell me about your weekend.
Like we can.
Take a step away from the business
side of things, just as we're walking
back to our desk or let's, you know,
go out and grab a bite of lunch
together or something like that.
You really don't have those opportunities
that you, that you had, uh, when
you worked in an office space.
And I think that Bluehost is,
has been great at promoting and
finding those opportunities.
Say okay.
You know, like before we get
started, how's everyone doing?
You know, I haven't seen you in a while.
How's how's your kid, or, you know,
like, I know you have this house project
you're working on, what's going on
with that, you know, and, and, and
really making an effort to strengthen
those relationships beyond just the,
Hey, your, the email channel manager.
I need you to email, you know, I
need you to, to manage this channel.
Like it's, I think viewing
people as people, instead of.
Tools in a, in a tool chest is
something that they've done a really
good job at doing on top of that.
They also try to schedule, uh, events
on a regular basis and sadly, I'm
not able to attend all of them,
but I attend as many as I can.
Most recently we had a marketing
Valentines Olympics, so it was
a combination in February of a
Valentine's and the Olympics.
Um, we set aside, I think it was
an hour and a half or so, and
everyone from marketing jumped on
the same call and, and they, they
had breakout rooms and everything.
So you could get to know some people
that maybe you didn't know before
they had awards, they had games.
Um, so it was, it was a lot of fun.
It really was.
Uh, and in addition, uh, they also have
employee resource groups or affinity
groups, so they have, um, Uh, I say they,
we, I guess, uh, I say they, because
I don't personally contribute to that.
So I don't, I don't want to take
credit for someone else's, uh, hard
work, but Bluehost provides its
employees with, uh, an affinity group.
Um, one that comes to mind
is the thrive affinity group.
And they host regular breathing
exercises and meditations where
anyone can join and participate.
And, uh, they have a focus on the, the
mental health and mental wellbeing.
Any employee that feels like they need a
little bit of a boost or a pick me up or
just want to be involved with that group.
Michelle Frechette: Wow.
That's great.
Well, I can't talk about Bluehost without
also bringing up two very specific things.
So I have two more questions.
One, how many games of Mario cart
have you played over the years since
you've been part of the post and two,
how many big screen TVs have you not
given away in the last three years?
Devin Sears: Oh man,
that's a great question.
Games of Mario kart.
I don't, we've played so many
games of Mario kart, uh, for,
to clue in the audience that
might not be aware, uh, Bluehost.
Traditionally, when we have an
in-person event, we will buy a.
Large TV locally.
And we bring with us and
Nintendo 64 and Mario kart 64.
And so usually on the first day
of the event, we'll demonstrate
a Bluehost product or the newest
features that we're working on.
But then day two, we'll, we'll break out
the Nintendo 64 and, and attendees that
are looking for a quick five minute break
and stop by and race and things like that.
And just over the years, after
going to as many events as I have.
I have played a lot of Mario
kart, um, to the point where we
have discovered if everyone ties.
So if you do like a four race circuit
and everyone ties, we had discovered
that the game prioritizes who wins
by the, the controller position,
like where you've plugged in your
controller, if you plugged in his player,
That's prioritized so that you win.
So I've paid enough to do
all of these very weird tests
unintentionally just over the years.
But, uh, I would also like to take
this opportunity to plug, uh, the
Bluehost's booth here during WordFest.
Obviously we don't have an intendant 64.
We're not able to give away a TV, sadly.
Um, but tomorrow, depending
on when you're tuning in.
Tomorrow, we are going to
have an hour in our booth that
we're calling, switch it up.
And anyone that has an Nintendo
switch, if you like, you can stop
by, uh, share your game code, make
a new friend within the community,
and we'll be doing some Mario kart.
If people want to, you know,
we're, we're there to play whatever
game that that you want to do.
So, uh, there's still some more
Meyer card to be played for.
Michelle Frechette: Um, I played
Mario kart twice in my life.
My daughter, she was in her late teens
and early twenties at the time she brought
it over just to see how I would do.
I am terrible at it.
And she laughs because I always like
move my whole body what I'm trying to.
Yeah.
So.
I do that when I watched the luge, um,
like, and skiers in the Olympics too.
So I just, I think, I guess
maybe if I leave, I'm going
to help them a little bit.
I don't know.
Devin Sears: I'm going
to tell you something.
I think you're actually ahead of the
curve because with the emergence of
virtual reality, I feel like that's
how a lot of the games are played.
I feel like it's with the leaning
and the head tilting and all of that.
So I think you are just a savant.
I think you were ahead of your time.
You were just ready for
the virtual reality.
Michelle Frechette: Can you
text that to my daughter?
Let her know that I am.
I am a head of the head of the well Devin.
I'm going to go ahead and wrap it
up so you can say hi to people.
Uh, I don't know what
your whole plans are.
I hope that you're going over
to your booth for a few minutes.
After this case, everybody wants to say.
And I know that you're probably
going to take some time to sleep
tonight before you show up before
you come back to the, with tomorrow.
But, um, AF after we sign off here,
go over to the community tent, see the
Bluehost table, say hello to Devin, Devin.
Thank you so much for taking the time
to get to know you and Bluehost, uh,
during this little interview, but also.
For the sponsorship that blue house
has provided, so that Big Orange
Heart can do the work that we do
in the community, which is reducing
those feelings of isolation for
people in the remote work community.
So thank you so much for being here.
Devin Sears: Thank you for having us.
We're excited to be here and looking
forward to chatting with some people.
Michelle Frechette: Sounds good.
All right.
Well, we will see you all later
at, uh, let me actually, I want to
read our thinking is real quick.
I said I would do that.
So I do want to thank our sponsors
Bluehost, Cloudways, GoDaddy Pro,
Nexcess, Yoast, and Weglot be sure to
visit their tents, to chat with them.
You might even surprise us.
Don't forget to go to our photo booth
and get your photo snap sponsored by a
Multicollab and DreamHost tweeted out
with the hashtag WordFest Live, and also
thank you to our media partners and our
micro sponsors in the community tent.
In the next hour Cloudway, we'll
have their hourly giveaway.
We do have about a 15
minute break now schedule.
So go over to that community
tech, we will be back on the.
And also we would love your support.
So please consider a donation via
the button on our screen, or go to
https://big.ht/march4th, you all make
a difference for our Big Orange Hearts.
Thank you so much.