Yoast: Do you know, the Yoast SEO,
plugin, they're red, orange, and
green feedback bullets that help
you optimize your posts for the web.
It runs on millions of websites.
We tried to make SEO understandable
and accessible to everyone.
Nexcess: Oh great.
My website crashed.
I give up.
Don't give up on your dreams.
Jordan, who are you?
It's me.
You from the future.
Your professional website
is not out of reach.
You just need Nexcess.
With Nexcess managed hosting, you
get lightening pass load times
built-in performance monitoring and
updates, and always awesome support.
24 7 365 for all your projects.
Whoa.
Yeah.
Weglot: Discover Weglot the simple
translation solution for your website.
All you have to do is add Weglot to
your website, select the languages
that you need, and that's it.
Your website is now available
in multiple languages.
Bluehost: Who says building
an online store has to be hard
with Bluehost website builder.
It's more than just easy.
It's tell us your thing and smart AI.
We'll take it from there.
Easy it's WooCommerce friendly.
So you can add one of these,
or swap this for that easy.
It's set up shop in minutes
with unlimited products.
Easy.
Whether you sell boots, books
or bowls, it's create an online
store with Bluehost, easy build
beyond boundaries with blue house.
Cathy Tibbles: Hi, welcome back.
Hi Misty.
How was your break?
Misty Combs: Um, great, thank you Cathy.,
our next speaker is Michele Butcher-Jones
presenting sticks and stones will break
bones, but words really do matter.
We had the pleasure of
meeting her a few minutes ago.
Michele is a leading word, press
technical specialist at Thrive
International Marketing Agency and
runs her own WordPress shop at 13 Core.
She has also the head geek out.
Over at Can't Speak Geek
when not working her jobs.
Michele is an organizer at WordCamp St.
Louis and the lead organizer of the
Southern Illinois WordPress meetup.
You can usually find her snapping
pictures at the gym, hanging with
her family or reading a book.
She's always down for an
adventure, especially if it
involves great food or drinks.
Welcome Michele.
Michele Butcher-Jones: Hello everyone.
I hope you can all hear me.
And my slides are still
backstage at seams.
There we go.
Uh, hope everyone's having a great day,
night, evening, afternoon, whatever
it is in your neck of the woods.
But watching those videos, Devin
from Bluehost, we need to talk
about me seeing a nice big bowl
of ramen right before I talk.
Well, we'll get into this.
Um, let me get over there and starting
off a little bit about myself, um, as
mentioned, I'm the lead support specialist
at thrive digital marketing agency?
Um, I have my own, um, in-house
agency that I do, um, hosting and,
um, support management with, um,
blogger over at Can't Speak Geek
and enthusiast of volunteering and
organizing WorkCamps and taking pictures.
Now we're getting into why is
effective communication important?
Um, It's not only just speaking,
but writing and body language
all goes into your communication.
And when the communication is effective,
it sets expectations from the start.
So there won't be as many questions
on what you mean by what you
say and what did they hear?
And it makes feed, people feel like
they're being actually listened to and
that their point is getting across.
And in a business, it can reduce,
turn in distress, this trust and
conflict, because you are setting
the bar exactly where it should be.
And you're putting everyone
onto a level playing field.
There's no questions of, will
this actually get accomplished?
Am I being scanned or anything like that?
And you will build trust
within one of them.
Because you as a sender, you need
to make sure you put across what you
mean in the message of what you say
so that the receiver takes in exactly
what, uh, what you want them to hear.
And by nature, we're really selfish.
Communicate.
Um, we don't really mean to be,
uh, we tend to talk a lot about in
the perspection of I's and me's,
and unfortunately that's a bit of a
narcissistic default because it makes
us spend more times of the I's and
the me's instead of stepping back and
having the you's and we's and our brain
is actually more responsible for that.
And it starts out.
At birth because in the first few years of
life, you're very much of a everything's
black and white, hot and cold do not
touch this because it can hurt you.
And it's a lot of autopilot and
it grows from there in this trend,
kind of goes through childhood.
It's a very, um, fight or flight
type of mechanism, but then
once you hit adulthood, it's
just kind of ingrained in us.
To be that selfish listener.
And we're not really aware of it until
we actually step back and think, and look
at the words we use in a conversation.
Um, like, uh, one of the biggest ones
I've seen, especially when we're more
blossoming into inclusiveness of being.
Um, respectful of pronouns
is the one really big one.
Like for example, I know of someone
who, um, is non-binary and goes by
they, them and someone wished them a
happy birthday and talked about what
a wonderful woman they're becoming.
And.
In a way that was a very selfish
response out of the person,
because it was not honoring them
of what they want to be called.
And so with effective communication,
it makes you more mindful of
the words you say and how they
can impact the other person.
And then with that, you are now armed
with the things that you can, um, sorry.
My brother went over there for a
second, um, to access the two most
important concepts in the communication.
There's it actually really
just boils down to two things.
And the first one is self-awareness and
in any given situation, um, Have those
quick judge of what to say and what to do.
Sorry, um, with that, it's good
to get to the point where you can
detach yourself from the emotions.
And sometimes we respond really
quickly and really harshly without
realizing what we're saying.
And if we take that step back and give
an honest assessment, even if it's a
quick one, Of what we're going to say.
It can actually lead to better outcomes.
Now it doesn't really mean make
anything you less than human for, if
you do, sometimes the words are pop
off on a response, um, when you're
being less than perfect, um, which
is a huge fear for many people.
But the best thing to do is when
there's something does take in
a way, a mental dislike, pause.
Okay then respond and no one
can hear inside your brain
for doing those self checks.
And when you do take those pauses,
sometimes before you speak, it
shows that other person that you
are taking the time to give a good
answer and practicing the pause.
Not only helps in effective communication,
but can also help with mental.
'cause how many times have you said
something in that split second decision
and then instantly regretted it, um,
stayed up like sometimes two, three
years later, something gets in your
head of why did I say that so quickly?
I should've stopped, um, stop
for a second and thought about.
And then also sympathy versus empathy.
Sympathy is a feelings of pity and
sorrow for someone else's fortune, where
you're just like, oh, I'm so sorry.
Oh, I thoughts and prayers,
that kind of stuff.
But empathy is the ability to understand
and share the feelings of one another.
And it's really empathy that
makes someone a good and effective
communicator because you're recognizing
those other people's feelings.
You're recognizing that their
thoughts are real to them or
their feelings are real with them.
And that you are with them.
And when you're only having sympathy,
there's that whole disconnect because
with sympathy that's you and I'm me.
And that's when you see a lot of the
qualifying words like the at least,
or if I, or, but, but as one of the
biggest qualifiers there is, cause
it'd be like, I'm sorry, you're sick.
But when I was this.
And it really takes away those feelings
of validation from the other person.
Then also always err, on the side of
clarity, because it's not really about
the message you send to people, but,
um, the message that they receive, um,
and the more effective, the more on
purpose you can be with your words.
The more clarity they have.
And then on the flip side of
that is at the end, you have them
kind of repeat it back to you.
Like, you know, say, this is what I
understand, or if I get this right,
you mean dada, and kind of like at the
end of a client meeting that you might
have with someone and you send out that
email of going over, everything that was
said, Not just with me after meetings.
Is that good after really any
conversation that you think your
message might not be getting across?
It's good to revert back
and go over everything.
And then.
Um, we'll get into kind of just
building a voice guide for people.
Um, if you have one kind of for
yourself, or if you are a person
who owns a company on how to set up,
um, a voice guide for getting your
point across what words to use in
conversations, what works not to use.
And here are some general
communicating tips.
These can go over email, um, chat,
talking, uh, public situations rather
pretty much any style of communication.
Okay.
That's not in there and
should not be there.
Let me just skip over that one.
Sorry about that.
I look these over now.
One.
I never saw.
The first one soon will never
come in a professional setting.
You should never use the word soon
because soon does not really have any
definitive, um, um, wording to it.
Cause if I say, oh, I will get to
that soon and get back to you in my
head that soon could be, I'll have
that done by the end of the week.
Now the person I say this
to takes the word soon.
It means, oh, they'll have
that done this afternoon.
So when this evening comes around or
the next morning comes around, I'm
getting an email saying, Hey, I'm
looking for an update on that task or
that question, because you said that
you'd have an answer back to me soon.
And in my head, I was like, oh,
I wasn't planning on getting
to that till later today.
So if you give them a definitive
timeframe, and now that doesn't mean
it has to be due by that timeframe,
it could be you just plan on giving
them an update and an update could
be we're still working on it.
But if you give a definitive time,
like for that one example, I thought it
would be done by the end of the week.
I could have went back to the person
and said, thanks for sending that over.
I will have that information back
to you by the end of the week.
So they know they don't
even have to contact.
Until the end of the week to get that
information from me because they know
it's not going to be there till that time.
And that gives you more time to
do what you need to do instead
of answering questions, because
there was not a qualified time.
And when communicating in email,
always make sure your subject
lines of your emails are clearing.
This is mostly due to a lot of the
spamming that goes on that nowadays,
where you get one that might say, you
know, open this for your website or.
It reads like, oh, I don't even
need to look on this when it's
an actually important email.
And then if you are working with a lot of
clients, if this is your business email,
it makes it a lot easier for if you put
that client name or that client business.
Like, we'll say if one of my clients
is big orange heart, and we're talking
about building a new form, I would put
like big orange tart dash new form.
So when I'm looking at my.
I can pick out the one that's four, and
that also helps with your clients because
they know which one is attached to which,
but if I just email it over and say, go
and charge nothing to it, which emails
us for, or if I say new form, I don't
really know which client that's for.
And email greetings matter when it
comes to communicating in text and
emails, it's always good to address
the person preferably by their names.
And, or their like rank or title who,
because like, if they're a doctor, um,
if they are, um, someone in clergy, if
they are someone like in the military
with a higher ranking, they've earned
that rank and or title and should have,
um, should be referred to as that.
Um, but also by name.
If you just kind of go into the meat of
it, of your email without greeting them,
it's a very kind of cold reading email.
And then also when using their
name, please make sure you
are spelling them incorrectly,
especially in a professional setting.
With my name.
It is only a one L in Michele Frechette.
And I have talked about this on link
of how often my name gets misspelled.
There's always two L's in it.
Sometimes I get Michael instead
of Michele and it's all over that.
And most of the time, I don't
even really bothered by it
because it happens all the time.
But when it comes to something
professional or something, financial,
something kind of more serious,
like it boss emailing me, um,
something from like the government.
I kind of expect my name to be spelled.
Right.
Um, And it, when you're using that kind
of effective communication and having
names spelled correctly, people will tend
to be more open and more worth because
you are acknowledging them properly.
Now, if you have no idea what their
email is, like, say they emailing in
from like, Marketing@bigorangeheart.org.
And you're no idea who it is.
You're talking to.
It's always good to just be
like, hi, there are howdy.
Um, or something like that to still
be greeting them without using a name
next, when it comes to effective
communication, especially in
this day and age, gender neutral,
inclusive language is so important.
And always be gender neutral
in your communication.
Um, nowadays when it comes to names
being used, and then also how they're
spelled, if you're talking to someone
outside of the us, like say if someone
has name for, um, more American cell
names, someone has the name of Peyton
or Shannon or Shelby, um, Carol.
Different names like that.
It could be either a male or
female in those names, because I
actually know, um, people in both
genders with all of those names.
So.
And oftentimes if you're like, hi, I think
that's a guy and you email him like Mr.
Michaels and they come
back and know I am a Mrs.
When you do that type of
guessing, ended up wrong.
It really breaks down the level
of trust in the communication.
But if you use some general
neutral language, you won't
ever have those issues.
And then also using pet
names that are gendered.
Like guys, dude, lady, darling, honey, Mr.
Sugar pie.
And those type of words can be
considered demeaning to other people.
And like I've even seen if you
call someone miss, who is a more
mature of woman will sometimes
think that, oh, you must think
less of me just calling me a miss.
They acting like I'm young and dumb.
So if you're completely opening your word.
You will keep that trust
within that communication.
Now proper wording can be like, Hey,
y'all, that's a big one in a way with us.
Um, word pressers, calling them
by name or referring to them
by their title is always good.
Uh, Hey, you is not really a good
one because that can be more of
like a demanding phrase, but.
Whatever language you use is
always to make sure it's open.
And if in question with someone most
of the time, if you say I don't mean
to be intrusive, however, would you
mind sharing with me your pronouns?
Because you're taking respect to them
on asking and not assuming that we'll
tend to build trust with them instead
of again, guessing and possibly being.
And then being inclusive in your
conversation, always keep that circle open
with people and riff refrain from using
comments or remarks in a group setting
of, can you guys help these ladies?
Um, the sentence can not only implies
that the lady is helpless, but it's
also unfair to the guys on the team.
Um, now, if you was to be like,
Hey, this person and call them
by name is having an issue.
Is there someone who could help just
those change in those two words of
person and someone can make some,
the person who needs a help not feel.
Like they are less than now, not only with
using the inclusiveness of genders, but
also in levels of intelligence or ease,
we should not be using because like, if
someone comes to your, the problem that
says like, Hey, my website's not loading.
I can't get it to work.
And someone comes back and
says, oh, that's a simple fix.
I can get that done in a hot.
Saying stuff like that, that it's easy.
I can get it done in a second.
Kind of will make the other
person feel like, oh, I must be
dumb since you're saying this
is easy or that this is child's.
'cause, you can make them feel less
than what they are because all of us
are really intelligent at many things
and might not be so great in others.
Like I'm really good on with WordPress
and working, um, on customer experience.
But if you handed me I, um, box that
says, build this rocket ship, it
might not even get off the ground
because that's not my expertise, but.
Am I all around lesson because I
don't know how they built the rocket.
No, because I do Excel and other things.
Another thought when it comes to
effective communication, that's
not really talked about is having
accountability in your words, in your
actions and in your communication.
One of the biggest ones that is
hard to kind of switch from is
when some question in real quick
to be like, I don't know when you
say just, I don't know, it's rare.
It's very dismissive, um, to the
other person, because it's almost
saying like, I don't care what
you're asking because I don't know.
And I'm not going to try to find out.
Yeah.
If you change that language and say that
you're not sure right now, but you can
try to find the answer for them, or you
can request some time to do it, or you
can speak so you can speak to someone else
who might know the answer or send them to
the person who you think might know that.
Yes.
And it's all because anytime you w
we, you, me, all of us have an issue.
So not really the issue we want
to dwell on, but we want to
find the solutions for that.
And so when we are in the businesses,
like we are, when it comes to, uh, working
in WordPress, building websites, um,
fixing websites, hosting websites, we
are in a solution based business because
we're there to offer a product or a sir,
And then we should not use
qualifying works and you know,
the no ifs, no buts aloud.
I don't take this personally,
but, or I just wanted you to know,
or I know what you're thinking.
However, and in my absolute
one that I load is it.
Trying to give their response
and be like, just cyan.
That drives me crazy because
the qualifiers exist for
pretty much every situation.
And in a way, if there's not one
nowadays almost make up ones.
And when you're using them, it
can totally drive people up a
wall and it can make people feel.
Devalued less than not as smart and that
their feelings and thoughts don't count.
But if we acknowledge them going back into
talking about, um, using the empathy and
the effective words and just hearing the
people and saying that they are there for.
Uh, like a lot of us have had
times where we're just having
a day and we just want to vent.
We just want to yell about it, get it off
her chest, and we'll be a happier person.
And usually you'll have a couple
of people that you can do that too.
And they're like, girl, I'm
here for you are abroad.
Why we good?
And they just let you let it all out.
Validate your feelings.
You could move on, but when you do
have people where you do go try to
just vent and get it all out, and then
as soon as they get it up, they're
like, well, I've had days like that.
Well, I've done this well.
I, I it's devalued.
That person's communication.
And it's again, taking away the trust
out of it because later on, they
might not come to you to vent with
a question with an issue, because
they're going to feel like if they
do come to you, it's just going to be
an invalidated conversation and we're
not going to get in, in the solutions.
And then on top of that
is not have excuses.
Everyone is busy.
Everyone has a lot on their plates.
Everyone's over-capacity, especially these
days, everyone's going 200 miles an hour
and everyone's got something going on
that they're not even telling you about.
How many of us tend to hide when we're
having a bad day, tend to hide when we're
hurting both physically or emotionally.
And we don't show it and
not everyone knows everyone.
Else's stories.
There's always something that's
not being really shared because
we don't know everyone's story.
We've not walked in everyone's shoes,
but we are all here to work together.
We're all here to get to the same place in
a way we're all here to succeed, to grow.
And if you need assistance, just ask.
There's always going to be someone there
to help you be it mentally, physically
in, um, mental health and physical
health and professional and impersonal.
There's always going to be someone there.
That's part of the thing that big
orange heart is for is to be there for
people to help people grow, to help
people succeed, to help people have
better mental health in there, people
that have the back, but the excuse.
Won't get you anywhere.
It won't get the work done.
It just either will keep you at the
same spot if you're making excuses or
it will actually make you move back
in life because the excuses gives
you a chance to not move forward.
Like, you know, the I'm too
busy to do this, or that's not a
priority or something like that.
And it's fine to have
things not as a priority.
Just, I don't know.
Well, it's okay to tell someone that
is not a priority for me right now.
And it's actually better.
And you build more trust.
If you tell someone that is not a priority
for me right now, instead of just saying
I'm too busy or making the excuse, pushing
it about because the more excuses that
are made, the more distrust there is,
there are no.
First in the blame game.
This is a big one.
When it comes.
If you are working in a company
with a bunch of people are, even if
you're just working on any type of
collaboration, it's always good to
refrain from passing the blame or the
responsibility or the work onto someone
else, unless they are, uh, agreeing to.
Unless they know about it beforehand,
because again, we're all here to get
to the final destination together.
And I have seen where there'll be
a number of coworkers, possibly in
different departments on a call with.
And there might be an issue.
And I have seen some co-workers
who will throw another one on the
bus, whether it's right or wrong.
I've seen some times where a
person will say, if someone from
the other department's fault
for dropping the ball on a time.
Sensitive situation.
And it was actually the person
throwing the blinds fault because they
didn't carry over the communication.
But when we kind of take ownership
in it and instead of being like,
I'm sorry, we didn't get to it.
I'm sorry.
They didn't get to it.
Just be like, thank you for the reminder.
We will make sure that gets done
for you because we're all here
to get to the final destination.
And when it comes to someone asking you
for help, especially in the world for,
with the people who are developers,
coders, engineers, who tend to end up
having to work on code somebody else.
Now say like someone else build a
website and then you took it over
two years later to help maintain it.
And you have to fix some CSS issues on it.
You wouldn't tell that client.
I didn't write that code.
So I'm not helping you with it.
No, it's your solution.
Now it's your purpose now to get that
solution for them since they are with you.
And since we are a solution-based society.
We should always be there to help
people along the way, because
also to the person who, um, did
it might not be around anymore.
And then another thing that can
set people pull back and trust
is like, that's not my job.
Because most companies, most freelancers,
most, anyone who works in the service type
industry, whether it be in WordPress or
tech or whether it be restaurants, retail,
we're all there to create solutions.
We're all there to help people.
We're all there to take on whatever
it is, our service, our product is.
And your company, your freelanced,
your community, you're all.
To do the work together and to get to
the same goal, whether it be at your
company of 50 people at your word camp,
or a word Fest with a hundred volunteers,
we're all there to get to the same goal.
And even in the communities and
everyone on earth, the more we do
work together, the better we are.
And when we.
Stay humble about things
and we help people.
We're not being arrogant.
We're not, you know, in a way, some
people being lazy now on the flip side
of this, always be there to help always
be humble, always be kind, but take
care of yourself to remember yourself.
Like I mentioned before of, if something
does get too much of saying, this is
not a priority anymore, and I need
to take care of myself, but it's all
about the words you choose to use.
And in every everywhere, professionally,
we've all dealt with, as I shouldn't
say attitudes and escalation and
Zen attitudes can be from coworkers.
They can be from, um, clients
that can be really from anywhere
now as the person, when it comes to
dealing with an issue, especially
if it's a professional one.
Check your attitude at the door.
My step grandfather used to say he is the,
well, you would use a little more colorful
language than what I'm going to use,
but he would say to, there only should
be one Butthead in the conversation,
because if there's two people who have
the are in an aggressive, combative mood,
nothing's going to get accomplished.
And sometimes you would have to
take the higher road and check your
attitude to get to that solution to
de escalate that agitated person.
Sometimes it takes a lot of effort to pull
out your attitude from the conversation.
However, if your bolt just butting
heads at the same time, there's
never going to be a solution for.
And like it says on the thing, a
bad attitude is like a flat tire.
You can't go anywhere until you change it.
You have to fully fill yourself
back up with the good attitudes
with the joy to progress.
Because as long as you're fighting is kind
of like you see in the movies with the
two ramps locking horns and they can never
get apart because they're just so at it.
Yeah, escalation is, do happen
and they can't be helped.
And some people just, they, I
swear they like having them, but
oftentimes it's just because of, um,
miscommunication and it can be resolved.
And when you are in a team
with people or there's other
people with, um, you can go to.
Sometimes it's that other way
of presenting information makes
it fixed between, um, I've
also Peter and I at thrive.
If we notice that a client is either as
an understanding or getting agitated for
like something I would say, I would ask
Peter to come in and pretty much say the
same thing in his own words or vice versa.
And usually it takes
care of the situation.
Now, if you are a team of one, yeah.
Reach out like on Twitter, or
if you're in like post status of
the ladies of WordPress slack or
something like that, where you can
bounce ideas off of one another, um,
to help out with that escalation.
As a matter of fact, I had.
Last week, a friend of mine in the
WordPress community to call me.
And, um, because she was having an
issues with the client and what's, um,
who was wanting to cancel their project
and pretty much take their files and
run of stuff that she's already built.
And we talked about it
for about a half an hour.
It was like, no, honey, if
you built it, they pay for it.
Or they don't get.
To after the call, she's like,
that's what I was thinking.
And it felt so good just to have
someone to run that by with.
Um, cause again, you're just never
alone in that, but if all those feels
it's okay to fire a client, it is okay
to remove yourself from the situation.
Because if you can see, it's
just not getting anywhere.
Um, like say if it's a client that.
The money they paying you is
not equal to the level of what
drama you're dealing with.
Feel free to divorce them or
fire them, whatever you call it.
There's a couple of clients we've co we've
said divorce on because they were, it was
a toxic marriage professional mirrors.
That was for sure.
And often with that too, is when you do.
Fire them as a client, you don't even have
to have that as a quote, bad situation.
I've seen a number of times in agencies
where it just has a point that it's like,
this relationship is no longer good.
And a lot of us are friends with
other agencies and other, you know,
personalities with the agencies.
And there's no reason why you.
Reach out to another one and be
like, Hey, I have this client where
does not really seeing eye to eye,
but they seem to be great people.
Would you like to meet
her, refer them to you.
And quite often when they do
switch to different, um, team
different, uh, company, it ends
up being a good relationship.
Sometimes it's not, but oftentimes it is.
And professional and
technical communication.
But when it, when you are working
on like coding something or, um,
any kind of a client community
professional communication, it is
always good to keep a paper trail.
And I say paper trail in quotes,
because any more now you're doing
more online paper trail with email
are your project management software,
um, your CRM, something like that.
So it's digital paper.
Um, and document all your work,
all the communications that's done.
So you can always have something to come
back to something, um, that you can either
prove or not reinvent the wheel for say
like you have a site and found out here's
the one that actually happened to me.
We have a client who has.
Detailed, um, gravity farm's set up and,
um, it's in some of the products it has.
Um, some of the form fields, it
has links to the products in them.
And we found out the hard way that
when you run a search and replacing the
database to change URL links, it does not
change them in the gravity form fields.
And so we had to go back through
all the forms with all the products
and them and change out from
the dev links to the live links.
And had I not put that in the comments
at that task and had to do it again,
that could have taken us, you know,
20, 30, 2 minutes, two hours to
remember that that's what had happened.
But if we documented it in like
sitting there, it's like, Hey, I
remember something like this happening.
And you do a search surgeon.
Um, PM software and it pops up that
task that, oh, I get won't do it.
I have to manually replace them all.
It saved you a lot of time.
And then also when you document
everything you do with other people, if
there is an issue arise, you can pull
up that email, pull up that task, pull
up that whatever, and be like, this is
what was said, this is what was done.
Um, Fan of Denzel Washington films.
There was a movie called, um, training
day and one of his quotes was, it's not
what you know is what you can prove.
And that has really struck with
me professionally, because if you
can't prove that you did it, if
you can't prove that you said.
That can sometimes come back to bite you,
especially when there's escalations of
issues of what was done, what wasn't done.
But if you have that paper
trail, it's proven, and there
can not be any arguments on it.
And that also builds trust that
you can pull up those kinds
of things at a later time.
Especially with, since we work in the
world of internet, there's always on
looking, especially if you're using
Chrome and browsers and you should treat
each communication like your grandmother
and the person you look up to most is
reading every thing that you write,
because you want to keep that respect.
You want to keep the honor,
you want to keep that trust.
And in the digital world, it is way too
easy for something we do not want to
come public to be unleashed in the world.
If you want to question that you can
always ask him Kardashians are parasols.
They will be the first to tell
you that sometimes things that
they do not want to get out.
Sure.
Well, and then questions.
Cathy Tibbles: Hi.
Thank you, Michele.
Michele Butcher-Jones: Hello, I
accidentally did a "derr" moment
because my website for my slides are
actually https://mlb.pw/wordfast22.
Back in 2016, change my last
name from Butcher to Jones.
And obviously I have finally hit the
point where instead of not thinking
and using my maiden name, I have
not thought in used my married name.
It's only taken what?
Six years.
Cathy Tibbles: Well, we have the link
across the bottom of the screen now,
so everybody can find the slide deck.
Michele Butcher-Jones: Thank you so much.
Misty Combs: Thank you so much,
Michele, for your presentation.
It was a lot of good information.
I'm sure a lot of it we'll be
able to put to use right away.
Um, if we have time for one question in
a, in the tech community, there's so many
people who are just very painfully shy.
Do you have any words of wisdom
for either improving or starting
communication with somebody who might be
very shy and hard to pull information?
Michele Butcher-Jones: Work on it slowly.
Um, and keep your circle open for it.
Um, like in a lot of times, you see
if you, uh, way back when we were
still going to in-person events, a lot
of people were standing to the sides
and you can see on the, on the side
of, they kind of would like to talk,
but not for sure of how to do it.
Um, kind of go pull them in.
At a slower speed.
I've just kinda be like, Hey,
would you like to come join
us and do have more than.
Smaller type questions of what do you
do in WordPress or, um, what are you
most interested in if you're like in a
setting like this, to do those questions
that are easy to answer and then
progress into a more meaty conversation.
There's a lot of times, once you get the
ball rolling with the more shyer people.
They tend to open up, but if you
kind of just jump into it more of
like the Energizer bunny with, Hey,
my name is Michele, how are you?
What do you do?
Blah, blah, blah, blah, blah, blah, blah.
They're like, nope.
Cathy Tibbles: What about
the open-ended questions?
But do you think that's where
it would come into play?
Michele Butcher-Jones: The open
ended are, tend to be harder for the
more, uh, Quieter types to answer
then the more easier, yes, no.
Um, quick questions, because the
more time they, it takes a person to
think when it comes to on the being
shy, the more it tends to, they tend
to question themselves at first.
But if it's more of something
where they can be confident in
answering, like, you know, um,
what's going to be your favorite.
Topic today or, um, or like, you
know, for wearing like a sh um,
Yoast shirt and coming up and be
like, oh, do you work for Yoast?
And they're like, actually I do.
And kind of bring that out loud.
Misty Combs: Also in the WordPress
community, we are a really diverse
group and very broadly distributed.
Do you have any words of wisdom for
improving or opening communication
between people who may not
have the same native language?
Michele Butcher-Jones: Um, on
that one it's there, it's just
a lot of keep your circle open.
Um, both figuratively and physically,
if you're standing there and you're
having a conversation and that's very
closed, people won't want to try to
join in, but if you stand where you're
more like this, it gives that opening
for people to come in and also like
you're standing there and you're more.
And even in the words that you use in
the tone of voice, you have the more
closed off the more tight you are the
less people will want to interact, but
if you're more open, you see more hand
movement, more talking, more smiling.
Um, people tend to go talk
to those types of people.
Like there is actual, um, studies
that's been done, where if you have
a room full of different types of
people, And you put a child in that
room, they will almost always figure
out who that person who was like the
kindergarten teacher or the nurse, or
S um, the, um, um, policemen or someone
like that, who has that temperament
of always helping are always teaching.
Um, they will find out those people who,
um, to go and talk to, to go and ask,
instead of someone who just kind of gives
off that vibe of kind of closed off-ness.
Misty Combs: And any words of
wisdom or advice in more digital
communication between people who might
not share the same native language?
Michele Butcher-Jones: Use precise
words and do not use slang.
Cathy Tibbles: Yeah, that's a good one.
Michele Butcher-Jones: If you were
trying to talk to people without other
who's in other languages, because they
might not understand what you mean.
Um, like I'm trying to think
of, what's a good slang phrase.
Out of someone like getting
aside to buy something, I'd
be like, shut the front door.
You did not
say that to like someone from,
um, like South Africa or India.
And they're like, I did not open the door.
Yes, I did do it.
Where if you say that to someone
like from the south of America, You
might get a response like yes I did.
Um, but if you use more of the
literal phrases and not sling is
your best way, because also a lot
of people will use Google translate.
And when you put the slang type
of wording in there, sometimes
Google might be like, I don't know,
Misty Combs: For the most intense
you covered some, um, conflict or
dispute situations, but do you have any
go-to phrases to help diffuse those?
Not putting you on the spot?
Michele Butcher-Jones: Now, the
first thing I do is number one,
I do not apologize for anything,
unless it was actually my fault.
Um, just because.
If it's not your fault, it's not
something that you did or your team did.
You don't want really want
to take liability of it.
However, if you change it in, like,
someone's like, I can't believe
this wasn't done, blah, blah, blah.
If this isn't done like
today, we're gonna fire you.
Um, whether it be client or boss,
um, always give the solutions
and be like, okay, um, Thank you.
You can even say, thank you
for reminding me on this.
It did slip through the cracks.
We will get on this.
Or, you know, we had a site that just
completely blew up because it had
a hundred gigs, a mile we're on it.
And you know, that took priority.
Um, always kind of give the
solutions instead of excuses, always.
Okay.
You know, we'll get this done for you.
And it kind of goes back to setting those
boundaries, setting those expectations.
At first, to hear like a lot of
times we will have setbacks on things
and like I'll message the client.
Cause like I already said, like
I would give them a response back
Tuesday by end of day in Tuesday.
We haven't even started it.
I'll message you back and be like,
uh, due to, um, capacity issues.
We are still working on this.
I will give you another update.
X.
I always say I'll give you an update
instead of it will be done by because.
Everyone here in the tech world
knows the whole Murphy's law of
what can go wrong will go wrong.
And especially if you try to
deploy anything on a Friday,
you say update.
I never give definitives because
Ooh, there's something we'll
go two minutes beforehand.
Um,
Misty Combs: thank you
again for everything.
We're a bit over time.
Um,
Michele Butcher-Jones: I do want
to quit, put, put a quick thing out
because of Allie coming on next.
Yes, she did give me a black eye in 2019.
It was quite beautiful.
It was done by makeup.
Uh, she didn't actually clock
me because we did the Halloween
party and I went as a beat up.
Uh, hockey player, this hears
actually I've got recited.
No, Allie Nimmons did
not beat me up again.
Cathy Tibbles: Well, we
can give her a hard time,
Misty Combs: Michele.
And again, we'd like to take an
opportunity to thank our sponsors,
Bluehost, Cloudways, GoDaddy
Pro, Nexcess, Yoast, and Weglot.
Please be sure to visit our
tents and chat with them.
You might even win a prize.
Don't forget to get your photo snapped
in the photo booth, sponsored by
Multicollab and DreamHost and tweet
out the WordFest Live hashtag also
thank you to our media partners and
micro sponsors in the community tent
with the next hour visiting Cloudways.
For the hourly giveaway.
We'd love to have your support
consider donating via the button
on the screen or go to the website.
Um, y'all make a big difference and
big, and our Big Orange Heart is full.
Thank you.
Cathy Tibbles: Thank you.