Nexcess: Oh, great.
My website crashed again.
I give up, don't give up on your
dreams, Jordan, who are you?
It's me.
You from the future.
Your professional website
is not out of reach.
You just need Nexcess.
With Nexcess managed hosting, you
get lightening fast load times
built-in performance monitoring and
updates, and always awesome support.
24 7 365.
For all your projects.
Whoa.
Yeah.
Weglot: Discover Weglot the simple
translation solution for your website.
All you have to do is add Weglot to
your website, select the languages
that you need, and that's it.
Your website is now available
in multiple languages.
Yoast: Do you know, the Yoast SEO,
plugin, they're red, orange, and
green feedback bullets that help
you optimize your posts for the web.
It runs on millions of websites.
We try to make SEO understandable
and accessible to everyone.
Bluehost: Who says building an online
store has to be hard with Bluehost
website builder it's more than just easy.
It's tell us your thing in smart AI.
We'll take it from there.
Easy it's WooCommerce friendly.
So you can add one of these
or swap this for that easy.
It's set up shop in minutes
with unlimited products.
Easy.
Whether you sell boots, books
or bowls, it's create an online
store with Bluehost, easy build
beyond boundaries with Bluehost.
Misty Combs: Welcome back next we welcome
Allie Nimmons as presented for how to use
admin day to manage.
Cathy Tibbles: Allie Nimmons is a
WordPress contributor video producer
writer, active community member.
WordPress became a primary
professional focus for her in 2014.
When she taught herself website,
design and development through
the software, she has spoken at
WordCamps in Miami, Kent Lawson.
Austin or Lando Boston,
New York city and Phoenix.
She has also spoken at WordCamp US,
WordSesh EMA ,WP campus, Laravel
PHP and Fern tech conference.
The under, uh, she is currently a
content freelancer, LinkedIn learning
course instructor and co-founder of
the Underrepresented In Tech database
alleys, mildly obsessed with making
lists, growing plants and knitting.
And she lives in Austin, Texas
with her husband and cat.
We are so grateful to have you.
Allie Nimmons: Hello everyone.
Hello?
Hello.
Thank you so much for having me.
Uh, my, my, my camera's here and I have
two screens, so I apologize if I'm not
making beautiful eye contact with you, but
I'm so happy to be here with you today.
Uh, talking about how I use admin day
to manage my stress as a freelancer.
Uh, and hopefully there's some things that
you can take away from this presentation.
So I had a beautiful introduction just
now, but just a little bit more about me.
I've been freelancing
for about six years now.
Um, I've started a couple of
businesses and I've worked at a
couple of businesses, but I think
my primary heart is in freelancing
business, owning entrepreneurial.
Stuff.
Um, and I do struggle like a lot
of us do, especially these days
with depression and anxiety.
And so I've been really cognizant about
how I can work smarter, not harder
in order to deal with those things.
So this presentation is for you.
If you are a freelancer, a contractor,
or a business owner, anywhere you
fall on that spectrum, um, this
information should be helpful for you.
If you feel any of these things.
This presentation will be helpful for you.
If you're feeling that you have just way
too much to do as you run your business.
If you're feeling as though you lack
organization, or you lack the discipline
that you need to get things done, if
you feel like things just keep falling
through the cracks and you can't get
everything done that you want, if
you're new to freelancing and you're
kind of finding your stride right now,
or if you feel like you don't have a
reliable routine, these are things that.
We all struggle with no matter how
long we've been doing, whatever it is
that we're doing, these are things that
everyone feels and everyone encounters.
Uh, but there are ways to set yourself up
for success and to minimize the effects of
these feelings, uh, as a result of those,
um, feelings, you might additionally
feel overwhelmed, discouraged, lost,
depressed, or anxious, and identify these
things because I think it's important to.
Naming these things and acknowledge
that we are feeling them and kind of
sit with them for a moment and say,
okay, you are in the passenger seat
of my car and I'm going to be driving.
Right.
My depression sits right here with me.
It's with me all throughout the day,
but I'm the one driving my car on the
one, deciding where we're going to.
So you to be thinking to yourself,
well, what the heck is admin day?
What does that mean?
What does that have to do
with mental health in any way?
Any way, shape or form admin day is
the one month, the one day a month,
rather that you set everything else
aside and you treat yourself like your
most important customer or client, your
most valued client, the person that you
have to focus on the most for this one.
It gives you a chance
to prioritize yourself.
So really admin day is a day where you
complete a series of tasks and those
tasks can include, uh, getting caught
up with your bookkeeping or your taxes,
um, reviewing your website and making
any updates, additions, maintenance, uh,
tasks, anything like that, to make sure
that your website is as good as it can.
Uh, any social media planning or
content creation that you want to do.
So scheduling out content or writing
a blog post or working on a video,
any number of things like that?
Uh, cleaning, that's actually kind
of my favorite part on admin day,
I will clean my whole desk area.
I would clean my computers.
I'll clean out my inbox, my email inbox.
I'll get rid of old files and to my
trash and just kind of make sure that
I could start this month with a clean.
This might be a good time to sit down
and do research on something that you've
been wanting to learn or take a class,
take a workshops and things like that.
Um, accountability, we, I feel like
a lot of people like the idea of how
having accountability calls with other
people who run businesses, uh, and
we don't always have time for that.
So this is a good day to set an hour
aside and chat with another business.
Or any reporting or analytics that
you want to do looking back at the
previous month, seeing how things
perform, seeing how things went.
So these are just examples.
This is just a starter list, depending on
the kind of company that you've run, the
services you provide, the products you
create, this, this list can definitely
change and flex depending on you.
Uh, this could also just
be a day off, right?
This could also just be a day where
you treat yourself to a really
fancy, expensive cup of coffee,
where you go spend some time outside.
This is a picture of me on a hike.
I took a couple of months ago, whatever
you feel like you don't normally have
time for anything that you feel could
kind of give you a nice reset, uh, where
you can be kind of quiet and undisturbed.
Admin day is a really good time.
So the number one problem I hear
when I talk to people about it's
like, well, I don't have time.
I don't have time.
I have client work to do I have this.
I have that.
I have a busy schedule.
I have all of these things to do.
How can I take a whole day off every
month to just focus on these other things?
The solution is yes, you do.
Um, I promise you have time.
You can make.
For yourself, right?
You are the most important person you
have to put on your own mask before
you can put on other people's masks
that has a different connotation.
Now doesn't it.
But, uh, you have to help yourself
before you can help others.
Uh, we waste a lot of time throughout
the month with the negative effects
of not doing a lot of these things.
Uh, so if you can take a day for admin
day, you can earn back some of that
time that you might ordinarily do.
Um, and also you always have
time to seed your mental health.
I think that's kind of what big
orange heart, uh, is all about, right.
Is taking that time for yourself
and making sure that you're okay.
This is a really good,
structured way to do that.
So some tips to make sure that your
admin day can go smoothly and that you
can really commit to it, a block that
day off, fully on your calendar so
that if you have a Calendly or anything
like that, people can book time with
you for that day without you noticing.
I just happened to me once or twice
if I forget to block a day off.
Uh, but yeah, block that whole thing
off and make sure that nobody can book.
Communicate with other people in your
life, friends, family, colleagues,
employees, whatever that this is your day
to really focus on what you have to do.
Uh, and it has value beyond just
keeping up with your business.
It has value for your mental health.
Be consistent.
So for example, I really like to do admin
day, the first of every month, whatever
day of the week that happens to fall on.
If you decide I'm going to do every
day or I'm going to do the last
Friday of the month, um, whatever you
decide to do, just stick with that.
And there'll be a lot.
Uh, I really like to try to
get out of my normal space.
So maybe I just work in a
different place in my home.
Um, he used to like to go out to a
coffee shop or a library or something,
but see if you can get out of your
normal space just to shake things up a
little bit, um, especially, you know,
working from home these days can feel
very monotonous and that can really.
Also keep a handy list of
tasks throughout the month.
So maybe a sticky note on your computer
or a note on your desktop or a Google
doc, somewhere that you can throughout
the month say, oh, that's something that
I'd really like to tackle on admin day.
Let me write that down.
So I don't forget that way.
Admin day, you come to your computer and
you see, I have this beautiful list of
things that I've curated throughout the
previous month that I can now work on.
So I feel like there are both short and
long-term benefits to blocking out and
planning and completing an admin day.
Um, these are the things that I feel
the short-term benefits are that you
kind of regain control a little bit.
You can, like I said, have that hard
reset and feel the rest of the month.
Like you have a plan that
you are in control of things.
All those good feelings, right?
You have a positive start to your month.
You're in a good Headspace.
You're in a good place mentally.
And as you go into that next week or next
day, you feel good about yourself, right?
You accomplish something, it's
a confidence booster, right?
I feel kind of like a
boss on admin day, right?
I'm I'm getting everything done.
I'm getting everything taken care of
and looking at how much money I made.
I'm looking at, you know, my
reports, my analytics, the
things that I've accomplished.
It makes me feel good about.
What it is you've accomplished
in the past month.
And what did you hope to
accomplish in the next month?
It also gives you a little
bit of perspective, right?
If you have trouble kind of seeing
the forest for the trees admin
day can give you a really good
overview of what it is you're doing.
So you're not getting lost
in the details as much, which
can cause us a lot of anxiety.
And like I said before, you have usually
a little bit more time in the next month.
You might not be scrambling
for things as much.
Um, you might not be stressing over,
well, I have to get a blog post out this.
I don't have time, but
I really want to do it.
It's already done.
You don't have to think about it.
The long-term benefits.
Um, and again, these are the
things that I've experienced in.
I felt your experience
may vary, obviously.
Um, but it's allowed me to build a
lot of trust in myself, especially
if I'm able to be consistent with it.
I don't, I think I only missed
one admin day last year in 2021.
Uh, and that felt really, really good.
Um, developing those strong habits, right?
It's great.
At the end of the year, to be able
to look back and say, I did my
reporting every single month, and now
I have a whole year's worth of data.
I'm just getting into those habits.
Definitely pays off in the long
run again, saving time, right?
Save so much time throughout the year.
Uh, especially for
things like bookkeeping.
When you go to sit down to do your taxes
quarterly, yearly, however you do it.
Um, you don't have to scramble
around and collect things.
You have everything in one.
It strengthens your business, right?
If you're able to get that content
out, that you've been meaning to
write and get your stuff organized,
it's going to help strengthen the
business in little ways here and there.
The more organized you can be and
the more mentally fit you feel,
uh, and just logistically sets you
up for success, getting all your
ducks in a row is never a bad thing.
So.
Admin day for me was only a couple
of days ago, as I said, I usually
do it the first of the month.
So Tuesday was my admin day.
Uh, and just an example
of this is what I did.
I, uh, did a lot of bookkeeping.
I cleaned everything up.
Right.
My favorite part, I scrubbed down my desk.
I just conducted everything.
Um, I moved in, I canceled a
bunch of subscriptions because
I accidentally put a bunch of
business stuff on my PayPal account.
And I was like, oh no, that needs to
be in my business, blah, blah, blah.
And I didn't have time in the
month to go back and fix it.
So I was able to do that.
Uh, it is tax season.
So I was working on my taxes and that
was a very stressful and not fun.
Um, but what I did do that was really
fun as I sat right over there behind
the camera, where I have a nice
little, uh, seating area, and I read a
bunch of articles and blog posts that
I'd been wanting to read throughout
the month, that I didn't have time
to, uh, with a nice cup of tea.
And it was really, really relaxing.
So my previous admin day was actually
a little bit stressful because of the
taxes, but now I feel so much better.
It's out of the way and off my plate.
So I want to hear from you,
if you do something like admin
day, I've heard people do like
smaller admin days every week.
Like it'd be Friday.
Um, yes or no.
Is this something that you would be
interested in starting or is this
something that you've already done?
Not for you.
Uh, you can find me on Twitter at
Ellie underscored humans, and I'd
really, really love to hear from you
and hear what you do on admin day.
That could maybe inspired me as well.
Um, so yeah, if we have any questions,
I'd be super happy to answer.
Cathy Tibbles: Hi.
Thank you so much, Allie.
Allie Nimmons: Hi, thank you.
Thank you.
It was a pleasure.
Cathy Tibbles: Yeah, that was live right.
Or was that a recorded?
Allie Nimmons: That was live.
Cathy Tibbles: How are you feeling?
Allie Nimmons: Good.
I feel like I talked really, really
fast, which is a bad habit of mine.
I'm sorry.
I was really excited
Cathy Tibbles: and it was great.
I'm curious how you came up
with the idea or did you come
up with the idea of Admin Day?
Allie Nimmons: I don't remember.
I honestly don't remember.
I think it might, it might've been
something that I heard somebody
else like write a blog post or
talk about it a long time ago, but
I've been doing it for many years.
And so it's now just kind of like a habit.
I don't really remember where
I learned, but I've evolved it.
Right.
Like figured out new things to
do over time and stuff like that.
I have a little running list, but,
um, yeah, I don't really remember
where I first heard about it.
Cathy Tibbles: Do you know?
A person would do if they
weren't a freelancer, would
you still think an admin day?
Like I'm just thinking self care day.
Allie Nimmons: I mean, mental
health days and self-care
days are remarkably important.
Like whether you feel like you need it or
not, like, I feel like a lot of us will
say like, oh, I don't something happened
or maybe I don't feel great today.
And I'm going to, I'm going to
take a mental day for myself.
Um, I'd love to normalize.
Taking a day, once a month,
even when you don't need it.
Right.
Like preventative care
rather than reactive care.
Um, so yeah, like I don't see
anything wrong with that at all.
I think that would be great.
And especially if you feel like you have
tasks that you'd like to get caught up
on, um, even if it's just catching up
on a TV show or something like that,
like if you could say, all right, I'm
going to make a little to-do list for
myself so that I can cause one of the
things I really love about admin day is
that feeling at the end of the day, it's
like I checked everything off my list.
Um, I completed everything and that,
that always gives me a nice little kind
of confidence boost of, like I said, I
was going to do something and I did it.
And that feels real.
Cathy Tibbles: I could also
see that working for people.
Like I find to do lists
to be a lot of pressure.
So I kind of organize it as in like
kind of a things I want to accomplish
in a week, but I could still see that
working really well because there'll
be the day when I don't have it to do.
Allie Nimmons: Yeah, for sure.
If that's, if that's what you need,
like, I love the fact that it's,
it's a flexible concept, right?
To say, I'm going to take this day.
To-do list every other day of the year.
Today is the one day I'm not going
to make it to do list, right.
If that's what you need for yourself.
And that's, so that's very valuable and,
uh, introspective to be able to identify
what you need and go ahead and do that.
Cathy Tibbles: I just think
it's such a great idea.
Have you heard of time-blocking?
Allie Nimmons: I do time blocking.
I started doing time blocking this
year, um, more than I used to.
Um, and yeah, I find it very.
calming.
Cause I don't ever have to think
about what do I need to be doing
what I need to be working on.
Like I always have, I can just
look at my calendar and it tells
me what to do and when I go do it.
Cathy Tibbles: If I don't have
it time blocked, I'm just like
putting out fires all day.
It's just like, I just let the
email dictate my day instead
of what I should be doing.
And I find it, the talk
reminded me of something.
Um, like I divide my company
tasks into a bunch of stuff.
And the one that always gets ignored
for me is research and development.
Like with the manufacturing
has to get done.
In our freelance world, it's,
you know, getting the code or the
site done or out to the client.
Yeah.
The customer service, the marketing, it's
kind of like your content, your videos,
like they have to get done, but actually
the time to read those articles, like you
were saying, Get better at your craft.
You have to prioritize that stuff.
Allie Nimmons: Yeah.
That's, that's one of my favorite
parts of the day and that's that's,
I feel like the number one thing
that I tend to put off throughout the
month, um, is yeah, it's like, okay.
I, I use this one videos, like for
my next admin day, I really want to
take time to like learn a new video
editing software because I've been
using the same for a long time.
It's been getting on my nerves.
I don't have time usually to just say,
I'm going to completely switch to this
other thing and learn it on the fly.
Right?
Like that's so stressful.
So to say, okay, I'm going
to take it after noon.
I'm going to block it off.
If somebody asks me to do
something, I'm going to say no.
Um, that is very empowering.
Right?
Cause it, I think that that's
another thing too about this
whole thing is for that day, you,
you can say no to everything.
Somebody sends you a DM or an email.
You don't have to answer it.
And I think that, um, That at
least for me, gives me a lot of
confidence as a business owner to
say, like, I am prioritizing myself.
I appreciate that you need something,
but I will get to it tomorrow.
Um,
no.
Cathy Tibbles: No, uh, you know, Amy
Porterfield, um, years ago, I listened
to her all the time and she had, I think
she called it dragon hour, power hour.
I'm not sure, but, but she's prolific
content creator, but there's two
or three hours in the morning.
Her team didn't even contact her.
Like they protected her little bubble
and that was her time to work like do
not poke the bear between this time and
this time, it just reminds me of that.
Like the people who are really productive,
you have to focus on what you want.
To get the work for your
mental health, right?
Yeah.
Allie Nimmons: Especially if you're in a
period of, well, we should all be learning
all the time, but if you're in a period
of like, all right, I I'm freelancing
or I started this business, whatever the
case may be and now I want to scale it.
Right.
I want to grow, I want to add
a new service or I want to, you
know, maybe hire somebody right.
When, when you feel like, okay,
I need to get to that next level.
You have to be able to prioritize,
well, like, how am I going to do that?
I need.
Time away from my clients and my
deliverables and all those things,
and really get my ducks in a row and
learn what I need to learn in order
to scale to that, to that next level.
Cause I feel like that's, that's
such a big reason why people
struggle with scaling or don't
scale is because they don't have.
The, the, the background foundational
knowledge to, to do whatever comes
with that next phase of their business.
Um, and so it's, it's hard to get there
if you don't know what you have to do.
Um, and yeah, when you have to pay
bills and, uh, you know, meet whatever
monetary goals that you have, it can
feel really scary to say, like, I'm not
going to put in billable hours to do.
Right.
Like, that's super scary.
If you have bills to pay, they say,
I'm not going to make money today.
I'm going to work on myself, but
in the long run, I think it does
enable you to grow and scale it
to make more money, you know?
So, yeah, it has, it has
all kinds of benefits
Cathy Tibbles: It does and, you
know, it's easy to say that we
prioritize our mental health.
It's harder to do when you're taking
cash off the table, but that's,
short-sighted like in the long-term.
Allie Nimmons: Yeah, yeah, for sure.
And so I, you know, if it's a matter
of, um, you know, I'm gonna reserve
an afternoon to do all to do some of
this kind of stuff, and then maybe
work your way up to a whole day, right?
Like, like you were saying, that
woman just had a chunk of time in
the morning that could work too.
Right.
It can be whatever you can
manage to do at that time.
But I think it's always worthwhile
to say, I'm going to put aside any
amount of time for myself, and then
you can grow that as you're able to.
Cathy Tibbles: And you've
been doing this for years.
Yeah.
Wow.
That's very cool.
Two minutes.
So I'm wondering if we can pick
Misty's brain and Liquid Web.
Do you have like, can people take, I
hope I'm not ousting something bad, but
can I, can people take like a morning?
Either do work-related R and D
gonna learn more about something,
but like not working on a project.
Misty Combs: We, we do have a lot of
flexibility, even just, if you want to
adjust your schedule to accommodate self
care mental health time, um, we have
a lot of support for that, but we also
have, um, a lot of leaders who give a
lot of flexibility and an independent
scheduling to their staff all the time.
So it is important that not that we
don't have that much and we don't have
things that need to get accomplished,
but at the end of the day, if I am
completely burned out and I am completely
exhausted, I'm not able to commit
the things that I need to do anyway.
So, so there's definitely an
encouragement take your PTO tip.
Take the time that you
need flex your schedule.
Take care of yourself.
Take care of your family.
Cathy Tibbles: PCO, did you say PCO?
Misty Combs: PTO.
So like your Paid Time Off.
Cathy Tibbles: Okay.
Okay.
That was HR speak.
That's good.
It's nice to see the bigger
companies, but we also do.
Misty Combs: We've also done a
lot, the things that stress people.
So when we, we became a more work
from home organization, we tried to do
things that help people be connected.
We also tried to do things
for all kinds of wellness.
Um, we have.
Zoom based yoga.
We have had series of financial education.
We have, uh, um, health and wellness,
diet, diet, mental health, um,
mindfulness, all kinds of activities
that people can participate in
when they're feeling stressed in
whatever way, they're feeling stress,
trying to give them some resources.
Cathy Tibbles: Yeah, that is cool.
Allie, can I switch
topics just for a second?
What is the Underrepresented
In Tech database?
Allie Nimmons: Oh, I was
hoping you'd ask me that.
Um, Underrepresented In Tech is a
database that, uh, myself and Michelle
Frechette, we co-founded together.
Um, because honestly we work at it.
Tired of people coming to us and
saying, um, you know, I'm looking to
hire someone or I'm looking to, um, get
people to apply, to speak at my event.
And I want to make sure that it's
a group, a diverse group of folks.
Do you know anybody?
Can you recommend anybody?
Can you ask people to
apply blah, blah, blah.
And we had a conversation about how
great it is that people want that, but
how it sucks up a lot of our time and
our energy, um, to have to like, Yeah.
Yeah.
Um, and we were like, wouldn't it
be great if we had like a, like
a giant spreadsheet or something?
Um, and they were like,
oh, that's kind of weird.
Just add people to a spreadsheet
without their permission.
Oh, what if it was like a database
where people could add themselves?
Uh, and so we just kind of started
running with that idea and we got a lot
of support from the community around it.
Um, Gravity forms and gravity view donated
software for us to be able to build it.
Our hosting was donated, uh,
Yoast has donated, um, you
know, premium SEO tools to us.
Um, there's a whole list of
sponsors on our website, if
you want to check that out.
But yeah, it is a, it is a
database where folks who.
Fall into any of the underrepresented
boxes within the tech industry.
So people of color, people who identify
as a women, people who might be older
than the average person who works in
tech, people who have some sort of
disability who are neurodivergent, who
are on the LGBTQIA plus spectrum, they
can add themselves to this database and
say, Hey, yeah, look, I check this box.
I am a marketer and a designer,
and this, these are the kinds of
opportunities I'm looking for.
I'd love to join a podcast or speak at
an event, and they add themselves to that
database and event organizers, business
owners, podcast hosts, uh, people from all
over can come to that database, plug in
what the it is that they're looking for.
So looking for a marketer to speak
on my podcast, and they're met with
a list of people, um, that they can
then contact, um, The only thing that
the searcher does not see is how that
person identifies as underrepresented.
So for example, if you're gay and you
add yourself to the database, the search
result is not going to say I'm gay, right.
That information is private and
Michelle, and I just use it as a
qualifier to make sure that nobody
is, is being lame and abusing it.
Um, but it, it has allowed us to.
Empower people with the ability
to prioritize diversity within our
community, without tokenizing people.
So you can go up to somebody and say,
Hey, I found you through the database
because I'm prioritizing diversity for
this project, but I'm approaching you.
And I'm asking you to apply for this
thing because of that, because you're an
expert marketer and I'm impressed with
what I saw, um, because we just, we have
a, we have a problem right now with.
People are having a hard time finding
the right ways to prioritize diversity.
And so they don't do it, um, and need,
Cathy Tibbles: It's hard for people
to ask are you special in any way?
Yeah, just somebody that looks different
than me, who also happens to be X word.
It can be an awkward conversation to
breach, especially with the person
that you maybe have never met before.
Um, and so we wanted
to make it easier for.
Um, and yeah, so we, we built
the database and it's been,
it's been really successful.
We have about 120 people
in the database right now.
Um, we don't track how it's used.
So, um, we don't have like data
analytics about like what companies
I've searched or what candidates have
gotten context or anything like that.
It is, as soon as you find
someone in the database, you can.
You know, send them an email or however
they have preferred to be contacted.
Um, and then that is a conversation for,
for those two people to have together.
Um, we also started a podcast.
Um, I don't really even remember why
we started the podcast, like what
the particular impetus was for that.
But Michelle and I have a lot of
conversations between the two of
us about things that frustrated.
Um, around DEI in this
community in particular.
And so on that podcast, we talk
about, um, all kinds of topics that
affect underrepresented people.
But also we try to provide information
that's useful for allies and people who
want to help underrepresented people
to get more opportunities and have
those conversations in an easier way.
Um, So, yeah, so it's a database
with the podcast that she
and I have started together.
Um, yeah, it's something that we're,
we're really, really proud of.
Is there anybody, are you
still open to people coming on?
Like if somebody sees this and
wants those opportunities, they can.
Allie Nimmons: Yes, absolutely.
So, absolutely.
Yes.
You can go to the website
https://underrepresentedintech.com.
Um, we have no plans of ever like.
Closing it as of right now, like it is
open for anyone, any, anybody at any time
in any place to, uh, to go to, so, oh
yeah, you have it pulled up right there.
So yeah, if you scroll up to the top of
the site there, um, there's a section
called on looking for opportunities
and somebody can click submit
profile and there's a little form.
They can add themselves to that
within 24 hours, um, Michelle, or I
will just let that person make sure
it's not spam or anything like that.
Um, and add them to the database.
And once they're added, uh, they can
come up in whatever searches applied to
them and they also have an individual.
Um, like page.
So if you search and find a person, you
can click on their name or their photo,
and they have a designated page on
the site that, you know, if they would
like to share and move like a resume
website or something, they have a page
that has all of their qualifications
and contact information on it.
Cathy Tibbles: So you'd recommend
that we, that people who are applying
to this database put something
similar to their LinkedIn or whatever
they're comfortable with the public.
Allie Nimmons: Exactly.
Exactly.
So we ask you for a bio, we ask
you for whatever social media
you're comfortable sharing.
If you have a website, uh, to add
that, and we asked him, you know,
what, what do you specialize in?
What do you do?
Are you, are you an SEO person?
Are you a developer or do
you work with e-commerce?
We have plans in the next month
to add more of those kinds of,
um, skills to the site as well.
Um, and then you get to choose what
opportunity you're looking for.
Um, because there are lots of job
boards out there and we didn't
really want this to be a job board.
We wanted it to be a place where somebody
is like, well, I have a job, but I'd like
to expand my reach into the community.
I want to speak at events.
I want to be on podcasts.
I want to participate in other ways
so they can choose which opportunities
they would like to be contacted.
Cathy Tibbles: That is really awesome.
Good for you guys.
Thank you for coming on and the talk, did
you have any other last minute thoughts?
Allie Nimmons: Um, no.
I just hope that everyone
enjoys the rest of the event.
And, uh, please thank an emcee
or an organizer or a volunteer
because they work amazingly hard.
Um, for no money, a lot of volunteers
they're doing it out of the goodness of
their hearts and it's extremely admirable.
Uh, so yeah.
Thanks.
If you're watching, please take a
moment to thank somebody, um, because
yeah, it's, this is a beautiful
event and a beautiful thing, and I'm,
I'm just overwhelmed with emotion.
Cathy Tibbles: This is wonderful.
Thank you, Allie.
Thank
Allie Nimmons: you.
Have a great rest today then.
Misty Combs: Thank you, Allie.
So again, we'd like to take an opportunity
to thank our sponsors, Bluehost,
Cloudways, GoDaddy Pro, Nexcess,
Yoast, and Weglot, please be sure to
visit their tents and chat with them.
You might even win a prize.
Don't forget to get your photo snapped in
the photo booth, sponsored by Multicollab
and Dreamhost and tweeted out with the
WordFest Live hashtag also thank you to
our media sponsors and micro-sponsors.
In the, in the community tent
for the next hour is Cloudways.
With our hourly giveaways.
There'll be a bit of a break in the
schedule now, head over to the community
tent and we'll be back at the start
of the hour off the Asian content.
We would love it.
If you'd sponsor, please consider
donating via the button on the screen
to go to the Big Orange Heart website.
You all make our Big Orange Heart.
Thank you.