Nexcess: Oh, great.
My website crashed again.
I give up, don't give up on your
dreams, Jordan, who are you?
It's me.
You from the future.
Your professional website
is not out of reach.
You just need Nexcess.
With Nexcess managed hosting, you
get lightening pass load times
built-in performance monitoring and
updates, and always awesome support.
24 7 365.
For all your plans.
Whoa.
Yeah.
Weglot: Discover Weglot the simple
translation solution for your website.
All you have to do is add Weglot to
your website, select the languages
that you need, and that's it.
Your website is now available
in multiple languages.
Yoast: Do you know, the Yoast SEO,
plugin, they're red, orange, and
green feedback bullets that help
you optimize your posts for the web.
It runs on millions of websites.
We try to make SEO understandable
and accessible to everyone.
Bluehost: Who says building
an online store has to be hard
with Bluehost website builder.
It's more than just easy.
It's tell us your thing in smart AI.
We'll take it from there.
Easy it's WooCommerce friendly.
So you can add one of these
or swap this for that easy.
It's set up shop in minutes
with unlimited products.
Easy.
Whether you sell boots, books
or bowls, it's create an online
store with Bluehost, easy build
beyond boundaries with blue house.
Yogesh Londhe: Right now we are in
Asia session and this is a part of
24 hours celebration of the people,
the technology and the Big Orange
Heart of WordPress, WordFest Live, not
only delivers festivals, educational
content, wellness sessions, and
networking opportunities, but it also
is a fundraiser for Big Orange Heart.
Please visit that donate link
at any time to support the
mission of our organisation.
WordFest Live is a 24 hour opportunity for
the WordPress community to come together,
to feel less isolated, learn from one
another and be present with each other.
Yes.
Yeah.
Lax Mariappan: Yeah.
So we are the Emcee's for this session.
I'm lax.
I'm a backend engineer at WebDevStudios.
And I, I love WordPress and
all the WordPress communities,
so glad you're here.
And I hope you, aren't all
excited for session, Yogesh.
Yogesh Londhe: Yes, I am excited for
all the sessions and even this one.
So our first speaker in Asia
is a Leo Postovoit . I hope
I pronounced that correct.
And he's going to give a session on why.
Website performance as a mindset, Leo
heads, product and partnership at XWP.
One of my favorite organizations,
a long time technologist Leo has
worked for various publishers,
including San Francisco Chronicle, the
Denver post and low rider magazine.
With a background in design marketing
and software engineering, Leo advises
on best practices for usability
deployment and performance, across
many verticals from publishing and
e-commerce to education and nonprofit.
Leo, we are here for you.
Hey everyone.
My name is Leo Postovoit.
I'm head of product strategy
and partnerships, XWP.
It is a very early.
5:08 AM.
This is a real live clock.
Uh, this is not some strange recording
from a distant past in the future, uh,
here in Germany where I am currently
based, but I'm also doing some stuff
in APAC and also, uh, in the US I'm
really excited today to talk to you
about website performance as a mindset.
And also I'm excited to kick off
things here in the Asia session.
For WordFest live 2022.
So, um, if you have real
questions, I'm a real human being.
It's good to see you all excited to
see everything as we all come together
for this wonderful session here today.
So first things first, I wanted to
talk a little bit about XWP, uh,
awesome organization that I work with.
Um, we are focused on building
a better web at enterprise.
So, what this means for us is we
build performance web class with
world-class solutions for enterprise
media and technology companies.
Um, which means the very best in
technology and the very best sites
that run on that same technology.
And so we work in a variety of verticals
across the web, everything from awesome
publishers to awesome technology
companies, to really cool things in
education and video games and nonprofits.
And.
But that's really not what you're
here to talk about, uh, with me today,
what you really want to hear about is
the growth and performance mindset.
So as we unpack and understand the ideas
surrounding the web, we want to understand
how we measure what success looks like.
So how exactly do we measure success?
Well, do you know that that bare metric,
uh, idea performance isn't measurable in a
single number or a single way at a level?
You have probably a dozen different
metrics for your organization or
your clients even on, on site.
Um, as we unpack this conversation,
you'll see that I'm really trying to
help you have the tools and language
to understand how you'll be able to
engage with your audiences or your site
or your customers in ways that will.
In terms of performance, you might
measure them already around things
like form conversion, checkouts, or
maybe click through rates, sometimes
organizations even further, and they might
say appointments booked or NPS scores,
costumes, customer success surveys.
I find that.
All of these scores are really
good to useful, but there's a key
metric that seems to come up again
and again with us that we find that
it's really useful for your team.
Be able to think about at a high
level, uh, in terms of things you can
do to improve your overall scores.
And that is page speed and page
speed and slow loading as a whole.
We find that if you don't do this
correctly, you'll have a softer
score across all of these other.
So, if you find that your page good
scores are slow through lighthouse
are page speed insights or anything
else that you're doing altogether,
you probably should start there.
And then we continue
to optimize from there.
Um, there was a great study done a
couple of, uh, a couple of years ago
now because COVID brain and everything
else as is the other, uh, Deloitte did
a wonderful study and, uh, early 2020
that talked about the ideas of what
it meant to optimize for page views.
So when these things come
together, we really think you
need to care about your users.
And what delights said was that if
you give your customers the kind of
experience that exact you'd expect
to watch these customers to be happy,
otherwise they would leave quickly.
And within this, we saw that at
based on a 0.1 second, natural
mobile student group grouping.
We saw a positive change, the
number of page views version rates.
And in some cases we saw for
just a single 0.1 second.
So a hundred milliseconds in total, we
saw retail conversions increased by 8.4%.
And an average order value is by 9.2.
So pretty substantial as these things go.
Um, in terms of page speed, we
find that if organizations care
about these things, you'll be
able to grow pretty substantially.
Uh, actually people like to call
this as the mindset of these
as this is coming together.
So performance is a mindset is
critical because if you can't
identify all the factors that are.
You won't be able to make the data
driven decisions that will be able to
help you understand what would be able
to make it, make you drive further.
So if you can decide what you want
to focus on first, you'll have to
ultimately sacrifice the things
that would be helping you along the
way, especially in the context of.
Um, another great case study that
we'd like to talk about is a case that
he's done about 10 years ago from an
Austin journal called behavioral and
behavior and information technology.
And so this was done back before
mobile technology was the norm back
before we thought mobile technology
would be the, uh, the standard across.
And at the time when people weren't
engaging just with desktops, which
are typically slower as a part of the
experience, they'd found that users
will Bandon a webpage bending to
form it 50, 50 milliseconds of delay.
I prevented them being able to engage.
And so if we found is that it's
critical for you to focus on eight and
it prevents your users to be happy.
So if you're finding that you have 50,
50 milliseconds or more of delay beyond
what standards, Hey, you're not going
to be able to engage with users at a
high level and you should be tracking.
The numbers from 10 years ago are
just as true as they are today.
And so if your numbers don't meet the
thresholds for critical, do your best.
So as we look at this idea of web
experience, as well as this idea of
content as a whole, we really unpack this
through will be called the four pillars.
So our next WP, we talk about this
four pillar experience as a holistic
look, and that holistic look talks
with the idea of an experiential.
So these four experiences, aren't
just focused on any one of these, but
rather they're together interlinked.
Um, and we're going to talk primarily
about page speed, but I've been
cooking mentioned the others as well.
You spell it out for us as measured
through the concepts of UX and design.
So this is a measurable way of
understanding how easy it is to
engage the webpage conversion.
As you probably understand from a forum or
booking journey, something that will tell
us whether a user actually did the thing.
And retention either.
Are they continuing to come back
to that customer journey experience
as we expect them to, or maybe the
second or seven or 12 purchase, right.
We want to be able to see are they
doing the things they want to do, but
if we were to pinpoint to a single
metric of these four things, the XVP
considers to be the sort of critical
elements around Patriot experience.
We see that, I'm sorry.
I brought up performance
and the experience, the pain
space is the critical element.
So what that means for us as to how
long it takes a user to make a request,
to build all this into the background
and deliver that back to that browser.
And so if you don't have good page
experience, we will see all, all of
these four metrics will be slower
and lower than with like humidity.
And so what we find is that if you just
focus on page B, just focus on this
as a starting element, you can do why
the bit to get started with, because.
And so page speed, we find
impacts nearly every site metrics.
So also things like conversion,
things like time on site, bounce rate,
things that will go even further.
And page speed has a ton of
metrics, uh, within these
different elements you can pull up.
Um, however, we'd like to ideally focus on
just a tiny subset at least a day, because
we know that this has a critical metric,
an oven that's just like to focus on.
We talk about these things
as the core website.
So the court vitals are a little bit
confusing, but I promise you by the end of
the day, stop, we'll be able to help you
understand what you can do to be able to
pull from a further level of what's there.
So, uh, Google defines the core
bottles as a framework to measure
your users page speed experience.
Um, that sounds like a big
topic, but I promise you it's
relatively straightforward.
So previously before 2020.
Things such as time to first bite,
especially in the context of posting
or first Contentful paint, which
is how quickly it'll take to load
something on the screen or the time
to interact in that amount of time.
It takes to load all those obstacles on
the page and get all thinking right there.
Well, Google bot and Chrome and other
power special up to 200 different
metrics of a pace speed, uh, on
a site as well as all the other.
Each of these different elements
are kind of confusing because
there's a lot of things that seem
to overlap on top of each other.
And it's hard to say, well, whether
it a good FCP will provide a good
experience, if ultimately you want it.
I use it to interact after
all, a lot of discussion.
Google came together inside of the
three metrics, the large screen
temporal paint, the first input delay
and the creative layout shift are
actually the three critical things
you probably should be focusing on.
And I know this is going to sound
a little bit confusing because
there's a lot of numbers of lumps
from a purchase we're talking about.
But let's talk about this from the user
perspective, because users ultimately
will tell us what you want to do.
And from a user perspective, we
like to think about, you know, the
idea of core vitals, uh, to be happy
and loyal, want users to be happy
and engaged with our platforms.
We want project product managers
who are building platforms with
us, or with websites, thus, we'll
be talking about, yes, there's you
have to be in future customers or
happy, or, Hey, should we feature?
Africans are happy or
Hey should be feature.
And our suppliers are happy.
We'll want to be ultimately
trying to move things on.
Developers really like to see if
the core vitals as a meaningful
metric that is actually measurable
in a neutral way across all sites.
If you have good fast scores and
everyone's happy, then executives,
of course, who are paying for these
types of things are looking to monitor
these things in terms of success.
So this is, that's an
opportunity for business growth.
All of these three metrics.
Let's talk about what they
mean and how we define them.
So with LCP, we're focusing on.
At a basic level we want to define
is the thing that we want to see
actually loading in an efficient way.
Uh, if LCP is a lower than 2.5 seconds
threshold, we know that load is too
slow for what users are expecting in
terms of FID we're expecting for the
first interaction that a user wants.
So in this case, we have an example of
a user trying to interact with a search
widget or perhaps on a menu or a back
button, whatever it might be on that given
application, especially in the context of.
If the application is not responsive
and a facet of experience,
the user is going to leave.
And the public one to build a bad trust
that experts is there in terms of FID,
we're expecting at least a hundred
millisecond response or faster to be able
to determine what's going to be good.
And the most egregious I
like to call out is CLS.
So you probably have experienced this,
this one's at some point in your, and
your time on the internet, you've been
trying to go to cancel button, but
instead you actually ended up hitting.
And depending on the submit button
by mistake, this is because that CLS
has this idea of positioning where
things don't necessarily line up.
So perhaps you're trying to engage
with content, but you see an ad.
Maybe you want to click.
Yes.
But you see no that the simple.
We don't want you to experience
things that are ultimately driving
you down the wrong direction.
So of these three things, we find that
if you have a good LCP, so a really
fast loading site in low FID and easy
to interact with score that allows you
to interact with the application and
the low CLS where they lay out does
not shift very frequently and very low
altogether within the page painting,
you have a good experience there.
And so, uh, across the board, one of
our key partners, Google, we worked with
last five or six years at this point,
we've seen that they've seen incredible
growth, uh, with various customers.
So on this first example with G
I G E D I a group, a editorial
publisher out of Italy, they saw an
incredible increase, um, with these
types of scores by decreasing CLSC.
So by increasing these things we
saw in major increase in basic
performance, things that were there.
So by decreasing CLS, we saw that
people didn't leave a site sending,
uh, Lazada, a Singapore based site.
We saw by decreasing LCP.
We saw an increase in conversion rate
by 17%, pretty high scoring us there.
And then, yeah, which I believe
is a, um, a Korean website.
We saw a decrease of LCP with an
increase of the rate by a hundred.
So pretty powerful scores that we're
able to increase over time with a
certain amount of focus on metrics.
So if need, ultimately try to improve
these basic scores, we should see at
basic increase in engagement, but that's
bounce rate conversion rate, click
through rate three different metrics.
You might measure it in terms
of success for your given.
Well, Y one of the things at a
basic level is that core vitals
are about user engagement.
They're not just measurements of
what it's pinned on the page, but
there are other focused on the
things that will show when users.
So if you ultimately delay content,
when it doesn't allow users to engage,
people will ultimately get away quickly.
We also find that in terms
of publishing content.
So this is typically focused on new
sites, but it does apply to blog sites.
The huge sector within WordPress, we found
that people will, will no longer engage
them as that we're expecting for them.
And they give good scores.
We usually see a 23% lower
abandonment rate in those sites
with excellence, core models.
That's what we're after.
We want people to be engaging and to be
happy with the content they're getting.
So all of a sudden done, I think it's
tips of Google are great for you,
but how does that actually matter
for your, your website, your site?
It's probably running on WordPress
and really focused on content.
Well, you distill this down to three best
practices, uh, and primarily paid speed
being our main guidance, because we think
that's probably the first thing you need
to care about because it seems that like
most sites today, for some reason on the
web don't care as much as they could.
First, we want you to understand
your current state of your
site or multiple sites of.
Second.
We want you to evaluate that and determine
how you get your use with the need.
And then third, we want you to
ultimately transform and to treat
performance as your long-term goal.
So within these three, we're going to
spend a couple of minutes here going
through each of these processes to
determine the best practice of how we
ultimately shift these things forward.
So first, do you actually understand your
current state of your websites before.
Um, we use a variety of tools, uh,
that we think are really useful.
So one of them we find
that's really critical.
It's free.
It's easy to do is a tool
called page speed insights.
So Patriot insights is probably our main
tool because it's a neutral heuristic.
Anyone can use this.
It's a self hosted, sorry, a cloud
hosted version of lighthouse, uh, on
the web that who uses that you can,
uh, mutually determine a score based
on the improvements of lab data.
And also synergizes some data from crux,
the crumb user experience apart, and will
tell us about how fast the website is.
We have a couple of other tools
with the are really critical, like
Google search console will tell
you about errors and warnings.
Google analytics will tell you about how
successful you are getting to certain
goals within the site and how you navigate
through these different things that are
there to Libra, which we find is really
useful for determining the overall
health within a site and the lab scores
across over time and new Relic, which
should tell you about server performance.
Ultimately, we want to be able to
determine a good set of lab scores
and a good set of, uh, uh, real
user metrics scores, field scores.
If you will, within this, we want
you to ultimately measure good
grades, but also aim for results.
You want to find how far gets
and to continue to move along.
So of all of these though, there's
a lot of tools we've talked about.
The one I'll mention
again, is page insights.
So the nice thing about business,
that it's a Google hosted lighthouse
scoring that as relatively neutral.
So if you poke and prod at this, and
here's an example of xDB the site
that we help maintain, you'll see
that we've got a pretty good score.
It's because we spent a lot of time
caring and concerning ourselves
with what our users are seeking in.
The wild that field data is based
off of real users and what they're
actually seeing in the wild.
The overall lab score will be helpful
to determine and tell you like how
far along the way you've gotten.
Uh, but ultimately if your scores are
good, it's like getting too many results.
If your at scores are low, though,
it's going to give you a huge set
of actionable recommendations.
For example, can you improve the
way your fonts are delivered?
Can you improve the way your media is
delivered in terms of images or videos?
There's a lot you can do typically.
Even more so though, if you haven't
actually paid attention to a
basic concept of user experience,
so take your actual phone.
And so for me here, it's 5.48.
And again, it's a real time.
I'm here in a live conversation
with Hugh out here with you,
uh, for work best live 2022.
You want to actually
examine what your users are.
So, if you see that your users
are getting lots of ads and the
concept of getting is a headline.
So here is a pretty terrible
example of a fake news experience
where the headline is cut off.
And we have an ad above an ad
above a newsletter, above a prompt.
We install and install the app button.
Right?
Pretty typical of the experience
you're getting across the web.
We don't want.
At a basic level, similar to the
principles of agile, the agile manifesto.
Many years ago, we care more
about content than advertisements.
We care more about integration
and attraction that we do
about prompts and distraction.
We care more about delightful
experiences than we do about conversion.
If you create experiences that people
want to engage with the things they're
presenting, then people are probably
going to more likely to present themselves
with the corn twins use to practice.
So, if you can focus on your user, as
opposed to your conversion goal, the
user will more likely one to convert.
And if you fail the critical task of
ultimately getting the user, what they
came for, they're going to abandon.
And if they abandoned nothing
else matters, you failed on a
basic premise of what you can do.
So if you aren't doing a good enough
job being introspective on what
things are there, then you use,
those are likely going to leave.
And we think that's a critical thing you
should be doing as a review of all of
your sites, of all events you're touching
you could be doing in front of you.
Um, well that's the
first part of us, right?
In terms of content, we probably also
want to consider the other elements of.
Um, I'm going to list here.
Just four things we thought over the
last couple of years are critical
for you to pay attention to.
So for products that we've ultimately
worked on over the last few years,
that we think can help with these
things along the way, if you thought
with the content journey, at least
for our some awesome plugins that
are free and widely available across.
The first is jet pack boost.
So this is a free plugin
that helps you with improving
CSS and JavaScript delivery.
The second is the amp for WordPress
plugin, which helps things like, um,
providing critical CSS, uh, within
the webpage, uh, that your ultimate.
Google scikit-learn should provide in-page
analysis in terms of the things you're
doing for analytics, pretty powerful
tool built in, uh, to a lot of different
aspects of WordPress and the PWA plugin,
which makes progressive web as possible to
do things like offline node and a backer
and rendering a content in fast way.
All of these performance related
plugins can take your experience
even further if you paid attention
to that experience of style.
So give your users what they want
as early and often as possible.
You can be.
So after hearing all of this, how
do you make sure this is going
to happen over the longterm?
Well, it becomes about strategy.
You no longer need to worry about
the remediation problem, but rather
the strategic long-term problem.
So the elegant experiments should be
ultimately focused on the realities
of technology and, you know, uh,
in an era where we're trying to
be conservative around energy.
You consider it that lower bandwidth and
also lower processing power means that
your users will get a faster experience.
If you could consider it, the ultimate
render that experiences, that means
less better that's being consumed.
It means less network.
Topic is less storage, all
that content and data it's.
Ultimately all the users are
getting a faster experience.
In addition to this, one of our, one
of my favorite, uh, colleagues, uh,
Mike , one of our lead, uh, front
end developers spends a lot of time
with, but this idea of cognitive.
If you have a smaller, simpler,
faster initial paint, your users
will experience a much more lighter
experience at mobile expected.
Meaning don't load all
the stuff above the fold.
Don't cram all the things that
are there, give your users the
experience to expecting, right?
If you give your users experience are
going to engage, but if you give them
a negative experience, they're going
to bounce as quickly as possible.
We don't want the.
Going one step further.
What we've found is that everyone
on your team probably cares what
the idea of performance results.
This means conversion, retention, page
experience, and so on and so forth.
So if you haven't actually considered
what your engineers are thinking
about, when you're preparing a design,
you're failing at a default setting
to be true under or now analysts
or SEO, NRLS, talk to your team.
Who's focusing on this.
You want to ultimately design
with performance rules in mind to
ultimately consider how your scores
will improve over the long run.
You want to be rerunning your
test early and often and consider
how you can ultimately improve
those experiences over there.
Meaning if you ship a feature
and you haven't rerun those
tests, you don't know if that's
actually going to help you or her.
And sometimes the feature you thought
was going to be good might actually
do the opposite or maybe not be
as big as you thought it would be.
So we find that you need to not
just measure them once, rather than
considering them over the long-term.
And also not just measure things
in terms of initial page views, per
se, but also consider conversion
metrics across the board.
Right.
So consider the entire lens.
What things will work by.
And the idea of the
long-term goals are critical.
If you ultimately consider what
is the metrics look like over the
proactive long-term metrics, you can
ultimately be doing things that will
help you feel good about these things.
So the one funnels we talked about
are focused on user research and these
user research metrics are focused on
what's considered natural, according
to the researchers at Google, and
then the positions I've thought
about there's metrics locally across.
And as the goalposts move, we want
you to be focusing on continuing
to make them obsessed even faster.
So you can optimize with performance
mindset across the board website would
be lighter, more nimble across the board.
So at a basic level, if you're given a
choice to remove the barrier in a way,
your customers wouldn't you do it again.
The hardest part is the research which
Google and other hospitalizations across
the board with the white have done.
So listen to the research and focus
on what you can do about getting.
So all things said and done.
I have a couple of items for you to
think back to your teams or maybe
onto your website and to be asking
about what we can do to improve
the overall performance website.
So the first thing you should be
doing is at least the measuring
things in terms of page speed.
And if you haven't actually done
a good job in understanding your
current state, your page speed start.
So we're view this with the tools
we talked about earlier at a
basic level of using lab tests.
Like the ones we talked
about as well as field data.
So you can use Patriot insights,
Patriot insights, reveals
a little bit of crux data.
You also pull the press reports directly
and give your users what they need.
So at a bare, bare, bare minimum,
consider meaning the industry best
practices, thresholds, or performance.
We also want to talk about
other things too, right?
So not just support vitals
are probably considered a time
interactive and time before.
Time interactive is, is important
because if you've bought lots of
third-party JavaScript loading
your page, it's probably providing
a pretty negative experience.
It's their time to first bite.
It's also critical because if you haven't
considered how the hosting experience
folds into these things with lots of PHP,
for example, a floating in the background,
it's going to end up hurting your scores.
You should be considered things like
object caching, or perhaps a better host.
If you haven't done the things, the
correct way to ultimately improve
the experience across the board.
Next up, we also want to talk
about conversion rate metrics.
If you don't get Christian metrics are
lower than Israel, we're expecting do
more to improve it and see what you
can do to match those best practices.
And if you haven't done a good enough job,
there's more, you probably can be doing.
And if by any sense, you haven't
actually met these metrics.
We want you to go back and
focus on mediation before you
move into the long-term, etc.
Finally, in the blonde combined
set goals, we want you to talk
about this idea is a basic level
of what we could do with property.
So as you ship a new feature, as
you ship a new update, whatever it
might be, you should be acting on
this idea of how we can improve these
integration experiences across the board.
Have you actually done a good enough
job to determine whether you'd
be retesting the scores across.
And over the long-term, what we've seen
is that Google and other organizations
being and so on have actually measured
the scores in different ways over time.
So at core vitals ships, the new
feature, which we know that was mentioned
a couple of times have less fence.
How will you respond to.
So at the goalpost moves
are requires new things.
You'll ultimately want to be measuring
new things along the way for these
page page experience metrics.
So this approach we've talked about is
relatively neutral, regardless of what
page experience metrics are measuring for.
But the idea of caring about your users
is the consistent part of the seasons.
So all that sudden done.
I want to say thank you for all coming
today to talk about this awesome, uh,
topic here at the Big Orange Heart,
uh, session at WordFest live 2022.
And I'm going to move into questions.
If anyone here in the audience
has any questions for us.
Leo Postovoit: Hello?
Hello.
Yogesh Londhe: Hey, thank you very
much for that amazing session.
And, uh, Yours was the first
station in Asia region and a
very, very good morning to you.
Did you have your coffee or not yet?
Leo Postovoit: I I've had a tea.
It was a delicious turmeric tea.
Yogesh Londhe: Wow.
Wow.
Well tell me, tell me
tea and a good t-shirt.
Leo Postovoit: Yes, unfortunately cleaned.
Okay.
Uh, so, uh, yep.
Hi Lux.
And, um, so we got a
few questions for you,
Lax Mariappan: uh, before, you know
Yogesh Londhe: yeah, of course there
will be ma many questions for you
from, you know, once you enter the
community tent or something, But,
uh, we'll take a few questions here.
Okay.
Uh, you discussed a lot of
important points and it was
very comprehensive the talk.
Could you discuss this
lighthouse score and that, uh,
Chrome user experience score?
Uh, what is the.
Can you compare them and what does
each one should, tell us more?
Yeah.
Leo Postovoit: So lighthouse is the
name of a tool that comes with Chrome,
Google Chrome, inside your browser.
It's a tool that you can set
up and we'll run on instance.
So lighthouse measure is a tool
based on whatever the environment is.
Lighthouse can be measured
with a specific set of frames.
So you can measure it as a mobile
score or based on network conditions.
Um, it would be very different if running
5g network conditions on a, you know, a
nine core, sorry, an eight core or 20 know
28 core computer in a major developed city
versus the same one in an emerging market.
Those different scores are critical
because we won't understand
what those things look like.
A small device with low spec hardware
is completely different experience
measuring a device on an aspect.
Um, also we find is that
it's a reality of a problem.
So as I said earlier on in the meeting
here, I'm currently based in Germany, we
actually have terrible internet and what
the city that I've been now, I love it.
But in reality, I actually have
slower internet here than I've
had in certain developing markets.
That reality of what it's like
to be and even inner cities.
So what that means is that I'm
getting, um, 2, 3, 4 minute bits
down, which is slower than you
might find in certain cities.
So even though network conditions
I'm at currently, even in the
idea of a so-called developed.
You might find that you have these
spotty connections and having things
like Peter ways or having reconnect
or other features that are there.
These ultimately provide a
faster experiences there.
So lighthouse tries to mimic the
experience of not being on a perfect
condition and crux measures the
experience of your users in the wild.
In fact, one of the things we're doing
right now, actually BP is trying to
explain the idea of your Chrome user
experience report in terms of what
your users being, seeing in the wild.
And so Google measures this idea of a 75%.
So of all your users on a bell curve,
the seventh, the percentiles, what did
they actually see as the real score?
So sometimes your lab's quarter and
lighthouse, especially on mobile,
especially on inspect hardware on mixed
network traffic, you might find that it's
actually faster than your users or even
slower than users, depending on locations.
Look like if that score is different
than your crux, use the scores,
you're not measuring for how your
users are experiencing those things.
So if you find that your scores are faster
or slower than your crock scores, go get
advice, go see what things are looking
like in that actual number, condition and
experience what it's like to be there.
So this means building ads
or loading a web video.
It might be looked experienced
these things together.
We want to see what these things
are actually like in the wild.
And in fact, I'll give them going
one step further and say that
your lab scores don't matter.
Your crux scores and your real
user measured scores matter unit.
Um, one of the things I'll call
up a real user metrics because
it's pretty much mentioned.
We use a tool at Sopp that actually
attaches your real users scores
in the wild, and it passes that as
a parameter for Google of licks.
So there's a couple of techniques on
the wild, where you can read about this.
You can pass through your
growing vitals as an accustom
parameter into Google analytics.
It makes it much easier to have
this as real user metric data as
part of each individual session.
So you want to be ultimately seeing
what you're used to seeing in the wild.
Otherwise you're not doing the right.
Well, that was a very
elaborate and very good answer.
So when you talking, I was, uh,
I know it brought back memories
of some of my own clients.
They came up with, they had this legacy,
what pre-site and, uh, some agency had
developed a custom theme and they had
a few Krause's too many on the front.
And you don't like the
front page loading time.
It was very long, but, uh, they had,
they had a loyal followers, so they had a
very good hips and they didn't know much
about Google analytics school and they
didn't know the Google console, nothing.
So I installed that Google
analytics and showed them that
they are getting not a fish from
around the world because you are.
Children's publishing
site and that was popular.
But, uh, the problem was they were
getting, um, investors and investors
had a few engineers and they were,
they wanted technical details.
They wanted, uh, the page speed
and they know the first rendered
object and all those things.
They, they were looking for that.
So that was, it brought, brought
back memories of all that,
uh, when you were talking.
Let's do you want to
take the next question?
Yes.
Uh, so you said about, uh, for
example, you read the, you make sure
you, you, where you read that popular
article from smashing magazine about
the, uh, it's a recent one, right?
I think January or something like, so they
talked about the field data and they found
out, even though they are like a static
site, like they, they found out that they
had more audience from India and India.
Poor internet connection and that give
them like, um, the goal replied a lot.
Their scores were less, uh, even though
they're the tech stack or everything
was pretty optimized and it's good.
So, um, my question.
Um, so you're smashing
magazine is a popular site.
Like a lot of visitors are going there.
Let's say if someone like a lot of people
who come to WordPress are affiliate
site owners, niche, blogs, or whatever.
So if I'm going to launch a new
site, I may not have the field data.
Right.
I may have just the page
speed insights, lab data.
So what's your take on that?
Like what advice would you do?
Like I should go wait for field
data or just lab data is fine.
How do take it from there.
Yeah.
So a lot to unpack there.
First things first, I think it's
a core responsibility of every
website to be tracking real
field data as much as possible.
So crux is fine.
The crux is 30 days late plus 30
days on top of that, it's really,
really slow to get back to you.
Things that aren't useful.
So Google analytics is.
Um, Hotjar is great.
New Relic is great.
And there's a ton of other
tools that are there as well.
You want to be ultimately measuring to see
what your users are getting in the wild.
And so as you try things and any
different hospice, we want to see
how far you can get to ultimately see
what you can do from those scores.
So you need real numbers to tell you
whether you're doing a good thing
or bad thing, or a neutral thing.
We don't, we don't necessarily know
if it's a good or bad thing, always.
Right.
Um, first things, first scores
and measurement has to be valid.
Um, as a, at a high level, we
want to, um, consider what field
data means across the board.
Um, I find that, uh, it's a
really interesting problem.
So if we talk about a website
in a traditional big Western
city, so a city say like one day.
Cisco or Los Angeles or New York
we've done that scores are faster
than the lab scores in field data.
But occasionally we find that
the opposite problem is true.
Um, we actually just started
applying at XRP a couple of days ago.
Really interesting site that has a 97 97.
That actually has slower scores on
lab because of how these things work.
So sometimes the problem is actually
an inverted problem as well.
Um, we know that that lab data isn't
actually relevant for measuring what
real users are seeing well, and if we
know that algorithms are measuring the
70 percentile as a concern, the question
is what are your users experiencing?
And are you using that as a real
metric to guide you what you want?
So I'll say it one step further.
You need to be ultimately trying
to ship code and ship features
that are going to improve what
your users are getting in the pile.
The vast majority of users, according
to Google, it's 70% say 5% of your
total Comodo users across the board.
And, uh, and the cases of, you know,
India being a really critical, uh,
concern within smashing magazine.
I would say that special magazine
probably should have a geo cluster
for is at CDN within India or a
close region and doing a better job.
What's that?
And ask them the question, can
they reduce their CSS size?
Can they offer an alternate style
sheet, anything to ultimately buy
a faster experience it's there.
And I'm willing to bet that
there's a ton more they can do.
Um, and we've actually not talked to the
special magazine team XVP, but if they
want to talk to us about how maybe we
can play faster, I can almost guarantee
you, we can make it even faster and you
can be even better for the audience.
We know this is where
you can do within that.
Um, and we can squeeze
out even more, right?
So it's, it's a worthy pursuit
and we know that helps with
conversion across the board.
Yogesh Londhe: Hey.
Great.
Thank you very much.
Yeah.
Great.
Okay.
So next question.
Um, you discussed this in your talk,
so let's discuss the delightful
experiences versus conversion from this
different aspects, from the aspect of
the users and users who are visiting
your website, the website owner
developer, and sometimes the investors.
Leo Postovoit: Yeah.
So, um, in terms of delightful
experiences, I would say that we want
these things to feel smooth and natural.
So one critical part of how
we approach the problem.
The next to the BP is that we identify
each persona and then we name them.
We say, one is Bob, what is Jim
was Joe, or might be, we want
to navigate through the experts.
So a user might have a different
experience if they're on their mobile
device, again, on a train, on a bus,
navigating through a place maybe on
terrible hotel wifi, um, you never know
what your experience is going to be
compared to what someone else's view.
Um, and sometimes it's
actually really funny, right?
So maybe.
Especially in this ecosystem
here, we might have heard about
the client stakeholder who was on
internet Explorer, 11 on a computer.
That's like many years out of
date, but they happen to be, you
know, they hold the purse strings.
They happen to be the most
important person at the company.
And maybe they're really senior.
And you know, it has nothing
to do with developing markets.
Shop is good.
That's the stakeholder.
You have to ultimately shape your answer.
What's there.
Delightful experience is a
true question of all of your
users and each of your users.
Sometimes it's that strange one-off
example of a a hundred percent or like
an investor other times, it's going to
be the question of you're both users.
What I find is critical is your users
need to be the things you measure by that.
So, So consider that entire bell curve
that you've got and make that experience
be as reliable and elegant as possible.
And not just some random anecdote.
In fact, I would say the investor that's
on nine 11, as much as he might care
about the considerations that are there.
I would say Google's idea of centile,
all the things that are there matter even
more, that's the cohort you want to care
about and to do more than an audience.
Yogesh Londhe: Great.
Uh, okay Lex, you got a.
You have a question for the Leo ? I, I,
Lax Mariappan: yeah, so, uh, uh, it
just, no matter how, so just a simple
question though, like you answered
already, like let's summarize, we have
another two minutes left or so it's like,
uh, how can I make my website faster?
It's come to everyone's mind.
So your question, your answer.
Be.
Leo Postovoit: Yeah, TLDR you
somehow managed totune in for only
section high Leo from XWP, run your
site through a page speed insights
or similar tool, pay attention to
recommendations, probably install
plugin that makes your website faster.
That's probably not going to be enough.
You'd probably want to remove stuff,
actually pay attention to what your
releases are doing and do even more.
Your real users are probably going
to be different than we expected, and
you probably can do even more than.
So this is going to be, you know,
optimizing video, forensic images,
throwing fonts, and asking the questions
around letter blocking experiences.
We want you to lighten everything, right?
So, um, I I'll mention a quote from the
great team out of the UK many, many years
ago in the 1960s, it seems from Lotus.
I said, simplify, and then add lightness.
That's how you win races.
Right?
So consider that for your website.
Is there a faster way for you to do it?
Well, the answer is probably.
Lax Mariappan: Yep.
Yes.
So I can just take it as a performance
is a process, not just plug it, right?
Leo Postovoit: Yeah.
It's a hundred percent.
Yes.
Yogesh Londhe: Yeah.
A hundred percent.
So, uh, yeah, I think let's
take one more question.
I'll I'll combine few more, few things.
So, you know, we are
talking about performance.
So once we have a website, a WordPress
site, so should I have AMP or PWA?
The AMP or PWA.
And then can you go ahead and
tell us, uh, how does CDN affect
any of those two are without the.
Leo Postovoit: Man.
I don't have enough time to answer the
question, but I would say, I would say
about, uh, after they experience update
in, uh, last year, amp is still a useful
thing, but it's shifting in a different
way, but for customer page has been,
so it's there, first of all, I'm up.
So I focused on in sambal technologies
and offline a lot you can do within PWAs.
Um, I think he was just, don't be useful.
I would also say the CDNs are
great, but you have to measure
where your real users are.
And if that's, again is
ultimately going to help.
Um, what we find, for example, um, we work
a lot with customers that are in Asia,
for example, uh, things like Singapore
or China or India, there's sometimes
restrictions within content networks.
Um, there's also a huge discussion
happening today within Russia and Ukraine,
which I'm not going to get political,
but even sometimes we talk about networks
and accessibility is a huge concern.
Sometimes actually accessing your
customers might be challenging
because of now Netflix work.
So we want to ultimately be
able to access your users.
Are the world.
And so do you, the network might be
actually blocked for a variety of reasons.
You wanna make sure that your
CDNs can actually get around
these things to connect with
the customers for your audits.
So, um, China's is probably the
biggest concern because sometimes
getting around the so-called great
firewall of China makes it hard to
get this audience of there, that
your audience is actually there.
You wanna make sure that you're either
noted from an ad standpoint or the
actual cluster for your website.
That's there, that's hosted on a
utilized, but WordPress house can
actually access that client directly.
So.
Uh, long story short, probably his AMP
probably use PWA, probably use a CDN,
make sure it matches up for users.
Yogesh Londhe: Right.
Thank you very much, Leo.
It was amazing session and
really engaging a Q and A.
And uh, how do people reach you
if they are looking for resources,
other things, how do they reach you?
Are you on.
Leo Postovoit: Yeah.
Yeah.
So XWP has a great blog
https://xwp.co/blog, tons
of resources that are there.
I, Leo I'm found on Twitter
at, at literally @PostPhotos.
Um, and I'm also available at leo@xwp.co.
So super easy to find on the web.
I'm happy to answer any questions people
have and again, check out WordFest.
Uh, I'll be hanging around
for a little bit, uh, here
this morning and good to see.
Well, and we'll talk.
Yogesh Londhe: Okay, thank you
very much again, have a great day.
Yep.
So, okay.
That was a fantastic session.
And our thanks to our sponsors, Bluehost,
Cloudways, GoDaddy Pro, Nexcess, Yoast.
And Weglot, please be sure to
visit the tents and chat with them.
You might even win some prizes.
Okay.
Lax Mariappan: Yeah, we have Photo Booth.
Don't forget to get your photos snapped
in the photo booth and it's sponsored
by Multicollab and Dreamhost and
feed it with a hashtag wordFest Live.
And also thanks to our media
partners and micro sponsors.
Yogesh Londhe: Okay.
Um, in the, in the community tent in the
next hour, Cloudways have their hourly
giveaway with a special guest activity and
you all make our Big Orange Heart full.
Lax Mariappan: Yeah.
We'd love your support.
Consider donation where donate button or.
On the screen or go to our website,
https://bigorangeheart.org and
then you can make a donation.
Yogesh Londhe: So now we go for 10
minutes per week and, uh, we come
back in, let's see, eight minutes.
Okay.
It's not a 10 minute break.
Seven to eight minutes.
They come for the next session.