Yoast: Do you know, the Yoast SEO,
plugin, they're red, orange, and
green feedback bullets that help
you optimize your posts for the web.
It runs on millions of websites.
We tried to make SEO understandable
and accessible to everyone.
Bluehost: Who says building
an online store has to be hard
with Bluehost website builder.
It's more than just easy.
It's tell us your thing in smart AI.
We'll take it from there.
Easy it's WooCommerce friendly.
So you can add one of these
or swap this for that.
It's set up shop in minutes
with unlimited products.
Easy.
Whether you sell boots, books
or bowls, it's create an online
store with Bluehost, easy build
beyond boundaries with Bluehost.
Nexcess: Oh, great my
website crashed again.
I give up, don't give up on your
dreams, Jordan, who are you?
It's me.
You from the future.
Your professional website
is not out of reach.
You just need the Nexcess.
With Nexcess managed hosting, you
get lightning Paslode times built
and performance monitoring and
updates, and always awesome support.
24 7 365.
For all your props.
Whoa.
Yeah.
Weglot: Discover Weglot the simple
translation solution for your website.
All you have to do is add
Weglot to your website, select
the languages that you need.
And that's it.
Your website is now available
in multiple languages.
Yogesh Londhe: Hey, Lex.
Lax Mariappan: Hello.
Welcome again.
Yogesh Londhe: Welcome again to Asia
stage one and we are in session 1 0 7.
Joining us live now is Dan Maby
himself, not maybe himself.
He is.
But yeah, maybe it's the name.
Okay.
So Dan is our lead WordFest organizer
and director of Big Orange Heart.
This WordFest, we are taking some
time to get to know our organizers and
why they volunteer for this huge job.
Why do they give so much time?
What they do when they are not,
uh, WordFest'ing, and to learn
a little bit more about the
person, the human who is Dan Maby.
Okay.
And about people were
contributing to Big Orange Heart.
Hey Dan.
Dan Maby: Hello.
Hello.
Yogesh Londhe: This is the session
where I've been looking for.
And I'm lucky enough to be here in person.
So Dan, maybe himself.
So he is himself, but Dan Maby
Dan, we've got few questions
for you, but not enough time.
Sure.
Thank you very much.
Thank you very much for doing this
WordFest and thank you very much for.
Dan Maby: Yeah, you're very, very welcome.
And, uh, and did just wanna say thank
you both  for giving your time and
equally across, across this events.
There are obviously, we've got
some of these 108 volunteer roles
that are being filled just during
that 28 to 24 hour period to us.
We're delivering this event.
So a huge thank you to
everybody that's involved, uh,
across, uh, across WordPress.
Does that mean that
Yogesh Londhe: they say that, uh,
find the cause and means we'll follow
a good cause people do come to it.
Dan Maby: Absolutely.
Uh, let's let's start
with the questions then.
Um, so much to learn about you.
What do you, what, what
is Dan's role in WordFest?
What does Dan do and WordFest?
Um, I, if I'm honest, come up with lots of
silly ideas and then try and find people
that will bring those ideas to reality.
So, um, my, so my official role across
WordPress Fest live is a lead organizer.
Uh, so essentially, uh, ensuring that
we've got the teams in the right places,
individuals, you know, making sure that
individuals understand what they are.
That tasks they're undertaking and
basically supporting the team leads.
So we have a number of
teams across word Fest.
We have our speakers teams, our
marketing teams, our DevOps, uh,
there's AV teams, our sponsors teams.
There's, there's quite a number of them.
And basically, um, the, the idea of, uh,
for me, is to ensure that each team leads.
Is supported.
And I want to make sure that
every role is supported in a
way that's, uh, that is needed.
Making sure that the mission of Big Orange
Heart is fulfilled all the way through,
um, the delivery of WordFest Live.
Obviously with our mission being
to support and promote positive
wellbeing and mental health
within remote working communities.
Uh, and the idea of delivering an event
of this scale across a 24 hour period.
With any of such a huge
global audience there is.
Yeah.
There's the potential for, uh, for,
for, um, stressful situations, stressful
scenarios to start to creep in.
We, of course, that's, that's the last
thing that we want to be creating as
a, you know, as a, as an organization
that's focused on wellbeing.
Um, we need to make sure that this,
you know, this, this, uh, delivery
of this event is taken undertaken
in such a way that it really doesn't
have a negative impact on the
community that are delivering it.
Yogesh Londhe: Thank you very much.
Uh, uh, you know, WordFest always makes
me happy and it, you know, it always has
a very positive impact on the community,
so, you know.
Okay.
So Lax next question?
Uh, yeah.
Lax Mariappan: So next question.
Why do you think events
like WordFest is important?
Dan Maby: So that is a great question.
And I think we're in this, um, we're
certainly in a transitional period,
I would say, uh, we've obviously had
an incredibly challenging couple of
years to say the very least there's
been an awful lot of, um, change that
we've had to adapt to an awful lot of
things that we've had to, um, overcome.
Uh, both, you know, for, for, for many,
many reasons, but, um, obviously not
least the fact that as a community,
we've not been able to truly be together.
And the, if we specifically talk about
the WordPress community for a minute,
I think the WordPress community.
Very very kind of bound around the people.
And it's a very special community
is a community that I've
absolutely fell in love with.
I've spent a long time within, and really
we wanted to deliver something that
could enable people to come together
and create some semblance of that
community spirit whilst coming together.
Trying to, you know, there's been lots of
attempts around delivering virtual events
and there, there are a lot of challenges
in relation to it, but really we want
to be creating a scenario where it feels
very community driven and it's about the
community that's delivering the event.
And it's about that, that same feel that
I think we can, we do get in our in-person
or physical events, which we have
obviously been lacking for for some time.
Um, so it's about bringing the
community together, creating an
environment where the community
truly feels part of the event.
Uh, but also making sure that we are
creating an environment where our
community members can come together
and we're, you know, we're reducing
that ability, you know, that, um,
impact that social isolation can have.
Uh, if we're in an environment
where we can't physically come in,
Yogesh Londhe: Thank you
very much for doing this.
And, uh, I think, uh, you know, if,
uh, you should put this question to.
Let them come up with the short clip.
I'm sure if you allow me Topher,
Michelle, to talk about this,
we could talk for a few days.
Why this, why, WordFest?
Why, WordFest is important?
Yep.
Dan Maby: Yeah.
Okay.
So Yogesh if you'll allow me, why, why
do you, what is for you interesting?
It's interesting to hear what is,
what is the importance of WordFest?
Yogesh Londhe: Yeah.
So some of the, the first thing will
overlap with what to say, you know,
WordFest brings people together.
It makes people, you know, the, the
social contact, the feeling of community
coming together, learning from each other.
And it's not only learning.
It's about, uh, mental health, the
very important issue, especially in
this stressful time in last two years.
And we don't know what's going
to in this uncertain time.
Uh, you know, coming together
and meeting people, you know, uh,
contacting with people you still
don't know and making new connections.
And on top of that, learning new
things about, uh, what, WordPress
and the best part is it's it's,
uh, goes around the world.
So it's truly globally event.
It brings the world together.
It's uh, you can choose what
session you want to join.
What, where do you want to go?
And so it really brings the world, the
whole global purpose community together.
Yep.
Very important.
Thank you very much for doing this.
Dan Maby: You're very welcome and safe.
It's a community, a
community driven thing.
So, um, you know, across the
board that, uh, I just, I just
feel it's, it's wonderful to see.
So, um, if you are a participantin
WordFest Live right now.
Um, there are, you know, there's a,
there's a great opportunity around
the, the, you know, the venue fever
to connect with people, head over to
the community tent, spend time, spend
time with the, uh, with the community,
jump on a table, jump in there with
the sponsors, uh, you know, just simply
connect with, with the community again.
But it's not just about that.
Um, something that I really,
really enjoy seeing is the way.
Across, for example, across our
slack community, the way everybody
supports one another in their roles.
And it's just wonderful to see
how people can just really step
up and, you know, w we're getting
volunteers answering questions for
volunteers, and it's just a really.
Special kind of, um, uh, a
community bond, I guess, uh,
that we, that we see across this.
And it's lovely.
Usually we see the screenshot people
taking photos of, you know, their
environment and how they're enjoying
WordFest Live and just creating those
little moments and, um, you know,
jumping over to the, the photo booth,
getting it, getting a little photo
snaps and obviously sharing that across
the social, all these little things.
I think they just add up to what often
becomes quite a, quite a special thing.
Yogesh Londhe: Sure, sure.
Lax Mariappan: To add to your question.
It's like, uh, I'd like to share
my experience with WordFest so far.
So last year is my first time to
attend the WordFest and that time
I had my first anxiety attack just
a few days ago and I was there.
I was recording my Udemy
courses with my girlfriend.
Got stuck in a quadrant.
Like she had to stay away.
And I was actually, I'm the
only person in that apartment.
So it's like mentally, I couldn't
go out as well because of, you know,
people consider that I'm exposed
to the virus, something like that.
So it's like, it was literally,
it was too anxious in nervous
or um, I'm a talkative person.
I never been alone or
I'm not used to that one.
And luckily I was like,
oh, WordFest I seen that.
Like, I was like, okay.
I just thought like, it's another
WordPress event like WordPress has a
lot of communities, a lot of things.
And then.
And I joined it.
I mean, it was just joined as a
participant and I visited, um,
all the attended all the sessions.
And then I visited the tents in, uh, I
chat with, uh, one of the sponsors like
Elementor group and other groups as well.
I saw Yoast community as well.
They have had this, like you
said, the sponsorships and.
Giveaways and games.
And also what not, like you can
ask any question about Yoast.
You can ask any question about
Elementor and things like that.
And, and also you get to meet other
people as well in the community chat.
So it's like, I spent
almost the whole day.
It was not an hour long shifts,
so that's my experience.
And that's how I was like, oh, okay.
So it helps that that's, that's
kind of the day I discovered like
being with people, like being with
like-minded people really helps.
And also I was also able to
answer some of the questions
of other participants as well.
So that helped me like, okay.
I also like to overcome my
imposter syndrome and other stuff.
Dan Maby: Sure.
Yeah.
Lax Thank you though.
I mean, that is that that's wonderful
to hear because essentially that's
what we're looking to achieve here.
The ability to, for people to
come together, uh, come together
as a community, uh, connect
with one another and you know,
there, I've got some, um, really.
Uh, I would say I'm really blessed to be
able to say that off the back of working
with a number of the, um, the, the
core team members, uh, across waitress
life, I've got friends for life here.
Um, and you know, it really is about,
you know, building up, how do we,
um, you know, make sure that we are
supported, uh, you know, between, you
know, with one another, um, that is
ultimately what Big Orange Heart is.
You know, we, we're trying to ensure
that we are, uh, enabling positive.
Uh, positive focus around wellbeing
and mental health for our community,
our remote working community.
So these opportunities to deliver these
events where we can come together,
that really a key focus for us.
Uh, something I did want to just
mention that, um, you know, Pushing
forward and we will be building
out, uh, through throughout 2022.
Uh, thanks to our global sponsors.
And I just want to quickly say a thank
you to Bluehost, Cloudways, GoDaddy
Pro, Nexcess, Weglot and Yoast for
coming on board as global sponsors.
They are actually enabling us to
build out our LifeGroup program.
So this is an exciting program
that we're going to be bringing.
Uh, we're going to be expanding upon.
We've already been delivering
it within Big Orange Heart.
It's something that's been
tested for some time now.
And we're looking forward to bringing
that into the community, which again
is an opportunity for community
members really to come together
and, uh, and to support one another.
So we simply couldn't do it without
the, the, you know, the financial
support that these companies provide.
Uh, but equally we are incredibly
grateful for every single penny that
is donated, uh, by the general public.
Uh, and again, if you're, if you're,
uh, here on WordFest Live and
you'll, you're gaining any benefit,
you're taking something away.
If you have the ability to, uh,
we would really appreciate it.
If you could hit the donate
now button in the menu.
Um, but I also know that I can
keep talking for a very long
time and we've got some far more
important sessions coming up.
Yogesh Londhe: So yeah, let's, let's,
let's take this last two minutes
to talk about, uh, Dan, the human.
Okay.
So what's your full-time job.
We'll make it quick.
Rapid questions.
Dan Maby: Full time.
Job is currently focused
on Big Orange Heart.
Yogesh Londhe: Okay.
That's your full-time job.
Okay.
Thank you very much.
Tell us about your family on,
uh, if you have a non-human
family four legged family.
Dan Maby: I do.
And I'm surprised you actually can't hear
him snoring away down in the corner here.
I've got a three year old Beagle
asleep in the corner here.
Yogesh Londhe: Lovely,
lovely, lovely, lovely.
And so tell us about your families.
Dan Maby: Yes.
Yeah, my, my I've got a, an ever, um, ever
giving wife that said that supports me,
supports me tremendously through this.
And the fact that we're sitting here.
Yeah, absolutely.
For me, I mean, we're sitting here
at 5:00 AM in the morning for me.
She, so she's sleeping in the, in
the room next door and, you know,
uh, I'm just, I wouldn't be able to
do what I do if it wasn't for the
support network that I had around me.
Yogesh Londhe: Thank you.
Also, I connect with anybody
who has a four legged family.
I live with a lot of pets.
Yes.
I got like 20 dogs and 30 odd cats
and so many other wild animals yet.
Okay.
So.
Uh, what would, other than
WordFest, what other ways do you
contribute to what this community?
Dan Maby: Uh, so we've, I've been
running events for a very long time.
Uh, so obviously pre a near we're
going back more than a decade
now in terms of delivery of,
uh, in-person physical events.
Um, and.
I'm very community focused for me.
It's about the people.
Um, you know, we, we often hear it.
You came for the tech and
stayed for the people.
Uh, it's a bit of, a bit of a cliche,
but it absolutely is true for myself.
Um, you know, the, the moment I
stepped into a meetup, I was hooked.
I then went from the meetup
into a, um, a WordCamp.
And from there on it was a, that was it.
Yogesh Londhe: Yeah.
And so, uh, Dan, thank you very much
for doing this and we would love
to talk with you for much longer.
We already have gone beyond time, so, yep.
I really connect with you because I, I
am also, you're only for community now.
I did come for tech and
state for community.
Thank you very much.
Dan Maby: Thank you.
Uh, I appreciate your time.
And as I mentioned before, thank you
very much for, for giving your time
into, into this, both of you and
everybody else behind the scenes.
Lax Mariappan: Yeah.
Thank you for giving us this
platform and the opportunity so
that we all can contribute to.
Yogesh Londhe: Okay.
Allowing us to come here to this platform.
Okay.
Great.
So, um, that was, uh, Dan Maby
himself the human and, uh, it
was amazing to talk with him.
So now we go on to session 1 0 8.
Okay.
So this is, uh, our sponsor interview
with, uh, Thomas Fanchin of Weglot.
Emily Hukler met with Thomas earlier to
see what makes Weglot Vishal and why this.
Committed to the WordPress
community and Big Orange Heart.
Okay.
So this is, um, the
recorded interview by Emily.
With Thomas.
We will have, uh, the adverts
from our amazing sponsors and
the video of the interview.
Okay.
Thank you.