Yoast: Do you know, the Yoast SEO,
plugin, they're red, orange, and
green feedback bullets that help
you optimize your posts for the web.
It runs on millions of websites.
We tried to make SEO understandable
and accessible to everyone.
Nexcess: Oh great.
My website crashed.
I give up.
Don't give up on your dreams.
Jordan, who are you?
It's me.
You from the future.
Your professional website
is not at a reach.
You just need Nexcess.
With Nexcess managed hosting, you
get lightening pass load times
built-in performance monitoring and
updates, and always awesome support.
24 7 365 for all your projects.
Whoa.
Yeah.
Weglot: Discover Weglot the simple
translation solution for your website.
All you have to do is add Weglot to
your website, select the languages
that you need, and that's it.
Your website is now available
in multiple languages.
Bluehost: Who says building
an online store has to be
hard with Bluehost website.
It's more than just easy.
It's tell us your thing and smart AI.
We'll take it from there.
Easy it's WooCommerce friendly.
So you can add oneof these
or swap this for that easy.
It's set up shop in minutes
with unlimited products.
Easy.
Whether you sell boots, books
or bowls, it's create an online
store with Bluehost, easy build
beyond boundaries with Bluehost.
Yogesh Londhe: So this is, uh,
our sponsor interview with,
uh, Thomas Fanchin of weak lot.
Emily Hunkler met with Thomas earlier
to see what makes me special and why
they are committed to the WordPress
community and Big Orange Heart.
Emily Hunkler: Hello.
We are here for a community
interview with one of, uh, Big
Orange Heart's sponsors Weglot.
So we're very excited today to have
Thomas Fanchin  here with us as
the partnership manager for, Weglot
thank you, Thomas, for joining us.
It's great to see you.
Thomas Fenchin: Just so much.
Emily Hunkler: Wonderful.
Yeah, let's jump right into it.
So, um, can you talk a little
bit about Weglot and how
community is important to them?
What community means to you all.
Thomas Fenchin: Sure.
I mean, originally, uh, Weglot was
lunch during WordCamp Paris in 2016, 16.
Sorry.
So, um, I mean, since then we have
supported a lot of WordCamps, meetups,
but I've met a lot of friends who,
uh, uh, for community and also like a
lot of partners and great connection.
And they also help us with
giving us great feedback.
Um, which help  to be, to try, I
mean, at least to build a, one of
the best multilingual plugin that
it's available to be on WordPress.
And I mean, it's kind of a, a, it's
really part of our DNA and it's kind
of an extension of, Weglot really.
Emily Hunkler: Yeah, absolutely.
That I think that makes sense.
And it is so important to remind
people, um, that community is
about connecting for one part and
also about connections, right?
Like creating those relationships and
nurturing them and exposing yourself
to new ones and helping them not only
grow yourself, but grow your business,
that open doors for you and all of that.
It's, it's huge.
Yeah, absolutely.
Um, what are some ways that
Weglot that you helped nurture a
sense of community internatlly?
Thomas Fenchin: So that's a, uh, a
really interesting question actually.
Uh, I, I think within the team, we
do a lot of team meetings and we have
like project feedback, for example,
where everyone can join us and,
uh, give us feedbacks about how we
would like a project, whoever you
also have, like learning session,
where, uh, you can learn about, for
example, partnership in community.
You can learn about WordPress
integration and you can learn
about empathy, for example.
So I believe, uh, uh, this is how we,
we actually kind of like build this
community, uh, uh, uh, not cheating, but
community aware maybe, uh, in the team.
Emily Hunkler: Yeah, absolutely.
And I think that's, it's so great to hear.
So.
Uh, kind of empowering your team members
to get involved, to help edge further
education, that sort of thing about,
about WordPress in general, about
what's out there and keeping everyone
aware and involved and supported
and feedback, like you mentioned,
is such a big part of that as well.
And knowing how to receive
feedback, how to implement feedback,
um, how do you give feedback?
All of those sorts of things
all go into kind of building a
productive community, for sure.
So that's awesome.
Um, What are some ways you've touched on
this a little bit already, but what are
some other, um, some of those ways that,
that Weglot contributes to the WordPress
community and the remote community.
Are you guys a remote team?
Thomas Fenchin: I mean, part of the
team is working remotely like myself.
I just moved to one.
So we are based in Paris and, but I
mean, we, we, we, we do support, like
I said, events, meetups, WordCamps,
and I feel like just last week we
announced, that we are now WordPress
Global community sponsor, which
means that we are now supporting all
the, uh, WordCamps to meetups all
around the world, which is awesome.
And, uh, this is, uh, uh, one
of the ways that we are actually
supporting the community.
There's also the, we do support a
lot of resources, podcasts, blogs
to help, uh, the community and
funds from the community grow.
And, uh, another way is also, uh, to
create, uh, sort of educational content
webinars guides about multilingual,
and about our area of expertise.
Really.
Emily Hunkler: I love that.
That's fantastic.
I, I saw that you all were
global sponsors, with WordPress
as well, so that's fantastic.
Um, that's, that's all so great and it is
so important to when you have that remote
team and recognize the importance of, of,
of supporting those people, even though
you're not there and you, you, yourself
being one of those remote team members.
Right.
So, so, you know, firsthand for sure.
Um, wonderful.
How, what are some ways
on that note, especially.
Um, Weglot helps to support their, their
teams, um, physical and mental wellbeing.
Thomas Fenchin: I mean, uh,
first, uh, like I said, there's
like a lot of team activities.
So, for example, we do like online,
uh, chocoholic testing, online
cheese testing, and we do a lot of
fun activities like escape game.
In one time we did an escape game
online it was like, uh, awesome.
And there's also like in-person
meeting where, uh, for example,
every two weeks we meet at a bar
and, uh, we have like a time off.
Uh, there's also like what we call,
uh, sometimes we go and we're going to
go skiing together for, for example,
in the next, like the next few weeks.
Uh, the last time we went and we
went on a, on a, on a mountain
bike, a trail, it was awesome too.
So, I mean, there's like, like
I said, online activities, uh,
physical in-person activities, uh,
for remote workers like myself.
Uh, we, we, we do have,
uh, an mean for everyone.
We really, from the team, because everyone
is now working remotely, you have like all
your equipments for your home office, but
it's like a sponsored basically by Weglot,
so, which mean that you have your screens,
your chair, your camera and everything,
like for your home office, uh, set up, uh,
kind of sponsored by Weglot, which means
that, uh, you, you, you can like work at
a, at the, at a nice place at home too.
Emily Hunkler: That's amazing.
That's great.
We're going to have to share if
you guys are hiring at the end of
this community, this interview.
Cause I think you just sold.
Everybody's going to
want to work at Weglot.
Um, that's amazing though.
That's fantastic because it also
sounds like you all recognize.
That wellbeing, mental health and
physical health look different
for different people, right?
Whether that is getting together
personally, and whether it's, uh, you
know, going mountain biking or skiing
or meeting at a bar, or whether it's
something that people, other types of
people are more comfortable with, like
an online meetup and getting together
that way and making sure you're set
up to be comfortable in your office
at home and that sort of thing.
So that's, that's amazing.
That sounds like you guys are
doing really cool stuff for your
team, and it's awesome to hear.
Um, way to go on that.
Uh, let's see.
Is there any to kind of wrap up this
interview is, do you, is there any kind
of personal anecdote that you could
share about your wellness and how it
relates to your experience that Weglot?
Thomas Fenchin: Sure.
Sure.
So, uh, basically like I come from
Mauritius, which is like really
far away from Paris and France.
Uh, it's like a 12 hour flight and all
my family are where my parents are.
So, uh, every time, but, uh, I come
at the office, uh, I really feel like,
um, and I'm happy to be at the office
to see my colleagues, my colleagues,
and it's such a, uh, A great feeling
to, to, to be able to just like, come
at the office and feel like home every
time, but your value, your happy.
So that's just like my anecdote and how
I, uh, I, uh, I really, uh, feel about
Weglot and what we do and the team.
Yep.
Emily Hunkler: That's wonderful.
That's so great to hear, and
you can see it in your face.
Like when you talk about, you've got
a smile about it and, and you, and
you can tell that you, you enjoy it.
So it's really wonderful to
hear Thomas, thank you so much.
Um, is there anywhere that, um, folks
should go if they want to find out
more about Weglot, or if you guys are
hiring or, you know, what you guys
are doing and all that sort of stuff.
Thomas Fenchin: We are actually
hiring a, an event manager.
Uh, uh, the job is based in Paris.
So if you want to actually, uh,
uh,  join the team, there is that job
position that is available in Paris
and yep, if you want to find out more
about, Weglot, you can just go on our
website https://weglot.Com and, uh, you
can also reach out to me, uh, if you
want on LinkedIn or on social media.
Emily Hunkler: Wonderful.
Thank you so much, Thomas.
I appreciate your time and recording this
interview for the community and thank you.
And Weglot so much for being such
wonderful sponsors, a Big Orange Heart.
We couldn't do it without you.
So have a wonderful day and
we'll, we'll see you around.
Thank you.
Yogesh Londhe: Thank you very much,
Emily and Thomas, we could actually feel
Thomas's, uh, passion and enthusiasm.
About the community about Weglot
about contributions, everything.
So our thanks to our sponsors,
Bluehost, Cloudways, GoDaddy Pro,
Nexcess, Yoast, and Weglot, please be
sure to visit their tent and chat with
them you might even win some prizes.
Lax Mariappan: And don't
forget to the photo booth.
Like don't forget to get your
photo snapped in the photo booth.
Sponsored by Multicollab lab in Dreamhost
and tweeted out and spread the word
with the hashtag WordFest Live thank
you to your, our media partners and
our micro sponsors in the community
tent in the next hour Cloudways
have their are hourly give away.
So don't it.