Nexcess: Oh, great.
My website crashed again.
I give up, don't give up on your
dreams, Jordan, who are you?
It's me.
You from the future.
Your professional website
is not out of reach.
You just need Nexcess.
With Nexcess managed hosting, you
get lightening pass load times
built-in performance monitoring and
updates, and always awesome support.
24 7 365.
For all your plans.
Whoa.
Yeah.
Weglot: Discover Weglot the simple
translation solution for your website.
All you have to do is add Weglot to
your website, select the languages
that you need, and that's it.
Your website is now available
in multiple languages.
Yoast: Do you know, the Yoast SEO,
plugin, they're red, orange, and
green feedback bullets that help
you optimize your posts for the web.
It runs on millions of websites.
We try to make SEO understandable
and accessible to everyone.
Bluehost: Who says building
an online store has to be hard
with Bluehost website builder.
It's more than just easy.
It's tell us your thing in smart AI.
We'll take it from there.
Easy it's WooCommerce friendly.
So you can add one of these
or swap this for that easy.
It's set up shop in minutes
with unlimited products.
Easy.
Whether you sell boots, books
or bowls, it's create an online
store with Bluehost, easy build
beyond boundaries with Bluehost.
Lax Mariappan: Yeah, our next speaker
is Sumant Lohar, and he will be
presenting about getting started
with podcasting for developers.
So I love this topic.
We want to get started with
podcasting and I'm a developer myself.
Sumant has a dedicated tech blog.
Based in Ahmedabad  also specializes
in crafting content for social
media strategies and, uh, for
various brands, as well as startups.
His core strength lies in
Instagram marketing video reaching.
Apart from that podcasting
is this new skillset.
WordPres is a true inspiration for
him that encouraged him to help
businesses through creative content.
That's also been a volunteer.
Organizer at meaning at WordCamps.
Yeah.
Many WordCamps and other tech
conferences and has been active
WordPress, community members since 2017.
So, but
Sumant Lohar: Namaste a warm
welcome to all of you to this
amazing session for today.
Today, we are going to talk about getting
started with podcasting for developers.
And I'm Sumant your company, and
we'll take you through the entire
process of starting your own
podcast, even if you are a developer.
So let's get started.
I spent, you know, least time
on introduction because more
than introduction, the main area
is to learn about podcasting.
So basically I'm a tech blogger or content
and social media strategist, video content
creator, which had a speaker at various.
Podcaster at the idea.
Well, content, so I so I Sumant Lohar
now welcome to this amazing session.
So here are some of the amazing, you
know, agent for today, and we are
going to see one by one, all of them
and explore all the opportunities.
What is the first thought that comes to
mind while we are starting with podcast.
So I got this first amazing and
inspiring thought from Pat Flynn,
who is a well-known podcaster.
He sees that the riches
are in the niches friends.
You all are almost, I assume that in this.
Working as a developer or maybe a
designer and a CSS, a specialist,
a blogger, or a marketer.
So if you see that, the way you
focus on one niche, you get, you
know, grow, growing and growing.
So the way you are, you know,
making it a statement, it says
the riches are in the niche.
So if you just stick to one or two niche,
you can be rich the way you want it.
Okay, now let's get into the
basics of the podcasting first.
Let's say a first history.
You know that from our forefathers,
we have been listening that they
used to, uh, listen to all the
audio part through gramophone.
And then we came with her antique
radio then came tape recorder.
Sony Walkman, which we used to put
in our ear and take it everywhere,
video audio castte, and then can be
apple iPod MP3 players, where you
can store 300 more than 300 songs.
Right.
But all of this was replaced by a
smartphone where you can do multiple
things, audio, video, social media,
marketing, you know, messaging everything.
So what is the definition of.
Podcast is an audio format available on
different distribution platforms, which
is downloadable that makes it convenient
for the people to listen to them while
traveling for other activity hours, daily
workouts, or while relaxing at home.
This can be published on website.
YouTube social media platforms.
So it's something that you
can download them from the
various distribution platforms.
These are not the social media platforms.
These are the platforms like
Spotify, Google podcasts, and those
where they can download them and
listen at your own convenience.
So.
What is the importance of podcasting?
It is usually in a series of podcasts.
So you, how, like, for example, if we
are talking about, let's say Gutenberg
editor, so it takes into different
series, like one to 10 and then 10 to 20.
Okay.
Again, you can have the variations
and do that different podcast.
Now this few points are very
much, uh, of importance, right?
It is a niche based.
So if you have forecasting
generalized away, maybe you get
an audience at a lesser pace.
But if we are focusing on, let's
say you are a tech, but that person.
Focus on tech tech things.
If you are, you know, related to fashion
industry folk focus on fashion industry.
So that's how you slowly,
slowly grow in this area.
It gives you immersive experience while
listening, you know, you, while you are
listening to each podcast, you have the
combination of audio, uh, you know, the
sound effects the voice off a broadcaster.
So that gives a very soothing
effect, that relaxing effect,
where you can listen to them any.
It's a conversational, it's not a, you
know, very serious matter or something
which, uh, makes you, uh, that you
are to concentrate on that time.
It's a conversational, it's a
casual form of delivering content.
Now next, no barriers for listening.
You can listen to them while
walking, running, traveling,
eating, or even relaxing, right.
Everyone enjoying with friends
as well, access them for free.
What does this mean?
All of the podcast, genders
today are available for free.
Of course you can listen to them,
but there are some premium channels
as well, where you have to subscribe
on a monthly basis or yearly
basis, and you can listen to them.
That's what we call about
as a membership right now.
What is the punchline of podcast?
It's the new normal for
travelers and commuters.
If you are traveling to any part of
the world, so you can listen to what.
If you are a commuter commuter
means from home to your workplace or
somewhere where you're going for a
job or you're going for your business
or something, that's how you travel.
And you listen to podcasts, you
know, utilizing that precious.
Next, this is very important.
You can take the screenshot of
this because, uh, you know, when
we talk about podcast, so you need
to be very clear with what type
of podcast you want to start with.
So we have solo, solo, or monologue,
that means you alone right now, while
I'm talking to you, that's a solo thing.
So that means you can range from 15 to 20
minutes each episode, and you can publish
three to four episodes that depends on
your expertise, your time, convenience,
and the way you want to deliver it.
Second is host and co-host, you may
be seeing in this particular word,
WordPress, because that makes you very.
Uh, you know, you can relate with that.
You see that there is a
host and there's a cohost.
So when their conversation and they're
introducing to a new guest, so that's
how it's a host and co-host part.
And that, uh, you know, ranges from
20 to 25 minutes, you can publish
weekly two to three episodes, right?
Interview you, you invite.
Within your industry, like, let's
say you are a developer WordPress
developer, and you invite someone else,
uh, you know, WordPress developer from
another company and you gain to, uh,
ask them different questions around
their methodology, what challenges they
face and what are the tools they use.
So that's how you make it more
impactful and influential.
So that ranges from 35 to 45.
And at least you can, uh, publish one to
two episodes per week panel discussion.
If you have people around, let's
say a two or three or four guest for
your podcast, you can hell around
50 to 75 minutes of each episode
and you can publish one episode of.
Storytelling storytelling is, uh,
not something like solo stories.
So storytelling is something about sharing
about the people of others, or you take it
something about, uh, you know, considering
the, uh, the success stories of others.
So in that way, you can, uh,
you know, share your thoughts
as 15 to 20 minutes range.
And weekly three episodes
or even two episodes.
Last one is a fusion one.
Well, this word is given by me.
So why I wanted to make it very, uh,
you know, impactful and something that,
uh, you know, you can easily remember.
So fusion is something.
Where you are not sure about whether
you want to go for podcast, which
is solo or interview, you can do
combination of all the above things.
So you can have that combination
and people will love it.
So based on the feedback of the, of
your audience slowly you grow, and
that's how you make it impactful.
And that ranges from 20 to 30 minutes.
And depending upon the frequency
you can publish on a week basis.
Is, this is something very important.
Now, here is the real journey
that starts for you, right?
Is this good time to start podcasting?
Yes, definitely.
So what is the first step?
Now?
You are clear that you want
to start with podcasting.
So what is the first step?
Identify your strengths and weaknesses.
See friends, you are developer, and
when you are starting your journey.
But you might have identify your
strengths and weaknesses or what you
might have happened that your seniors
might have advised you for certain,
certain things that you are good
at this, you are not good at this.
You need to improve at this area.
So this is the right time to list down
all the things and see for yourself
next while you have listed them.
What steps you for.
What stops you from
starting with something new?
Always.
This is a question around for everyone.
When you are starting your new journey for
anything, that is something, and that is
one barrier for each and every one of us.
And that is fear, fear of speaking,
fear of running fear of, uh, talking
to someone as fear of networking.
So this is RD now, what are
different types of fear?
Let's see the next slide we
have fear of exploration.
So is that, uh, uh, assembling with you?
Expiration means you have everything,
but you are not able to bring
up among the people publicly.
So this fear you might be having,
I'm not saying you are having, you
might be having fear of communication.
You are good at everything.
And sometimes you too, the language
barrier sometimes because you
have a shyness, you may be having.
Uh, fear of communication.
You are not able to communicate with
people in a very effective manner.
That's fine.
You just start with something
and slowly you can improve that.
Fear of public speaking.
Now see friends today.
I'm able to talk in front of you.
It's not just because
I, I am, I was expert.
I, you know, took this time and learn from
different people within the community.
So while I'm, uh, you know,
learning from the community, I make
mistakes and that's how I grew.
And today I'm able to speak in
front of you without any fear.
So you can also identify your fear and
you can come out of that knowledge.
You know, friends, uh, sometimes
what happens is you have knowledge,
but you are not confident whether I
should share this publicly or not.
So this also fear, uh, you
know, sometimes, uh, puts
you in a wrong direction.
Fear of, let's say.
Uh, point of view, for example,
there is something, uh, on a blog
or a statement made by a famous, uh,
influencer or developer or someone,
and you want to, you know, write
something, but you fear what if I write?
Or what if I talk about a particular
discussion on a podcast or something?
So this is how.
Fear of planning and execution.
You are very good at, you have, you know,
decent years of experience as a developer,
but you fear to start, uh, planning and
executing, uh, each episode, where are
you where to start and all those things.
Last one is the most important
and most common one fear of ideas.
You have everything with you, but
you're, uh, you know, figuring out.
Uh, how to start when to start, what
to start and why should I start?
So that is also the caution.
Like if you are a developer,
why should I start?
So you will get all the
answers in the upcoming slides.
How to overcome the fear of speaking.
Now you have identified
different types of fear.
So what is the next one?
Networking is the best way that as much
as you network with people that you
will come to know that you are gaining
confidence and that confidence will
eventually help you in podcasting.
As well, so always network
friends, even today.
I do not miss out any conferences
and I network with lots of people
participate in the discussions.
So the more you discuss, the
more you discuss with people
and that's how you grow.
And, you know, you make, uh,
your network in a more proper.
Grab opportunities to become a speaker
at various grant opportunities to become
a speaker at various meetups and events.
If you are a new one, new,
if you are someone who is
very shy in sharing publicly.
And do not fear, you know, become
a speaker and let's make a mistake.
It's not something you can give
everything in the first shot, right?
So slowly, slowly, you grow, listen
to various podcasts to understand
the flow of delivering a speech
right now, you are a developer.
So there are lots of people, even
within WordPress community who
have started their podcast channel.
So listen to them and take
some inspiration from.
Start your watching loud debates.
Nonpolitical.
Of course I start your
own YouTube channel.
Now, here is something very important
to note when you are starting with
podcast, see friends, uh, it's
always better to start with video.
Why?
Because after all podcasting
is all about audio.
So the expression of your face.
That automatically reflects
towards your, you know, this
mouth and that comes to the voice.
So it's a psychological thing.
So always start your YouTube channel
and come to the comfort level of
speaking to the people through first
video, and then starting with audio
part frequently share videos on
social media platforms about your work
progress experience in new learnings.
If you are working on a project, let's
say, and you, uh, explored a particular
functionality or a feature, but there
are a few things that you cannot express,
or you cannot talk about publicly.
That's fine.
But if you come to a challenge or you
help solve something, you can share
with people and take advantage of that.
The more you share with people,
the more networks you get, the
more leads you generate now.
Come out of language barrier, see friends,
podcasting is not just about, uh, uh,
you're not talking about in just English.
You can, if you are, uh, you see
today, uh, I'm very fortunate.
I feel lucky that I have talking
to people around the world and you
all are from different regions.
You may have different languages.
So you start with that language, right.
Be comfort in that.
And then you can come to
English and international level.
That's fine.
Come out of a language barrier
and never look at people when
they might make fun of you.
When you are starting with your
journey, you know what happens?
Uh, people make fun of you because
you are they mistake now, who does Mr.
Because you are taking something action.
When you take action, then
only you make mistake, right?
So that's fine.
Be comfortable start working
on it and be consistent.
Be keep working and keep
focusing on yourself.
And the last one is be a good listener
along with being a good auditor.
This is also very important.
Now, if I just go on speaking
before luck, uh, let's say one hour,
two hour, it's not going to help.
I also have to listen a lot.
So even today, this is a practice
that I do when I talk with people
and listen to their challenges.
First, I, I listened to their
introduction first, and then only I
start with my introduction that helps
me to understand their perspective.
So when I understand their perspective,
I can address according to them.
So this is a good practice for everyone.
Next.
Okay.
Now you have overcome the fear next.
You want to start your podcast.
Get that information.
That's the important thing.
Listen to podcasts.
As I said earlier, record your own voice.
Now, when you have started a podcast,
uh, let's say, uh, your YouTube
channel now record your own voice.
I'll talk about different
tools at the very last.
Take feedback from your
friends and seniors.
Keep consistency in networking consistency
in context, that will help you to grow
at a, you know, at a very larger level,
explore topics, trends, and interests.
Don't randomly start
podcasting on different topics.
No learn out, identify topics
on which you are comfortable.
Identify times I did have
a interest of the audience.
For example, you are, uh, on,
let's say on Twitter and you
have 1000 followers with you.
So do not just, uh, uh, start with
something that I'm going to start hell
you know, their feedback, what they
are interested in, learn about their
interests and then start your journey.
So now, Are you excited to
start a new journey for podcast?
Yes.
Now next few slides are the most
important one, so never miss out,
you know, keep focusing on this.
So what are they the reasons to start now?
If I, I have been telling you
start your podcast journey, but why
you don't need to start, you will
have this question in mind, right?
So it's a, one of the most
preferred form of content.
Even if you do not have ability
to write blogs, if you do not
have the ability to, um, you know,
work on your videos, that's fine.
You can start with podcasting.
You can listen to anywhere.
It's the era of multitasking.
What is the meaning of the multitasking?
So multitasking doesn't mean that,
uh, you do everything at a time.
Multitasking means if you are doing some
activity less a year, you're working on
some coding part and you'll feel bored.
So at the same time, you can
even listen to a podcast.
So like, listen now, Uh, just imagine
you are starting your own podcast
channel and someone other developer,
they want to, uh, get some to podcasts.
So they search for you.
Okay.
This is something that I will do, uh,
listen, and also I want to work on.
Now that's a, uh, you know, multitask
and, uh, they will find it very useful,
has lot of potential to generate leads.
As I said earlier, forecasting has lot of,
uh, you know, uh, potential to generate
leads and to make connections, but it
takes a lot of time with team based
medium to build a relationship with.
Businesses, whether it is agency owners,
whether it is enterprises, whether it is
it companies or even Browns, they want to
invite you, or they want to collaborate
with you because you are delivering
something very valuable to them.
Opportunity to be guest or not.
This podcast series see
friends, if you want to grow.
Okay, that's fine.
You are starting your podcast series,
but also apparently simultaneously focus
on being a guest on different platforms.
Uh, and, uh, you know, you
do not have to be doing.
By yourself slowly and steadily while you
share a good, valuable content with them,
they will, uh, reach out to you as today.
Even today, people reach out to me for,
uh, you know, interviewing or for getting,
uh, you know, Uh, let's say published on
their articles, like blogs or something.
So I hope almost a given my interview
on two to three podcast channels.
So that's how you grow.
You share your address with their guest.
Now podcast has just
opened up a long way to go.
What does this mean?
It's not that it's just how
awkward, but you have so much to
share with people through podcast.
And that's where it makes it very
unique from different forms of
content today, forecasts episodes
are available in different languages
for various niches market is here.
So what's the next.
Now you will know that.
What are the reasons now, second
question that may arise in your mind
is should I use website development,
team development and plugin
development to start with podcasts?
Because podcasting has
its own process, right?
Recording, editing, and everything.
So that does mean that you have to
live your, uh, present, uh, uh, you
know, business or a job or something.
No, you do not have to live that, but in
fact, forecasting improves your knowledge.
It helps you in personal branding.
It has.
Gaining confidence, talking to
people, the removes fear of public
speaking, no one is there to see you.
Yeah.
When you are recording a voice,
no one is there to see you or
judge you how you are looking.
See it the way you are speaking.
No, it's all dependent on your voice.
So you have to only work on just one area.
And that is what.
You have a dead areas.
Sound is that, uh, you
know, the volume is there.
That's different, but you have
only one focus that is audio.
Part process is easy at first.
You might find it very difficult, but
as in V when you progress, it will,
uh, you know, uh, look very easy.
Abs in business growth.
Yeah.
If you are doing business, let's
say freelancing, if you are doing,
or if you are an individual, this
helps a lot in your business as well.
You scope of various topics to talk about.
It's not just about one or two topics.
You have a lot of industry you
have today in, uh, even in,
uh, WordPress community itself.
We have so much to talk about.
From the perspective of marketing from the
perspective of SEO, from the perspective
of, uh, let's say, uh, front-end
back-end and everything is there, right?
So can be a form of giving
back to the community.
See friends, uh, community is giving
us in a lot of different models.
But, uh, when we share with people
through, uh, podcasting is we share
knowledge, we share our experience,
we share our challenges and we
invite some of the famous people
or some well-known people or people
who are working in community day
and night, if you invite them.
So you see you are in the form of you are
giving them back to the community right?
Next.
What is podcasting for developers?
Now we all ready, talked about
fear and everything, but actually,
what is forecasting for developers?
It improves work efficiency.
When you collaborate with others or
when you take interviews with others
or when you, uh, you know, listen to
podcast, you get to know a lot of things.
You, you, uh, explore different resources,
you explore different methods, you explore
different, uh, functionality to send fi.
Among the WordPress community itself.
So this is something very important.
Get broader idea about themes, plugins for
press lettuce updates, get to know about
other developers, their methodology tools.
They use challenges.
They have best practices.
Stand out from the crowd.
You are a developer, you are
doing something amazing within
the WordPress community.
And I believe you all are doing amazing.
Not just one person
you all are doing with.
Uh, something which is a commendable,
but if you are starting your
podcast journey in the beginning,
you might face a lot of challenges.
You might, uh, how the fear that's
fine, but when you get going with
that, You, if people would recognize
in that form, that this person is
also a developer and a podcaster as
well, people will want you to give
advices as an expert on their podcast.
So they will invite you as
an, uh, you know, someone who
will, uh, give them advice.
For example, I went to give a very
simple example, a quick example.
Let's say you are in a growing stage.
You just started with one or two episodes.
People love to listen to it.
And you get the invitation from
a, another podcast channel who
is having around 10,000 to 15,000
audience regularly watching each
episode or listening to them.
Now, just see the impact
you are giving them.
You are going there as a guest, you are
sharing your knowledge and the response
you get, or people will approach you.
It's just unimaginable, right?
You can focus in that manner, better
visibility among the people down yourself
from knowledge equity to knowledge
provider right now, while you do not
have much knowledge about podcasting.
Uh, so you are getting knowledge,
you know, you're acquiring no.
Once you get the steps once, you
know, the process of podcasting.
And when you share with other
people, that's where you
become knowledge provider.
So see that transformation from knowledge
equator to knowledge provider next.
Now this is something very,
uh, much of your useful.
This is something very useful resources.
You can listen to some of this
podcast, uh, on, at your convenience.
First one is pat Flynn to who even I
follow on a regular basis and I are
learned so much of things from him.
So I highly recommend
to learn from scratch.
If you don't have.
Any of the steps to start with podcasting,
you can start listening to pat Flynn.
Gary Vernicek, we know is good at branding
and different aspects of marketing.
Tim Ferris set called in who, uh, he
runs like a akimbo or cuss channel.
Do the VU from the WordPress community.
We have WVU is a to Zed WP coffee talk.
The guiding was which.
Oh, it's focused on interviewing, uh,
it professionals and other experts from
various industries around the world.
Post status forecast, your website aging.
So these are the, some of the,
uh, well-known, uh, forecast.
And I think that if you refer them,
you'll get to know a lot of things now.
This is something of the real
formula, or you can say the
real ingredient of podcasting.
You can take the screenshot of this.
I have been working in most of,
uh, I have been working on some of
the tools and still I'm exploring.
So there are some things that.
Uh, uh, you know, that keeps changing
and even as they change the features
functionalities and all those things.
So you have recording and editing
where you can use garage band
and logic pro for Mac or sat, or
the Adobe audition for windows.
You have zoom and Skype
for recording purpose.
You have designing for Canva, Adobe
illustrator, Adobe spark Raila,
wispy post, a podcast distribution,
where you can distribute.
Recorded and completed episodes.
So these are the, uh, areas where
you can start with anchor.fm.
Why?
Because it allows you to
distribute into multiple channels.
But, uh, uh, you can also learn to, uh,
distribute separately manually, right?
You have podcasters streaming platforms
where all the podcast episodes will be
streamed, uh, for all of your channel.
And when you want to get your, uh,
you know, sound effects or let's
say a background music you can get
from the YouTube's audio library,
music for content creator, you can
search this and you can get that.
And the book that the heart
of the podcasting planning
and execution is mind map.
So you can use whimsical or mine.
Mister, I use whimsical.
Why?
Because it's very simple.
You just have to plan
out the anti-oppressive.
Just think I, you know, uh, how,
uh, plan of, uh, exit complete, uh,
execution from the scratch level.
So it's a like, uh, research work,
inviting guest, uh, execution marketing.
Distribution editing all episodes,
recording all episodes, title, everything.
Is there, uh, for me at, uh, mind maps.
So use for yourself also slowly, slowly,
you know, first, uh, you know, you, uh,
create smaller mindmaps and then you.
And before I, uh, you know, tell about
or share about this monster thought in
the end, I would highly recommend when
you are recording your voice or you are
starting your podcast channel, do not plan
to start with 10 minutes or 15 minutes.
Always start with two to three
minutes because that's your,
your space to grow, to improve.
And, uh, to find out that
where you are lacking.
Because if you are starting for 10, 15
minutes, you have large, huge scope you
at right now, you do not need huge scope.
You need to take action for forecasting.
So this a last thought, something
that I want to share with you, good
ideas are common, but those who are
willing to take action and execute
those ideas are far more rare.
What does this mean?
You have, we all have, uh,
ideas which are very common.
Who all take action and execute them.
Those ideas become rarest
thing in today's world.
This is again by pat Flynn.
Well-known podcaster.
So that's it from me.
Thank you for your precious time.
I highly appreciate your time
spending on this particular session.
So thank you and namaste from India.
Yogesh Londhe: I see you here.
What did you say?
Lax Mariappan: That that was a good talk.
Very encouraging, motivating.
And thanks for putting all the, uh, all
the questions that a beginner might have
answered everything in the slides already.
Yogesh Londhe: So Lax, by the
way, in just distracting from the
topic that I'm just loving that.
You know WordFest, uh, that you get
the bite, the music it's very catchy,
you know, 24 hours, 60 sessions,
one community it's very engaging.
And, uh, Sumant mentioned about, uh,
finding, uh, copyright free music.
Copy, left music in.
Yeah.
So we've got few questions for someone.
Yes.
Lax.
Uh, you want to go with
the first question?
Lax Mariappan: Yeah.
So, uh, you know, podcasting is, um,
it's also like, uh, blogging or like
there's a lot of competition that
are already established podcasts.
So how do a developer or
someone who's just starting
out, make a podcast, stand out.
Sumant Lohar: Yeah.
So, as I said earlier, there are so many
resources within WordPress community.
You can refer them.
And apart from that, you can start
with just two, two to three episodes
and publish on just Audacity.
And once you publish that, and when
you share with your friends or your,
uh, let's say, uh, your companions,
companions, and that's how you come to
know that where are the areas that you
need to improve because at first shot.
If you just, uh, go on distributing on
different channels, there'll be a little,
uh, space for the improvement part.
Yogesh Londhe: Okay.
That's nice.
Okay.
Um, now, and I have a question
how to promote my podcast.
I have made a proud
podcast how to promote it.
I would do the same thing.
I think it's the same question.
So we'll go to the next question.
Yeah.
Well, I will put, put a question to you.
What kind of debates and
podcasts do you listen to?
Um, in what languages?
Sumant Lohar: Uh, usually I listen
to podcasts in a Hindi and English
languages, uh, and the debates are
around, uh, let's say, uh, the,
uh, cross border, uh, discussing.
Or maybe let's say around,
uh, technology part.
We, we have seen that in the
recent, uh, just few months
we have seen Meta Verse there.
And a lot of other technology has come
up, but, uh, are we ready for that?
So, uh, the experts, uh, talk very
nicely with an example, how to be ready
with all those upcoming technologies.
Yogesh Londhe: Okay, so you listen to
Hindi and, uh, uh, how so, how about,
how about the podcasts in Hindi?
Like, is there, uh, English has lot
of possible podcasts, but how many
podcasts are they in Hindi or Gujarati?,
Sumant Lohar: uh, see uh, compared
to of course English is the most, uh,
uh, preferred one, but even, uh, as
of last three months, if you count
so regional languages, uh, podcasts
are in demand, huge demand and people
are still in fear how to start them.
If they start, they will get huge
popularity from the beginning itself.
Yogesh Londhe: Okay.
Lax, any questions?
We can't hear you, your mic is off.
Lax Mariappan: Okay.
So maybe I muted my mic.
So, uh, it's almost the same question.
So what do you recommend or what do
you, uh, yeah, what do you recommend?
Like someone should start broadcasting
their language, like in their
mother tongue I am from Tamil Nadu.
I speak Tamil more fluently, so I should
start a podcast in Tamil, or I can try
English or like other popular language?
Sumant Lohar: Yeah, definitely.
Definitely.
If you start, uh, broadcasting in mother
tongue, you'll be more comfortable, you
know, comfortable and even, uh, you know,
confident because you know something about
your language and if you are starting
in English, what will happen is you will
first be struggling with the process of
podcasting as well as with the language.
So this, uh, uh, difference.
Yogesh Londhe: Okay, so you suggest,
um, mother tongue podcasts should be, it
should take, it should take priority okay.
That's good.
Technology podcasts in Tamil
or canada would be amazing.
Amazing.
Yeah.
Okay.
Um, Sumant, now.
I'll ask a question.
Uh, can you give us the popular,
uh, podcasts platforms like people?
What kind of platforms do people listen
to sound cloud or, uh, I don't know.
Sumant Lohar: So there are platform
platforms, mainly, uh, Spotify
is that apple iTunes is there.
So these are the two platforms.
If any of the  podcaster, uh, whether
they are new or the existing one,
if they focus, they will get a huge
popularity in terms of views, in terms
of audience, in terms of downloads.
Yogesh Londhe: Okay.
Uh, what about, do you see
about this one pocket cast?
I, I listened to pocket cast.
I dunno.
Yeah.
I, I like the content there too.
Um, is there a way to, uh, host
your audio file somewhere and just
let Google do its magic on Google?
Because Google has a tool, which a
collates podcast from around the web
and just gives you, it's not a platform,
it's just a tool which lets the.
Sumant Lohar: Yeah.
So every, every content format has
its own SEO, uh, you know, framework.
So like if you are using a YouTube SEO,
so you have video, uh, uh, part and all
those titles and everything in the same.
If you are sharing those audio files
through this platform, which I told you,
so they will help to in, in such also.
So, but if you randomly upload
somewhere, uh, it might not be
recognizable as it should be.
Okay.
Yogesh Londhe: Okay.
I got my own opinions on
some of the platforms.
Yeah, talk side.
We'll listen to your views.
Okay.
Um, yeah.
Lax Mariappan: So far developers,
what are the, some popular
podcasts or broadcasters, uh,
that you recommend to listen?
Sumant Lohar: Uh, yeah, as, as, uh, you
know, uh, shared in the slide itself.
So there are some, uh, podcasters,
like Do The Woo is also there.
And we have, uh, I suppose there is
some, uh, uh, w Elementor or Yoast
or other, uh, areas where you can
listen to podcasts and, uh, get
updated knowledge from them itself.
Yeah.
Yogesh Londhe: Lax, do you listen
to this podcast distributed?
Lax Mariappan: Uh, no, but, uh, I
listened to some other WordPress
related, like a Post Excerpt from
Post Status, uh, WP Minute from
Yogesh Londhe: very nice podcast.
It's not a technology, but it
talks a lot about distributed
nature of work sometimes.
Uh, the name of the podcast
itself is distributed.
It's it's started by some, uh,
angel investor jazz musician.
Okay.
Yeah, it sounds interesting.
So do we have any other
questions for, uh, Sumant, Lax?.
Lax Mariappan: Yeah.
So, um, I have, uh, some questions
like, uh, I mean, can we go with
the TLDR version of his talk
or something like, uh, yeah.
It's like, yeah, you can summarize
within another, like, uh, one or
two minutes about like most of the
challenges, like what people, um,
like the common challenges that every.
Experience and what should they can
avoid and also how they can monetize
are how they can benefit from it.
So again,
Yogesh Londhe: Monetize,
monetize, yeah, monetize.
Yes, that's a good question.
Sumant Lohar: Yeah.
So, uh, first thing is, uh, the
common challenge that, uh, most
of the business face is using the
tools because every tool has its own
functionality and a different purpose.
For example, if you are doing it
for you have recorded and, uh, an
episode in a zoom or Skype, and
then you're taking it for editing.
So you edit on audacity for windows
and GarageBand on a Mac, but
you, how to first learn all the
features and everything around that.
And then only you can move forward.
And at the same time talking
about the monetization part.
So, uh, say monetization, uh, does not
happen, uh, within one or two months.
But slowly, when you go with like 25,
30, 40 episodes and you collaborate
with more, more and more, uh, you know,
podcasters, you upper, you know, approach
them or they invite you as guests.
So the collaboration here, the
important element is the collaboration.
The more collaborations you have, the more
audience you have, the, you know, to get
better with, uh, the monitorization part.
Yogesh Londhe: Okay, thanks for the tips.
So, um, so Sumant there is a
question and how to promote podcasts
without installing any apps.
Sumant Lohar: Yeah.
So, uh, without installing any apps,
I think, uh, you can, uh, you know, be
very active on social media platforms,
especially on Instagram and Twitter.
Because these are two areas where
you can share with people and talk
about your podcast or what you
are looking at and you have today,
uh, Twitter spaces are so there.
And a lot of other things
also are there in a line, so
you can, uh, share with them.
And apart from that, if you want to,
you know, promote your podcast channel.
So along with the audio part,
record them in video part and share.
As a video on YouTube channel.
Yogesh Londhe: Okay, great.
So thank you very much Sumant.
Sumant Lohar: thank you.
Yogesh Londhe: Someone is a friend is
always whenever there is a WordPress
event, Sumant is there to volunteer.
Thank you very much nice seeing you here.
Sumant Lohar: Thank you so much.
Thank you.
Yogesh Londhe: So Lax do we want to thank.
Our sponsors?.
Lax Mariappan: Yeah, we'd
like to thank our sponsors,
uh, for giving us this space.
Uh, our thanks to our sponsors,
Bluehost, Cloudways, uh, GoDaddy
Pro, Nexcess, Yoast, and Weglot.
Please be sure to visit their
tents and chat with them.
And there is a chance
it might win prizes too.
And there are some guests
visiting in the tents.
And also don't forget to get your,
uh, photo snap in the photo booth.
That's sponsored by Multicollab
and Dreamhost and and Tweet your
photo, uh, with the hashtag WordFest
Live, and also thanks to our
media partners and micro sponsors.
Yogesh Londhe: You all make
our Big Orange Heart full.