Yoast: Do you know, the Yoast SEO,
plugin, they're red, orange, and
green feedback bullets that help
you optimize your posts for the web.
It runs on millions of websites.
We tried to make SEO understandable
and accessible to everyone.
Bluehost: Who says building
an online store has to be hard
with Bluehost website builder.
It's more than just easy.
It's tell us your thing in smart AI.
We'll take it from there.
Easy it's WooCommerce friendly.
So you can add one of these
or swap this for that.
It's set up shop in minutes
with unlimited products.
Easy.
Whether you sell boots, books
or bowls, it's create an online
store with Bluehost, easy build
beyond boundaries with Bluehost.
Nexcess: Oh, great.
My website crashed again.
I give up, don't give up on your
dreams, Jordan, who are you?
It's me.
You from the future.
Your professional website
is not out of reach.
You just need the Nexcess.
With Nexcess managed hosting, you
get lightning Paslode times built
and performance monitoring and
updates, and always awesome support.
24 7 365.
For all your props.
Whoa.
Yeah.
Weglot: Discover Weglot the simple
translation solution for your website.
All you have to do is add
Weglot to your website, select
the languages that you need.
And that's it.
Your website is now available
in multiple languages.
Yogesh Londhe: We are enjoying these
amazing sessions and even on stage two,
there are some fantastic sessions there.
Lax Mariappan: Yeah.
That's the beauty of online, uh,
events like you are free to choose
Yogesh Londhe: So much choice.
Yeah.
So I will catch up with I've.
I've got some of the couple of sessions
that I would love to catch up on a
stage two when the recorded sessions
already to be able to catch it.
Yeah.
Lax you want to introduce
our next speaker?
Meher Bala: Yeah.
Uh, coming up next, we have our speaker
Meher Bala uh, she will be talking about
the benefits of being part of a committee.
Uh, if you are part of, uh, Twitter,
our WordPress follow at  communities
and she's nothing new she's well-known.
So my Meher Bala is a WordPress
consultant and a front-end web
developer specializing in WordPress.
She builds and maintains premium
websites for her clients and delivers
them on the tight deadlines with care.
She co-hosts the podcast.
Unplugged Tech, uh, which seeks to
amplify inspiring and fascinating
stories of friendly talk, a
friendly folks in the tech world.
And Meher supports the WordPress
community as a member of, uh, make
teams and contributes to release us, uh.
Benefits of being part of the community.
Hello, my name is Meher Bala . I'm a
front-end and an expert at Codeable.
I work as a WordPress consultant.
And partner at a hosting
company, happy post.
I'm very active in the open source space.
I'm a co-organiser of WordCamp
Mumbai, WordCamp India,
WordPress translation days.
I'm, fascinated by the inspiring
stories from the people tech.
And as part of that, I
co-founded and co-host.
Unplugged Tech podcast.
This meant very first WordFest Talk.
I'm delighted to be sharing this team
inspired you to join your local or
global community and discover the
benefits for you and the wider project.
In this talk I will share with you
the learnings and the insights of
being a part of a tech community
during the last seven years.
Let's get started with
what is a community.
It is defined as a group of
people who interact with one
another and share common goals.
or vision.
It can be anything from a place, from
a physical place where people connect
or a virtual space as social media
groups and private community platform.
I think part of an engaging community
can give us a sense of belonging.
It can help us to share persons,
thoughts, and learnings to which
others can relate and support the
personal growth of each other.
As humans, we tend to benefit
from being with others.
Connecting at a part of the meaningful
community is important for their
wellbeing and general mental health.
In the next three slides, I'm going
to share some research data would show
how important community engage is.
That's have a deeper look at the first
data done on open source, engaging.
Thank you to nonstop news and non-stop
business support, which led me to the
source and let us data from 2018 to
2022 in my talk today, this was such
elapsed illustrate the benefit that a
community engagement can bring to you.
In 2018, 2019, a survey was done
with 67% oh, those who replied.
Found being a part of an open source
community was an important part of the
support system in business and local area.
In 2000, 2021, the pandemic here, the
same survey was conducted when it showed
an increase of 89%, the comments shared,
examples of how the different committees.
Had helped people connect
and to take together.
This varied from weekly get together to
drop it, to look at a particular issue.
Let's now take a look at the second survey
which is related to community engagement.
In 2000 2018, a survey was conducted
where people said what they
learned through tech communities.
They had learned practical skills
that they had put into the work place.
The same survey was conducted in 2021.
The pandemic here at it showed
a decrease in percentage.
Do you find the decline was partly due to
fluctuating internet access to office and
job opportunities during the pandemic.
People also reported difficulties
adjusting to learning environment
on video calls, especially with
dealing with multiple demands on
their time from work at home, online
events can add an extra pressure.
We all know that, but by being
a part of the community, people
found ways to adjust their learning
needs and make networks to help.
Let's take a look at the last
survey, which is conducted for
community engagement and wellbeing.
We've talked about how contributing
to a community can help you move
forward and be connected, especially
during the period of crisis.
This has been shown to in many research
studies during and after the pandemic,
let's look at 2018 to 2022 research.
People said involved in open source
and open source community had a
positive effect on their wellbeing.
They felt part of something bigger.
This was a case of both of these
who described themselves as being
on the edge of the community
engagement and regular contributors.
In 2008, 2009, the survey showed 34%
of the people that believed in this.
In 2000, 2021, 7, 3 73% of
the people believed in this.
And 12% of the people reported no effect
or highlighted stress effects from the
way of communication had changed in 2021.
This was in line with the wider research
done by non-stop business support and
from other studies global lead showing
that active community engagement can aid
well-being thank you to [inaudible] for
allowing me to include all the research
information for this presentation.
At the end of this presentation,
I will share a link where you
can go and vote anonymous.
Share your thoughts on
benefits at the community.
It will help researchers and
aware, rising being done by groups,
including unplug tech podcast.
It will be shared to assist the Big Orange
Heart the charity behind this wonderful
WordFest event it collaboration is like.
This is another example of how people
come together in a community for
greater participation, diversity, and.
Now let's look at how, how you find
a community, understand the different
communities around you, choose the
one which help you nurture, and
you feel really where you belong.
Community plays an important
role in all aspects of our life.
We have communities in our friends, our
family, our neighbors in our employment.
And so many other places, wherever
you go, you will find a community.
Being a part of the community can
make ourselves feel as though we are
a part of something greater, even more
reasons to research and find communities
where you will feel at home and grow.
People always ask me this question.
Why, why am I an advocate of a community?
I believe, I believe a community can
help each one of us in many aspects of
our life, a community like WordPress
and give us an opportunity to connect
with people, to just search our goals
and be a part of a confidence building.
Before joining the WordPress
community, I was asked a few questions.
Why are you joining the local community?
What are the benefits of
the WordPress community?
Is it community a waste
of time and energy?
What help can they provide?
It seems to be a few, a woman.
How will you survive?
These questions did not stop me
from finding a local community.
I wanted to surround myself with value
driven people who knew the language
of tech and coding and wants to be a
part of helping me make things bigger.
This led me to WordPress Mumbai community.
This is where I attended and wanting
to add my first WordCamp Mumbai.
Once part of the local community.
I got to know there was a WordPress
community that stretched around the
world events like this means we can
share our voices across the globe.
Let's look at some of the benefits of
joining an source community, first friends
and network, making friends and network
who live locally and across the globe.
You never know when friends can
turn into business or life partners.
This is a good way to get to know cultures
and different countries around the world.
Next knowledge learning and mentorship.
Join the community to learn from
and with others and share knowledge.
You will meet different types of
people with different views, experience
and beliefs, learning from them.
Reach insight that we may not
have learned in on our own.
I can certainly vouch for this
next collaborating and work opportunities,
collaborating, collaborating
with people from the community to
work on different and interesting
projects, like building websites for
nonprofits and support good causes.
Everyone loves to it.
Right.
WordCamps gives us, gives us the
opportunity to, with her friends
in the community and explore
different parts of the country.
Inspiration in the community
you will find many people who
inspire and motivate others.
Those are the people who you need
to follow, and then don't try
to be an inspiration for others.
It has been.
It is because of the people
who have inspired me.
And I have had the privilege
of being mentored by that.
I'm here with you today, able to deliver
a talk on an international platform
and share my experience with everyone
next support being a
part of the community.
And it was asked to give
support to other members.
Supporting others and help them
feel good about themselves and be
more confident with so much stress
in busy in today's busy world.
We live in.
There's never been the right
time to help those struggling
with the physical and what
the physical and mental wellbeing.
Next sharing, chatting
activities, ideas, feelings.
Reinforces not only a sense
of self, but also adds what
and value to that community.
Indeed.
The more the merrier lies in this case,
the last don't just take, but give to
any community works better, better when
relationship with it travels in both
direction being apart of the committee.
Does not always mean that you should,
you should expect automatically.
You should expect people continuously
and automatically helping you.
You need to make an effort to encourage
interact and know people in the community
and support them when they need it.
Remember being a part of the
community is a two way street.
There may be so many other benefits
and fossilized ones, especially to you
Sharing my top ten list, which will
hopefully inspire you to step outside
your comfort zone and join the community
that that will help you feel braver to.
WordCamps, and WordPress events.
I attended ,volunteered,
sponsored, spoken at different
WordCamps and WordPress events.
And in 2019, I was lead
organizer for WordCamp Mumbai.
Be great to be interviewed by
international podcasts, including
WP Water Cooler and Do The Woo.
Sharing my story with HeroPress to
inspire others, to overcome barriers that
they may face in their lives and work
finding opportunities to contribute
to WordPress and becoming a team rep
for the global WordPress marketing
team, all these oppurtunities
means I can encouraged others.
Being a part of the WordPress 5.6
release squad and a contributor
to a number of other releases.
This is how you can be a bot or the
future development of the software.
And it's open to all,
A, panelists on the page
builder, the summit 2000.
Uh, panelist on a page builder
summit, 2021, a big thanks to
Adam, Maya and the rest of the
team at GoDaddy in believing in me.
Thank you to the Bluehost in your
team for asking me to be a jury member
for the WordPress creators award
and the first edition of WordFest,
my podcast Unplugged Dot Tech
contributed at the media partner.
In the second edition, I was selected
to be a part of the community interview.
Third edition.
I was third edition, which is now I
stepped up further and applied to be
a speaker on the main team for the
event and support Big Orange Heart.
I have partnered with community
friends, opened up businesses and
worked together on good projects.
But the, for the past two years, I
have been a part of the organizing
team of WordPress translation day.
I've supported the event as a developer,
as a tech support giver as a marketer, as
a translator and as a community advocate.
I inspired to find the
community and get started.
I would love to your how, how my
story has inspired you and what your
journey will be chatting with me
on Twitter at @MeherBala via direct
message or leave a message on my feed.
A lot of people ask me where do you find
these active and engaging communities?
Here are a few names.
I am going to tell you, which you
may consider as part of your journey,
the local WordPress community.
This can be in your local town or area.
If you don't have one, start
one, find people who love the
software and build a committee.
The Big Orange Heart Slack, HeroPress
network, ladies of the WordPress.
Remote India.
This is the largest community of
folks working remotely in India and
has grown four times in the last
two years because of the pandemic.
Post Status, WooCommerce
community and Do The Woo.
WordPress product community on LinkedIn.
If you love Facebook, there's a group
named advanced WordPress on Facebook.
There's an other group name, web
creators community on Facebook.
There's an other group theme,
WP Builds, but not the least.
Don't forget your work for me.
It is a codeable for me, it
is at codeable with other
developers from across the globe.
I would like to take this opportunity
and give a special shout out to some
of the amazing people I have met first
Big Orange Heart team for giving me
this opportunity to share my thoughts.
Vachan Kudmule a community
friend business partner.
Abha Thakor for being my mentor
and access to training courses.
Michelle Frechette, Maja Loncar
and Andrea Middleton for being
inspirational community managers.
I told all my friends globally, I
locally for believing and encouraging me.
As promised, sharing this bitly link,
where you can express anonymously on the
community benefits to help for the work
to encourage open source participation,
diversity and sustainability.
Thank you to everyone who came to listen
to my talk, ways to connect with me on
Twitter and LinkedIn @MeherBala, WordPress
global marketing channel is @Meher.
You can contact me on my
website https://meherbala.com.
if you have interesting stories to
share, come contact me on unplug.tech.
Yogesh Londhe: Meher how
are things in Mumbai?
And how are you?
Meher Bala: On how are you back to normal?
Full speed.
Everything is opened
up, so I'm doing what?
Yogesh Londhe: Oh, good,
good, good, good, good.
And, uh, thank you very much
for a fantastic session.
And, uh, everybody who knows me
knows that Meher is a community
person, a fantastic community leader.
So we have a few questions for you meher
and, uh, I'm just glad to chat with you.
So start with, could you share an
anecdote, uh, how, what community has
benefited you are someone that, you know,
so first question is, could you share
an anecdote how, what birth community
has benefited you are someone who is.
Meher Bala: I think one of
the main benefits on the
Yogesh Londhe: Can we have
the questions on the screen.
Did you hear that question?
Meher Bala: Yes.
I heard it.
Yeah.
One of the main benefits I think
anyone gets is friendship because
that's where the bond is created.
That's where the communication goes.
If it's for me, it's the different
friendships around the world, but I
own the local community because that
is where it makes a person strong.
For example, if I give my example
becoming a part of the local Mumbai
community, I met so many different people.
It made me go around different words.
It made me travel.
It made me meet people like Yogesh
and a lot of other people Rahul
and a lot of other people around
India, which by not joining the
community, I may not not have met you.
Oh, by joining the international
community, I met amazing
people around the world.
I'm sure if I travel anywhere, I am
going to have one person, at least in
the WordPress community who will be
a part of that city or that country.
And I'll get to explore the local place,
not like a tourist, but like being a part
of the city because a lot of times like
tourist, you miss a lot of great cities.
So for me, community is.
First friendship and then everything.
Lax Mariappan: Yeah, that is great.
Like communities help you grow your,
uh, you know, grow your network.
And that network opens
the door to many options.
And then it can be your new job or
like you may meet your new client and
in your talk, you mentioned you may
meet you, you know, um, friends, even
business partner, or even like partners.
It was great.
Meher Bala: Yeah.
Actually, because I have seen
recently you do meet your life
partners as well in the community.
Lax Mariappan: Yeah.
Like minded people.
Yeah.
That, that ignites the spark.
It's nice.
Nice to, uh, and so, so, um, how
about the five for the future?
Like, you know, it's a community
driven event, so can you share us
like, uh, you know, maybe some of us
who are watching this may not know
about five for the feature and a lot
of people assume that it's for, only
for developers are like, you know,
contributing to the code or, uh, like,
uh, and maybe other ways to contribute.
Right.
So please tell us about.
It can be a part of the
community and contribute in
the five for the feature works.
Meher Bala: So being a part of the
WordPress community doesn't mean you
need to be a developer or you need to
know code, or you need to know, you
know what all, you know, you just need
to know PHP or, uh, any coding, like.
If you are a market out
there, a space for you.
If you are a translator,
there is space for you.
If you're a designer that has space
for you, if you are a community
manager, there is space for you.
There is space for everyone in this
community to five for futures, not only
for sponsored contributors, but for sales,
sales, sponsored contributors as well.
Give.
Some part of your time to the
software, which is helping you on
your bread and butter for some people.
Because when you spend time with the
software, that's because indirectly
the software, if you help the software
grow, you're growing yourself as well.
So that's why five for future helps
and anyone is allowed to join.
Everyone is allowed to join.
Everyone is encouraged to contribute
to different aspects of the community.
If you're hesitant joining the global
community, start with your local
community, start with, you know, if you
don't have a local community building.
There is ways and means
to get people together.
Like nowadays everyone
uses with WordPress.
A lot of non developers use WordPress
has set up this shop, set up the, uh,
websites and all, get them together,
start a local community and encourage
people translate in your own language.
That's the best way to get started.
Lax Mariappan: Great.
A lot of people assume like
they have to be a coder.
Meher Bala: Yes.
Even when I joined the local community,
I felt only coders are required.
And once I joined the community,
that thought went away because
I joined the marketing team.
I have a strong background of coding,
but being a freelancer marketing also
is my, is there in me, so I didn't join
the code, but I joined the marketing.
So, so,
Lax Mariappan: uh, can you hear me now?
Meher Bala: Yes, I can still hear you.
Lax Mariappan: Okay.
Great.
So I have a question.
This is, uh, maybe a difficult one, but
not little controversial, but still,
you know, cause I never felt this one.
So you are also from
India, like from Asia.
So how diverse and inclusive the WordPress
communities are because I I've seen
you are part of communities in your
experiences like 15 plus years with
WordPress and you are part of communities.
Not just a participant.
You are a volunteer, you
are, are a lead organizer.
So what do you think like, is that
any discrimination or the people
are not inclusive in terms of
maybe race, community identity or
whatever language, or I think that
Meher Bala: I have not seen the
inclusive, exclusive as of now.
Yes, though participation
of women is a bit less.
You cannot stay back because of that.
Because when I joined the Mumbai
community, there were hardly any
women, but if you were not going
to be the first woman to step up,
someone needs a familiar face.
Someone needs familiarity in the crowd.
And that's where I think one
needs to take the initiative.
WordPress is welcoming to everyone.
It doesn't discriminate based on
color or gender or any other thing.
It's an open, welcoming community.
I have been welcomed by
people who have never met.
I have interacted with people who
have very down-to-earth people.
It's not that, you know, just because
there are no women or just because,
you know, there are very few moments
where you should not participate.
No.
If there are few women start creating
a group start encouraging woman.
That's how women in WordPress woman
in WP got developed, got created.
Lax Mariappan: Uh, that's
good, like, uh, that will help
inspire other women to join.
Like you pointed out be the first, like
in WordPress, our default comments, right.
Are like, are WordPress.
We will say be the first one to review
something, like be the first one to join.
So that will help.
And it will bring, like, for
example, if Meher joints, maybe
her friends might be interested in.
So it might be like they might be using
WordPress, maybe shy or hesitant to join.
Or then if someone joins there,
they have a familiar face and it
brings more women to the community.
And it's like also I personally like,
um, uh, bringing tech to women, uh, they
can be users and, uh, they can be like,
um, you know, giving the feedback, like
any sorts of contribution is welcome.
And, uh, especially when you
teach a woman, it's like, you're
teaching your whole family that.
So saying in our language,
it's like, you know, cause see
some others, she's a sister.
Like she is going to teach and spread
the word and that's how things work.
Uh, so women who are watching this
Meher Bala: hello
from 2016, till now every WordCamp
I used to go, we used to take out a
group photograph  of all the women.
I think if you go compare each
photograph, you'll see the increase in
the number of women attending WordCamps.
And to me, it is like
you creating a network.
You're creating comfort zone.
You're creating familiar faces.
So yes, women need to be encouraged.
Women need to be.
So I would encourage all the
women out there participate.
If you are hesitant, talk to
someone, there are a lot of known
faces out in the community who
will be happy to talk to you.
If you want to talk to me, you can reach
out to me on Twitter or my website.
I'll be happy to.
Lax Mariappan: Yeah.
And here I would like to highlight
or something that we do for every
WordCamp or meet up in everything.
Cause we have community rules just like
when you join a Facebook group, they
have rules rights or something like that.
So every person who's joining or
participating in the WordPress or any
WordPress event, we have, um, almost
local or international communities.
They have, uh, uh, like any
harassment, violence related or
like anything, something that.
Uh, inappropriate behavior or whatever.
Like you can report that as well.
So it's like, not because of some,
uh, I don't know how to call them.
Like, it don't have to be, uh, or
read or like you don't have to step
away just because of someone bad.
So there are a lot of
good people out there.
So you might get, find your new employer,
new job in, like, there are many good
opportunities that came out of WordPress.
And for me, it's like, I got this, um,
clients and also I met a lot of new
people, friends, and I got me new job.
Also, everything is related because
I know somebody in the community
and I get to know more about them.
I meet them, learn them, learn from them.
So things like.
Meher Bala: Yeah.
Eventually when you're a part of
the community, when you interact
with community, I think slowly
steady, everything falls into place.
But as I said in my talk community, this
two way street, if you only expect the
community to give you every information
and you don't reply, or you don't engage
with people, how would people come to
know that you are a part of the committee?
You also need to make that effort.
I understand people are shy.
Even I was shy.
I'm not going to say no.
The first two meetups, I did not come
in together to anyone, but it was great.
It was, I made an effort to break the
barrier and start talking to people.
I made that effort.
So it is a two way.
Yogesh Londhe: So nice
chatting with you, Meher.
Um, any, any advice you have for,
uh, the WordPress community is a
budding WordPress community is new
WordPress communities to thrive?
Meher Bala: If you're just
started and you're not getting the
people, you're not finding people,
don't lose heart, give it time.
Give it energy because initial stage
of starting is difficult for any group
to go ahead, but don't close heart,
better people who will support you
just keep on building and you will
grow to a very big community even, I
think Yogesh can agree with me with
when he started WordCamp Bangalore
community from a small community.
It became large.
Like when I started WordCamp
Mumbai, I didn't start the
WordCamp Mumbai community.
But when I joined, I heard that the
WordCamp Mumbai community was started
by, two people sharing one big dosa
and today's a very huge community.
So don't lose hope if
you're just getting started.
Yogesh Londhe: I had talking to two south
Indians and we know the magic dosa can do.
Dosa can make anything possible.
Meher Bala: Yeah,
[inaudible] three people.
Yogesh Londhe: Uh, the influence of
south India is not the power, the
soft power, the culture, the style.
Lax?.
Lax Mariappan: Yeah.
So was actually, uh, wondering about,
uh, for example, if I have a local
community, like, I like to say like
WordCamp Chennai or maybe WordPress
Chennai, something like that.
I have a.
Uh, some part of remote village or
somewhere in India or something.
And how can I, uh, connect with what
comes central or like WordPress central
thing, like a local community, how
they can interact with international
community and how, how things go, uh,
like, um, it's going to be difficult or
is it kind of welcoming or how it works
Meher Bala: No, it is welcoming, uh, to
join the international community, come
on slack, coming to community channel.
Put your, uh, credit.
There are a lot of
people who will help you.
There are a lot of people in India who are
there, the international slack as well.
You know, you will get it.
You'll get every help needed,
whether it be local or international,
you'll get every help needed.
So just reach out to people on slack.
Lax Mariappan: So great.
So it was actually nice talking to you.
And when you see Meher's profile
on WordPress, it's like she
got almost all the badges.
That's no
Meher Bala: No, I have
not got all the badges.
Lax Mariappan: Oh, what is missing?
Uh, I'm just curious.
Meher Bala: Lots.
I think design is missing,
Lax Mariappan: but you are a
designer, you are a content person.
Meher Bala: Yeah, that team I still
have to collaborate with, but there are
other teams that I have contributed to,
but it's not the badges only.
It's just contributing and doing
and seeing the software grow.
Lax Mariappan: Yeah.
But it's like a badge, just like a,
we can take it like a recognition
or like something that's like.
Uh, you know, milestone or something
that motivates others like to do.
That's why we, we to gamification.
So that's why we gamify it.
Meher Bala: Partly yes, I agree.
Yes.
Lax Mariappan: Yeah.
Thank we are out of time
Yogesh Londhe: Thank you, Meher.
Thank you very much for a fantastic
session and a very interactive,
uh, uh, discussion at the end.
Meher Bala: Thank you everyone.
Thank you to the entire Big Orange
Heart team organizers volunteers.
Y'all not doing a great
event and sponsors.
Yogesh Londhe: Of course.
Yeah.
Thank you.
So here we go.
Thanking our sponsors.
Meher thank you very much, and
it was fantastic having you here.
So our thanks to sponsors
Bluehost, Cloudways, GoDaddy
Pro, Nexcess, Yoast and Weglot.
Please be sure to visit the
tents and chat with them.
You might even win some prizes.
Don't forget to get your photo snap
at the photo booth and tweet it
out with the hashtag WordFest Live.
Also thank you to our media
partners and micro responses, Lax.
Lax Mariappan: Yeah.
So we talked about the community tent.
So if we go to the community tent on
the, in your minutes, so you can see
Cloudways Cloudways is now having,
uh, with a special guest and they are
having a giveaway event for this hour.
So don't miss it.
Yogesh Londhe: So now we have a
one hour break or I don't know how.
A few minutes.
Lax Mariappan: Yeah.
And then it starts, it goes to Europe now.
I mean, it goes to Africa, Africa.
Yogesh Londhe: Yeah.
So bye from Asia, um, you all
make our Big Orange Heart full.
Lax Mariappan: Yeah, and we, we
appreciate your donations and if
you are not yet donated, consider
donating, so visit our, uh, click
the donate button and be gracious
with your, it helps the community.
And now we all, again, once
again, we thank over organizing.
Uh, volunteers sponsors and
everyone who's participated.
Thank you.