Yoast: Do you know, the Yoast SEO,
plugin, they're red, orange, and
green feedback bullets that help
you optimize your posts for the web.
It runs on millions of websites.
We tried to make SEO understandable
and accessible to everyone.
Nexcess: Oh great.
My website crashed.
I give up.
Don't give up on your dreams.
Jordan, who are you?
It's me.
You from the future.
Your professional website
is not at a breach.
You just need Nexcess.
With Nexcess managed hosting, you
get lightening fast load times
built-in performance monitoring and
updates, and always awesome support.
24 7 365 for all your projects.
Whoa.
Yeah.
Weglot: Discover Weglot the simple
translation solution for your website.
All you have to do is add Weglot to
your website, select the languages
that you need, and that's it.
Your website is now available
in multiple languages
Bluehost: Who says building
an online store has to be
hard with Bluehost website.
It's more than just easy.
It's tell us your thing and
smart AI will take it from there.
Easy it's WooCommerce friendly.
So you can add one, a BS
or swap this for that easy.
It's set up shop in minutes
with unlimited products.
Easy.
Whether you sell boots, books
or bowls, it's create an online
store with Bluehost, easy build
beyond boundaries with Bluehost.
Michelle Frechette: Hello, everybody.
Welcome to WordFest
where you are in Africa.
And I was part of our 24 hours of
celebrating the people, the technology
and the Big Orange Heart of WordPress
WordPress WordFest live is not only
delivers a festival educational
content, wellness sessions and
networking opportunities, but it's
also a fundraiser for Big Orange Heart.
Please visit that donate link at any time.
You'll see it right on the screen there to
support the mission of our organization.
WordFest Live is a 24 hour opportunity for
the WordPress community to come together,
to feel less isolated, learn from one
another and be present with each other.
I am Michelle Frechette.
I am the director of community
engagement at stellar WP.
I'm also the president of the
board at Big Orange Heart.
And so everything that we do here at Big
Orange Heart is very close to my heart.
And, um, I just can't say
enough good things about it.
The work that we do, uh, has touched my
life as much as anybody else's for sure.
And, uh, it's one of the things
that we do to be able to actually
present something like this.
Uh, we started, uh, during the
beginning part of the pandemic,
trying to figure out what.
To reach our community, reduce those
feelings of isolation between us.
And we continue to do that.
Now this is our third iteration
of that, and we're very excited
about the work that we're doing.
Our first speaker up today is Elise Alley.
Uh, her talk is titled measuring success.
How to set your KPIs.
At least Allie is a Texas native
living in Oklahoma and has worked
with WordPress for about 10 years.
Those 10 years have primarily
been spent in support, both as a
support agent and in management.
She's currently a support
manager with stellar WP.
That's where I work.
So we get, uh, working with companies
like the event teams and cadence WP.
In her free time, Elise enjoys
reading, watching her nephews play
soccer and cuddling with her pets.
But before we go to that video, let's
hear a quick message from our sponsors.
And then after that, I'll
have a few messages for you.
Elise Alley: No matter what part of
the business you work in your team has
goals to meet in order to be successful.
It's relatively easy to determine whether
or not you've achieved your goals, but
how do you know you're on the right path?
Hold working towards those goals.
One of the best tools you can use
to measure your success is key
performance indicators or KPIs in
case you are unaware of what they are.
Let's start by defining KPIs..
According to KPI dot org key performance
indicators are critical indicators of
progress toward an intended result.
They help us to determine how we are
doing and what we need to improve upon
and to focus on what matters as Peter
Drucker said, what gets measured gets.
Before you start creating your KPIs.
It's essential to remember that
while they are tied together,
goals, targets, metrics and KPIs
are not all the same things, though.
The terms are sometimes confused.
Uh, The goal is the end toward
which effort is directed.
Whereas KPIs are the effort that
is directed towards the goal.
A, target is a specific
number you were trying to hit.
For instance, if you want to increase your
revenue by 20%, then 20% is your target.
KPIs and metrics are very intertwined.
A metric is a standard of measurement.
Whenever you measure
anything, that is a metric.
Uh, KPI is actually a type of
metric, but one specifically
used to measure performance.
It is also something that has been
defined as necessary or important
Confusing or combining these terms
can create problems as it does
not allow for goals that need to
be measured by more than one KPI
or where the goal is intangible.
So it is better to treat
them as distinct terms.
In situations where the goal is
intangible instead of using a direct
measure, you would use several
indirect measures, which are sometimes
referred to as proxy measures.
For example, say our goal was to
improve employee satisfaction,
a slightly intangible goal.
You would likely need to use several
indirect measures, such as the
results from an employee engagement
survey and the average turnover rate.
You could structure your goal, KPIs
and targets, something like this.
Your first KPI, maybe something like
employees say they are satisfied in
the role sitting at target of 90%.
Another KPI could be something like
employees say they see a long time
future here with the target of 80%.
And your last KPI may be something
like average turnover rate
with a target of less than 5%.
By considering these terms separately,
we aren't forced into deciding.
All at the same time, we
can start off with a goal.
Then use KPIs and targets to pin down
how we are going to define success and
measure our progress towards that goal.
Developing a good KPI takes
time and developing good
targets can take even longer
Goals, however, are comparatively easy to
create because they are just describing
something that you want to happen.
So now that we know what
KPIs are and aren't.
Let's look at what it takes to create
your KPIs, depending on your business team
or role, there are potentially limitless
numbers of KPIs you could choose from.
So choosing the right KPIs
can be a daunting task
to start creating your KPIs.
You will need to start by
creating your goals again while
goals and KPIs are different.
They're not totally separate.
You need to know your goals
in order to create your KPI.
Creating your goals is the what and
the why, what do you want to achieve?
And why do you want achieve that?
You should remember that poor
non-specific goals, make it more
difficult for your colleagues to
set good tactical goals and KPIs.
Once you have set your goals, the
next step is determine how you
were going to reach those goals.
And that is where KPIs come in.
An excellent way to get started
on creating your KPI is to
reverse engineer your goal.
So what makes a good KPI?
The term you'll often hear when
researching KPIs is the acronym SMART,
SMART stands for specific measurable,
attainable, relevant, and time-bound
a good KPI, should be obvious as to
what it is specifically that you were
measuring and why it is important.
It should also be measurable so
that you can determine whether
you were successfully moving
towards your goal or not.
A smart KPI is also attainable.
While it's always good to set high goals.
It is important that it's something that
you can achieve and deliver on because
KPIs are used to achieve your goals.
Obviously they should be
relevant to those goals as well.
Sometimes they are in smart stands
for realistic, instead of relevant.
If you're using that option, you'd
probably ask your self a question, like
is our measure practical and pragmatic?
And it should be time bound, meaning you
have a set deadline to achieve your goal.
At which point you can reevaluate
and create new goals and KPIs.
Well, this is a great starting point.
The smart acronym has been extended
by some from just smart to smart ass.
The smart and smart ass frameworks can
be used when creating goals and KPIs.
The additional three letters for
this method may apply better when
creating goals, but are helpful
when creating KPIs as well.
The additional three letters stand for
adaptable, social, and systems-based,
you should be able to change and
adapt your KPIs and to review them.
If they aren't helping you to reach
your goal, you need to adjust.
You should not be keeping
your KPIs to yourself.
You need to work with others on your team
when creating your KPIs as well as making
sure your team has continued access to
your KPIs, your goals and KPIs should
also fit with your other goals and KPIs
Will failing one of your
goals affect your other goal?
If so, then you need
to make an adjustment.
Be intentional when
you're creating your KPIs.
It is better to have a few meaningful KPIs
rather than a bunch of metrics that are
unimportant or difficult to understand.
You will want to start by
considering direct measurements.
If you want to increase revenue, the
total revenue by month or year would be
an example of a direct measurement, but
some things can't be measured directly.
For example, if you want to
measure something more intangible,
like customer satisfaction.
You could use indirect measures,
such as C-SAT surveys, average
return rate or repurchase rate.
If you're using indirect KPIs,
it is safer to use more than one.
You should also be careful that
you don't use bad proxy measures.
Talk to your team while
you're creating your KPIs.
It is better to work with others,
to create the KPIs than it is to
be halfway through your project.
Only to have someone ask if those
measurements are really effective,
KPIs do not have to be perfect, but
they do need to command the confidence
of everyone who will be using them.
Creating buy-in for your KPIs is time.
You need to invest at the start,
but it's also time well spent.
Again, goals can be used on
multiple levels within your company.
You can have different goals and KPIs
set for your business as a whole.
And then each of the individual teams,
common company goals include revenue,
growth, profit margin increase,
and customer growth and retention.
When you are setting strategic company
goals, you should be able to explain
how that supports the company's mission.
With customer retention.
For example, your goal may be to
maintain a 75% retention rate.
Your target would be 75% and one of
your KPIs might be customer turn rate.
Instead of focusing on overall
company goals, you might be
focusing on your individual team.
When setting goals for your
individual teams, they should
support the overall company strategy
for your customer support team.
You might set a goal as customer
satisfaction or retention for marketing.
It might be increasing organic search
growth for organic search growth.
Your KPIs could include something like
the number of customers you acquire
through organic growth month over month.
So let's take a look at a couple of
examples of smart KPIs for different teams
for your customer service or support team.
You might use KPIs like first
response time resolution rate,
and customer satisfaction ratings
using customer surveys or C-SAP.
For your customer service or support
team, you might use KPIs like first
response, time resolution rate, and
customer satisfaction ratings using
something like customer surveys or SEASET
your project management KPIs might
include things like on time completion,
percentages, milestones on time
percentages and budget variances.
Your marketing team might use KPIs like
new customers, upsell and cross-sell rates
and social media return on investment.
When creating your KPIs, you should
also be aware of two different types
of indicators lagging and leading.
So what's the difference between
lagging and leading indicator.
A lagging indicator
measures past performance.
Whereas a leading indicator is a
predictive measure of future performance.
Generally, we are most interested
in a lagging indicators.
However, if those lagging indicators
take a long time to materialize,
maybe something like revenue per
quarter, then it's a good idea to
track leading indicators as well.
That way you can make
better decisions day-to-day.
To look at a short example.
If you're measuring your cashflow
payments received would be an
example of a lagging indicator.
It measures what has already happened.
Whereas invoices issued would be
an example of a leading indicator
because it measures the cash you are
likely to receive in the near future.
It is only predictive because
it's not guaranteed that everyone
will pay or even pay on time.
A longer-term example of leading and
lagging indicators might be share of
market or share of voice share of market
measures, the percentage of revenue you
were responsible for within the whole
market compared to your competitors.
It's a lagging indicator, whereas
share a voice measures the percentage
of your brands media spend within the
market compared to your competitors.
And the excess share of voice compared to
your share of market is predictive of any
increase share of market in the future.
It's a leading indicator
along with lagging and leading
indicators, you also have qualitative
and quantitative indicators.
Quantitative indicators are
the most straightforward KPIs.
Basically they are measured
solely by a number.
There are two types of quantitative
indicators, continuous and discrete.
Whereas qualitative indicators
are not measured by numbers.
Typically a qualitative KPI
is a characteristic of a
process or business decision.
Again, quantitative KPIs are represented
by numbers and include things like
sales growth, customer lifetime value.
Number of resolve tickets,
customer acquisition costs.
Monthly recurring revenue
and service response time.
Qualitative KPIs, however
are not measured by number.
Therefore they are often thought
of as more difficult to gather.
Some ways to gather the qualitative
KPIs is through customer feedback,
anecdotes, stories, comments,
and responses to surveys.
Beyond leading lagging qualitative and
quantitative indicators, there are a
number of other indicators as well.
There are input indicators which are
used to measure resources needed for
a process or project and includes
things like equipment required.
Process indicators are meant to
measure the performance of a process
and facilitate any necessary changes.
Things like tickets resolved, tickets
opened and resolution times fall under
process indicators as they can tell
you how your support team is doing.
Output indicators, measure the success or
failure of a process, and are probably the
most commonly used KPI type and include
revenue, profits, and new customers.
Practical indicators measure the effect
of a process used by a business and
are typically unique to your business.
Directional indicators look
at trends within your company.
Where are the metrics moving?
Are they improving?
Declining, maintaining.
Actionable indicators measure the
effectiveness in implementing business
changes, including things like processes.
And lastly, financial indicators
measure economic stability,
growth and business viability.
These KPIs are things like gross profit
margin, net profit and asset ratios.
They typically provide the most
straightforward insight into the
financial health of a company, but they
are usually best paired with other KPIs
in order to provide a full picture.
When creating your KPIs, there are a
lot of things you need to make sure
to remember to do, but there are also
some things you want to avoid as well.
The first thing you want to
avoid is bad proxy measures.
As mentioned earlier.
Sometimes there are things we want
to measure, but are either difficult
to measure or are intangible.
In those situations we may
measure a KPI we think is related,
and this is a proxy measure.
It's not bad to use proxy
measures, but it is easy to use
bad ones if you aren't careful.
For instance, an increase in social
media followers does not necessarily
increase positive brand sentiment.
KPIs should be measured by performance,
not activity, making a KPI like post
five social media post, for example, is
measuring activity, but creating a post
with 5,000 impressions is performance.
You want to make sure that you avoid
using weasel words, weasel words are words
that are ambiguous words like effective,
optimize, streamline, and so on.
They make it sound important,
but they aren't measurable and
therefore should be avoided when
creating your KPIs, and your goals.
You also need to make sure you're
sharing your KPIs with your team, as it
tells your team what is important and
should be inspiring them into action.
You also want to make sure you
don't forget to review your KPIs.
Unfortunately, so many people go
through the long and sometimes tedious
process of developing KPIs, but then
don't look at them until the end of
the year or until the project is over.
By tracking KPIs and keeping them
visible, you can continually spark action
and focusing attention of your team.
As mentioned previously, it is very
important to keep your KPIs visible
and to be able to track them easily.
An excellent way to do that
is to use a KPI dashboard.
A KPI dashboard provides management a
platform for monitoring and analyzing.
It allows companies to track the
performance of individuals, departments,
teams, or even the entire company.
Dashboards enable management to see
trends quickly and can be alerted to the
KPIs that have exceeded set thresholds.
You can create your own dashboard or you
can use one of the many existing options
such as Domo, good data and power BI.
You might also already use a platform
that includes this type of dashboard.
For instance, if you're using a support
platform like Zendesk, Salesforce, or
live agent, they all include dashboards.
If you decide to create your
own KPI dashboard, here are a
couple of things to remember.
You want to keep it since.
Limit the number of KPIs to a single
screen for specific objective project
or department overlooking cause
users to miss vital information.
You should show a trend over time
because, for a graph or data to really
be useful, it needs context and history.
You want to tell a story
with your dashboard.
Any graphical interpretation
is best understood if it's
in the context of the story.
Overpowering color schemes
can cause your dashboard to be
illegible, pick a clean and simple
color palette for your dashboard.
When you're creating your dashboard,
you want to keep in mind the
type of dashboard that you need.
Strategic dashboards are mostly used
to view the business as a whole.
They are a great way to see
the company's current status.
Operation dashboards are typically
used by managers and employees
and provide real-time data.
Analytical dashboards are
used for investigation of any
unexpected anomalies and data.
They are sometimes called KPI
reports in our tool to determine
the cause of any fluctuations.
Another step we emphasized not to
skip is reviewing your KPIs regulary.
Click.com has outlined an
excellent KPI iteration process.
First, you want to make sure
you schedule a recurring cycle.
You'll want to create a schedule based on
your own business and your business needs.
When reviewing your KPIs, make sure you're
asking the right questions such as what
trends or changes am I saying, are any
of these KPIs underperforming, and so on.
After you've reviewed and questioned
your current KPIs, the next step is to
make any updates to them and then make
sure everyone knows of the changes.
As we learned today, there are
many types of KPIs you can use.
Because it's a measurement, the natural
assumption is that KPIs should always
be a number, something we can count.
However, evaluation particularly
of service and customer
experience often go beyond.
To get a true, complete picture
of your business, past present,
and future, understanding all
the types of KPIs as essential.
Each one provides valuable insight that
can inform strategic decision-making
and business development.
So when you walk away from
this session today, there are a
couple of things you should know.
First goals, KPIs, targets and
metrics are not all the same thing.
And when creating your KPIs, remember
to start with your goals, keep your
KPIs smart, or maybe even smart
ass, evaluate them often and make
sure to share them with your team.
Thank you for joining me today
to learn more about KPI's.
Dan Maby: How you doing Elise?
Thank you so much for your session today.
Thank you sharing it with us.
Elise Alley: Thank you.
Thank you for having me.
Michelle Frechette: Absolutely.
I, um, I just want to say you
are a smart ass was kick ass.
Absolutely.
I'm just going to check.
I don't think we had any questions come
in from the chat at all, but I know
Dan and I probably have a few for you.
Um, I have the pleasure of getting to
work with Elise and so I've, um, but we
have never talked about, we don't have the
same team and we have not talked about,
um, you know, KPIs and things like that.
But when I hear acronyms like that,
like KPIs and measurements, I know
that there are some people that
those are triggering things, right?
Like it's a scary thing.
When you start to talk about what you're
responsible for those kinds of things.
What are some ways that you
can think of that can kind
of take the stress out of it?
Maybe game-ify it.
Um, and have fun with meeting goals?
Elise Alley: Sure.
Um, it's not something it's
not something, a stressor that
I've really come across before.
If for me, it's, you know, we have a goal.
And so it's the question
of how do we achieve it?
And that's what KPI KPIs are.
So, you know, getting away
from the initials and all of
that, that can be intimidating.
It's just, what do we want to do?
Where do we want to go?
How do we achieve these things?
And, uh, finding ways to do that.
And, you know, so working with our
teams to finding different ways to
complete the things that we need to do.
Michelle Frechette: Yeah,
that makes perfect sense.
Um, what I was working at give WP,
sometimes we would, um, set different
goals to kind of outside of our
normal, regular KPI type structure of
like, let's have a contest to see who
can get the most five star reviews
this month, those kinds of things.
What do you think about using
some of those incentives to
help move the team forward?
Um, and, uh, you know, adding a
little bit of gamification just
to keep things insteresting.
Elise Alley: Sure.
It's always fun when you get a
chance to, to compete with people.
Some of us are more competitive
than others, uh, myself included.
So, um, it never hurts to game-ify things.
We, you know, I work primarily in
support and our goal is always to help
our customers and make them happy.
Um, so we do little things like we
do, you know, make sure that we're
reading positive reviews, not just
for ourselves, but I make sure in
our support meetings that I'm reading
positive reviews from customers.
I, um, my support supervisor sends out
a newsletter every month that has like
positive reviews and that sort of thing.
So, uh, not necessarily gamifying,
but I want to highlight what an
awesome job our team is doing.
Um, And so making sure everyone else
sees that, and they're getting positive
feedback, not just from customers, but
then they hear back from the rest of
the team who doesn't always see what's
going on in support um, but they get to
hear, you know, from our developers and
stuff saying what an awesome job they're
doing as well, when they read those.
Dan Maby: Elise I think the KPIs
are, you know, they're, they're
incredibly important for business
development, business growth, you
know, expansion and, um, you know,
understanding where the business is.
But I think what would your, what
would your thoughts be around, uh, when
you're dealing with a smaller business?
So a solo in a, you know, a solo
business owner and individual that,
uh, maybe a freelancer, I, from
some of the conversations that I've
certainly had with freelancers, you
get into this idea of KPIs and itself
to become a bit, scary, a bit kind of
corporate  do you have any advice for
that kind of, that kind of demographic.
Elise Alley: Um, I think, you know,
it's similar to, to what I said before,
whatever, you know, whether you work for
a larger business or for yourself, you
have some sort of goal, uh, maybe as a
freelancer it's to no longer work for,
you know, this nine to five company and
to go out on your own, um, So, whether you
call that a goal or a dream, or however
you phrase it, that's still a goal, which
means there are action steps that you can
take and can measure to get to that point.
Um, so, you know, maybe it's
having X number of clients.
Um, once I hit this point and I'm
bringing in this amount of money, then I
can walk away from my nine to five job.
Again, no matter what size
company you are on your own or, or
however, it may be, you have goals.
And these KPIs are just
action steps to get there.
Dan Maby: Absolutely I did.
There was a comment coming
from the chat there.
Wouldn't this wouldn't that add
stress to the regular work stress,
Elise Alley: but I'll be honest.
I.
I love where I work.
I have no ambitions to go out on my own.
So, um, that is definitely not an
additional stress I would want to add,
but I do know people that really want
to work for themselves and so sometimes
you've got to balance both of those
stresses and it's not a lot of fun for
awhile, but if it gets you to where
you want to be, then it's worth it.
Dan Maby: Yeah.
I mean, I think the old, then you
can go back to the old kind of
adage of, you know, if you, if
you don't plan, you plan to fail.
Right.
Sort of, and actually know how do you,
as a, as a, as an individual, as a
freelancer or a remote worker that is
maybe potentially isolated and you're
working on their own, um, it can be
quite difficult sometimes getting
out of your own head and how do you.
Work out where the business is
going, or what, what direction do
you want to take your career in?
Um, and I think it all relates
back to what you're talking about
here in terms of the kind of
goal setting and understanding.
Elise Alley: Yes.
And also, you know, I mentioned that, you
know, being social, so with the pandemic
and everything maybe that limits it
some, but whether it's on phone calls or
slack chats or whatever it is, talk about
your goals with somebody else, they can
help you narrow down what that goal is.
They can help you figure out
what those steps need to be.
Um, so don't be afraid to share and
get other people involved, even if
you're working for yourself, you've
got friends and family who are going
to support your dream and can help
you work through the things that
you need to, to accomplish that.
Dan Maby: Absolutely just out of interest.
And they're just another question.
Do you, do you, um, You don't
necessarily do answer this, but
just the question around, do you
set KPIs within your personal life?
Is that something that you apply across?
Elise Alley: I do not.
It is something I, um, when I first
became a support supervisor for I
themes, uh, we didn't really, we
had never had a support supervisor.
We had never had KPIs.
Um, so I was basically, I'd been
with the team for a long time, but it
was basically starting from scratch.
Um, and so.
What are the first things I did was
create goals and KPIs, um, and have
worked with, you know, the other
teams and stuff and helped people
create KPIs and stuff as well.
So it's not something I do
outside of work, but have,
have done quite a bit inside.
Michelle Frechette: Oh, it is
the middle of the night for you.
And we appreciate you coming on
to do a live Q and a with us.
Um, talk.
It was a great talk.
And I think that, um, you know, definitely
is what I'll be glad as on the, um, you
know, at our library of talks for, for
future reference for other people as well.
Great.
Thank you so much, Elise.
I also want to thank
our sponsors Bluehost.
Cloudways GoDaddy Pro Nexcess Yoast,
and WeGlot, uh, be sure to visit
their tents and chat with them.
You might even win some prizes.
There's some, uh, wheels
you can spin for prizes.
I actually won something from
Nexcess, uh, and we work there.
So I don't know how that's gonna
work, but we'll figure it out.
I'll send it over to the photo.
Our photo booth is sponsored by
multicolor lab and dream host.
And those are so much fun.
Dan, you did a great job
building the photo booth out.
I've already tweeted out a
couple of photos of myself.
Um, no Tiara this year.
We also, I think I have one of the other
room, maybe I'll maybe I'll fill it out.
We also want to thank our media
partners and our micro sponsors in the
community tent within the next hour
of Cloudways will have their hourly
giveaway and the special guests activity.
And WeGlot ahead.
Well I'm here, Nando joining
them at their session.
How could you be part of the five
for the future movement right now?
We would love your support.
Dan, tell him there's a button, right?
Where's the button?
Dan Maby: There is a button.
There's a button.
If you're in the my.wordfest.live, hit
the menu on the left-hand side there,
and you'll see the donate now button.
Every single penny goes directly into Big
Orange Heart and enables us to deliver
free wellbeing and mental health support
into the remote working community.
So if you have the ability, please do.
Please do hit that button.
And also please do share that and spread
the word about what we're doing here.
And the word, WordFest is open to all.
So if you've got a colleague, a
friend, somebody who's not, you're
not seeing in the community sent.
I think of a message
Michelle Frechette: drag.
Drag them in the in
it's worth it for sure.
At least I hope you could.
I know it's late, but I hope you
could spend a few minutes in the
community tent saying hello to people.
We will be back on the hour.
We have a little bit of time head over
to the community tent, meet some people.
Um, on the hour we will be doing a
live interview with Topher DeRosia.
One of our organizers.
And, uh, just continuing on after
that with a whole bunch of fun stuff,
including one of our sponsor interviews
with, uh, probably gonna just destroy
his name, but Taco Verdonschot of Yoast.
He'll correct me later if I'm
wrong, but we'll, uh, we'll
see everybody back on the hour.
And again, thank you at
least for being here with us.
Elise Alley: Thank you for having me.
Dan Maby: Thank you Elise.