Yoast: Do you know the Yoast SEO plugin?
They're red, orange, and green
feedback bullets that help you
optimize your posts for the web.
It runs on millions of websites.
We tried to make SEO understandable
and accessible to everyone.
Nexcess: Oh great.
My website crashed.
I give up.
Don't give up on your dreams, Jordan.
Who are you?
It's me.
You from the future.
Your professional website
is not at a breach.
You just need Nexcess with Nexcess
managed hosting you get lightening
fast load times, built-in performance
monitoring and updates, and always awesome
support 24 7 365 for all your projects.
Whoa.
Yeah.
Weglot: Discover Weglot the simple
translation solution for your website.
All you have to do is add Weglot to
your website, select the languages
that you need, and that's it.
Your website is now available
in multiple languages.
Bluehost: Who says building an
online store has to be hard?
With Bluehost website it's more than
just easy, it's tell us your thing and
smart AI we'll take it from there easy.
It's WooCommerce friendly so you can add
one of these or swap this for that easy.
It's set up shop in minutes
with unlimited products easy.
Whether you sell boots, books
or bowls, it's create an online
store with Bluehost, easy build
beyond boundaries with Bluehost.
Michelle Frechette: Hello, and
welcome back to WordFest Live.
Our next speaker is Andrija Radojev
presenting WooCommerce automation, tips
and tricks to save your time and money.
Andrija has worked on various projects in
the field of IT, which include websites,
video games, and information systems.
He's the founder of the video game
studio, thunder strike, which has
received multiple awards at home
and abroad for innovative and
socially responsible projects.
He has been in WordPress
development for six years.
Currently enrolled as technical
website builder at the GoDaddy
WordPress premium support team.
He's empowering business owners
and professionals to get the
most out of their websites.
And you are going to be presenting live.
Welcome.
And how do you pronounce your name?
Because I probably said it wrong.
Andrija Radojev: Andrija, you
actually, you actually sent it through.
Michelle Frechette: Okay.
Very close.
Anyway.
Well welcome.
I'm great.
I'm going to, uh, they're gonna take
me off and let you have the floor.
And then I will come back
and meet with you afterwards.
We'll do some Q and a.
Andrija Radojev: Hey
guys, my name is Andrija.
And uh, now I want to talk with you
about, uh, uh, how we can automate
WooCommerce stores and, uh, use those we
have at our disposal to, uh, to basically
save time and money, uh, doing complex
WooCommerce tasks that we do every day or
to resolve, uh, issues that may come up.
I hope you guys can see my screen.
Okay.
If somebody can't see my
screen, just let me know.
Uh, so let's start shall we?
First of all, uh, this
topic will be, yeah.
Great.
Uh, so this topic will be particularly
interesting, uh, to WooCommerce
store owners and managers.
Uh, however, it is also a very useful
for WooCommerce developers who regularly
work on, uh, improving WooCommerce
stores and, uh, and saying, and,
uh, finding ways to, to improve it.
Uh, if you have ever worked with
WooCommerce as, uh, technology and
the developed the websites then you
probably know that, uh, making certain
that, uh, that the, the process is
most efficient is one of the most
challenging tasks of WooCommerce.
Does this, this lecture, uh,
can be also useful for you.
And of course I will talk
about some depth technologies.
Don't worry, guys.
I'm a developer myself.
I did not forget you guys.
So we're going to have a
variety of topics to talk about.
And, uh, also, uh, you don't
have to actually be uh, current
owner of a WooCommerce store or
working with WooCommerce business.
Everybody who wants to do that,
or to learn something new or
doing basically how WooCommerce
and e-commerce technologies work.
Uh, this actually will be
definitely interesting.
We are going to share some details
on how commerce stores can operate
and, uh, basically, uh, They do that.
You're going to learn something new,
even though, even if you're not directly
involved with WooCommerce or eCommerce.
So, uh, we are talking about to
commerce today, but why WooCommerce?
Uh, that, that is probably the,
uh, first question, uh, new,
new commerce to WooCommerce
would ask why is it so popular?
Why is it a.
Why don't, why don't
we use something else?
Uh, we can have a WooCommerce site and we
want to set up, uh, we can work the site
and we want to set up a WooCommerce store.
Why do we choose WooCommerce instantly?
Uh, are there any other, uh, other
plugins that's similar to WooCommerce
and actually, yes, they are.
However, you can pretty much see
that WooCommerce is a big guy.
Uh, takes most the, of the, uh, market.
And, uh, you also have Ecwid easy
digital downloads, but as you
can see, they're minority here.
So you're mainly going to talk about
WooCommerce, however, uh, the, the
tools I will show to you are, uh, most
of them can be implemented, implemented
on Ecwid or easy digital downloads.
So I'm definitely, uh, so that,
uh, those, uh, E-commerce stores
can be automated that way as well.
Now, uh, we are talking about a
WooCommerce automation, but we
did not answer the main question.
Uh, why should they help me?
They can't have a WooCommerce store.
I earn money from it.
I, uh, I'm, uh, pretty confident about
my business and I'm, uh, definitely,
uh, I'm definitely happy with how it's
going, but why should they help me?
Uh, I'm not like a big company that
needs a major, a majorly solution.
I'm not, uh, I don't have enough
money to pay for it and I'm pretty
happy with this, with my stats.
Why should I help me?
Well, uh, even though if you're not
a big company, if you're a small
business, if you're just starting off,
if you have, uh, if you have a, like,
Just started your business, uh, of,
and you're working for three months
you, you should still automate because
if you have aspirations to grow your
business or, uh, basically just to have
more time to, uh, develop some more
interesting stuff and the basically
invest your time to do something else,
then automation is definitely for you.
And the first topic that
is very important is.
Uh, how much time we do spend, uh,
for updates, you know, a market is
changing prices, changing costs are
changing, and we need to adjust to that.
Uh, our ability to adjust to, uh, To be,
to basically adjust to market changes
mainly depends on how much time do we need
to make changes to our website and, uh,
how, uh, how responsive are we to the,
to the changes, uh, that that can happen.
Uh, that said there are lots
of, uh, things, uh, that.
That can go on.
You can, uh, change your supply.
Uh, you can, uh, you can, uh, find out
that, uh, sometimes it's changed the
overnight and the, that your business
is not so profitable as it used to be.
And you need to adjust to that.
Uh, you, you basically need to ensure
that you're always evolved in your, that
you're always involved, uh, with, with
the market and that, that, uh, That you
can quickly respond to those changes,
having manual, uh, updating, uh, manually
updating the products can be very tricky
and can definitely get to get in your way.
So you're going to definitely
needs to find ways to, uh,
improve or speed up your work.
Also when you see that your website
is working fine on your end, that
does not necessarily mean that that's,
that is the same for your customer.
Uh, and issue detection can definitely
be tricky sometimes, uh, especially
if, uh, the issue only targets specific
devices or specific customers, for
instance, uh, you might be used to,
uh, working on Google Chrome uh, and
using it as your main web browser.
And you're like, okay, I'm using Google
Chrome, it has all the features I have.
However, somebody else in the
road might still be using Edge
browser, even internet Explorer.
In some governments, it is still used.
And if you cannot get to those
customers, if they cannot complete
the purchase, post is the CMA you do
then you're basically losing money.
Uh, identifying those errors and
issues is very important in, uh,
making sure that you are putting
the best of the few business.
Another topic that is, uh, very, uh,
commonly, uh, ignored when you, when
you start to WooCommerce business.
Uh, his lead management, uh, when
you're having, uh, auto, uh, leads that
you need to, uh, to post this somehow
WooCommerce by itself is not enough.
Uh, Having all the information you need
about your customers and your leads
is, uh, probably the key, uh, the key
factor in, uh, managing those customers
and, uh, uh, and the putting the best
out of them out of, uh, to basically,
uh, ensure that they are going to be
engaged gauge within your business.
And, uh, that, uh, you can, uh, for
instance, quickly spot tissues or find
the ways to improve your business, uh,
that needs to be a two-way process.
So basically you have to always
be in touch with your customers
in order to ensure that that, uh,
you're going to receive the correct
feedback for your specific business.
And, uh, one last thing I
already spoke about it, uh, that
is, uh, basically managing...
let's see something is off here.
Oh yeah.
Uh, finally.
Okay.
So basically, uh, You will try to
avoid, uh, manual data transfer at all
costs, whenever you can, because, uh,
eat when you have lots of, uh, lots
of information that you need to enter
that can lead to serious issues, errors
and of course, you're going to spend
lots of time, uh, or, uh, pay lots of
money, uh, hiring employees, that will
that will manage, uh, the post of, uh,
data entry or, uh, uh, data transfer,
uh, which obviously is not, uh, which
is, uh, basically you to the business
post is that is not the most efficient.
That is, uh, pretty much the
time that you don't do not have.
Uh, let's talk about, uh, the first
case of we've mentioned, uh, how does
it affect a specific, uh, business?
Uh, how can we, uh, how can we
basically, uh, how can we, uh, see
how, uh, how can we see that, uh,
that things in, uh, in the world.
He's a real life example, uh, of how that,
uh, that can affect the business meet.
Um, yeah.
Uh, okay.
Meet Mary she's, the website coordinator.
And, uh, as you can see, many
is, uh, working in a furniture.
These are competent.
Uh, of course, you know, if you're
working with furniture, you have
lots of, uh, You need to be a quota.
Uh, you need to, uh, kept connections
with the market to adjust to
changes in prices shipping, uh,
in suppliers, uh, it's attracting
those is I actually can work for a
furniture, uh, uh, uh, sales company.
So basically.
Explains that, that myself
and the, this situation,
obviously Mary is somebody else.
However, I, I had to, I got to experience
this situation in, uh, in real life.
Uh, okay.
So, uh, here's the problem, her company.
Uh, has just found a supplier that
has a cheaper prices and the, of
course, that is going to make them, uh,
competitive, uh, on the market even more.
Uh, they, they, they need
to change their supplier.
And, uh, so, uh, and as, as a direct
consequence of changing supplier, they
also need to adjust their prices and.
If, you know, uh,
adjusted prices, uh, okay.
No big deal.
I can adjust 10 products.
Uh, I don't need automation.
I can type typing myself.
Uh, any changes that they have, uh,
There is not going to be, uh, th there's
not going to be, uh, any, any like
specific, uh, specific issues with that.
And I don't need to really
automate the task if I can, uh,
do it basically in 15 minutes.
However, uh, when you're running, uh,
lots of products and you have lots
of variations for those products,
essentially, uh, WooCommerce treats
those variations and separate
products, uh, not entirely.
But, uh, if you have like, uh,
I'm going to make an example.
If you have chairs that from, uh,
different types of food, obviously the
pricing is not going to be the same.
And, uh, each of those variations have its
own prices uh, that needs to be addressed.
And the once Mary, uh, calculated
how much time will it take to,
uh, implement those changes.
She found out that, uh, she's going
to need at least eight days since,
uh, uh, can stalk has a total of 500
products that need to be adjusted.
If you can multiply that
with variations or let's say.
Uh, a channel that has five
different types of three.
Uh, let's say, uh, we are shipping this,
uh, in, uh, two different sizes and,
uh, also in like five different cars.
So, uh, five times, five times two
equals 50, actually for that prompt
product of chair  she needs, uh, to, uh,
Make changes to 50 profits essentially.
And that, that could be really,
really time consuming and also
extremely boring if you have ever
about, uh, this, uh, business.
Uh, web coordinators are very important
in making sure that those tasks are,
are handled properly and, uh, it is.
For WooCommerce developers.
Uh, one of, uh, key jobs is to secure
that they're doing their, uh, their pro
uh, their process of data entry and, uh,
making sure that the story is flexible
enough to make changes is one of the key
factors of, uh, Uh, basically making sure
that, uh, they're not gonna get, uh, not
gonna have any delays or, uh, issues, uh,
that can, that can pop up in the process.
The big question we need to answer
is how can she get the job done fast?
Eight days is a lot, uh, five
content products is a lot.
If she had like, uh, fivehundred chairs.
Obviously that's going to
be, uh, an overkill, but
that is, uh, 55,000 products.
And obviously that is not humanely
possible even for the eight days,
uh, that, uh, she calculated.
Uh, however, there are some things
that, uh, we can do here to, uh,
ensure that Mary's going to have,
uh, her, uh, process improved.
And one of the things.
Uh, could help her out our bulk edits.
Uh, for bulk editing.
Uh, you can have lots of tools available.
I have only mentioned some of those tools.
So th there is, uh, I think 10 or 15
varied, uh, w WooCommerce, bargains, or
other the way to do, uh, WordPress plugin
that allow you to, to bulk edit products.
Uh, basically what that means instead of.
Opening each product when you need to edit
it, uh, at the opening each variation,
when you need to make edits, you can, uh,
basically, uh, open multiple products and,
uh, edit them, uh, uh, at the same time.
And once you save, save changes or the
changes in pricing for instance will
be saved uh, to all of those products.
So this is one of the, uh, Cubase
you can, uh, use to basically
improve, uh, to improve these poses.
Uh, there is, uh, one another way.
Uh, if you have lots of products and
for instance, uh, supplier sentence,
uh, Excel sheet, you can export to
the Excel sheet in a CSV file, or you
can uh get the next smell file at, uh,
uh, also, uh, export, uh, data in, uh,
in this, uh, form and, uh, input this
data, basically you would replace your
products, uh, one-on-one uh, using, uh,
using the data, uh, this like, uh, this
post is scan, uh, see what's of time.
If you have, uh, if you have a, like
a story that has, uh, more than, uh,
It comes with products, 1000 products.
However, it does come with a, with
some downsides because, uh, there are
limitations as to which data you can
export and how you can import them,
especially when it comes to CSV.
Uh, Handling images just can sometimes
be an issue and, uh, they're the plenty
of factors, uh, that, uh, that can go
wrong with, uh, with, uh, importing
this, uh, This, uh, uh, amount of
products, however, even the, even the
wheat, uh, with those side effects, uh,
if you able to import crucial data like
pricing or, uh, or changes in, uh, but
changes, uh, in, uh, shipping or, uh,
cars, if you have like products that have
different that attributes as well, then.
That can definitely save you lots of time.
And, uh, if anything goes wrong, you
can, uh, basically, and enter those,
uh, the missing information, uh, once
you verified that, uh, everything that
could be, uh, imported can be actually,
uh, is actually imported properly.
Some of the tools you can use, uh,
for, uh, For this, uh, uh, basically,
uh, yeah, that, that is actually
really important for common scan, uh,
can, uh, make those changes directly.
Uh, you, you also have, uh, uh, basically
you have, uh, the default template
system, which can be used to input
WooCommerce products, uh, and, uh, you
would, uh, and then you're presented
with, uh, with, uh, With the system
that to allow you to map fields and to
connect everything that can be connected,
like dicing the names of products,
descriptions, all of the, all the stuff
that would take lots time to enter,
especially if you're starting a new.
VPO in parties.
I go level up to that.
So, uh, about a couple of
products is very similar.
However, uh, there, there are also
many tools that, that you can use,
uh, to, uh, to basically complete,
uh, complete this task and just drop
all the products that you can then
replace them with new products from a,
uh, from a new vendor, for instance.
And also there is a, another cool
feature, uh, that, that you can use.
And, uh, that is to actually sync
products, uh, from a third party.
Uh, for instance, if you're your supplier
is using, uh, Using some third party,
uh, third party technology, uh, for
listing those products and the ha has it
available for, uh, everyone, uh, uh, that
that's, uh, completing, uh, a big, uh,
that is actually working in B2C market.
Then, uh, then, uh, syncing
products, they actually, from that
drink will definitely help you out.
And, uh, There are lots of different
technologies that can, that you can use.
Uh, actually I'm going just to mention
a WooCommerce CPI product thing,
because, uh, it can be useful even
for, uh, the, the smallest, uh, stores.
And I'm going to give you a use case.
You have like a one store that
sells furniture in, for instance,
Dallas, uh, another store that
sells furniture in Houston.
Third store that sells furniture in LA.
And, uh, basically all stores look the
same, but, uh, they, uh, and, and the
show different products from one stock,
however, they have a different pricing,
different marketing, and, uh, basically,
uh, their, their branding is different.
Uh, if you need to, uh, if you need
to, uh, Update changes, uh, uh, or
the one store you need to do that
also for the others, unless you have
a way to actually propagate those
changes directly on our stores.
And these two can really help you
out, uh, automate IO and some things,
more advanced technology center have
a in integration systems to basically
connect you to a third party services?
Uh, I think their, uh, their, uh,
integration library, uh, is, uh, filling
them with lots of, uh, basically the,
the integration library, uh, is expanding
every day and some of them even have
the, the ability to, uh, expand the.
Uh, to basically allow developers to, to
add their own libraries for integration
with which can be really cool and, uh,
can, uh, can save you lots of time.
Essentially this so eliminate the post-its
of, uh, of, uh, basically, uh, trying to
find the different ways of export to give,
just connect to the two technologies and
you don't have to write custom apps to.
Uh, basically to connect,
uh, to connect those two.
And, uh, if you say, uh, if for
instance, supplier changes, prices.
Your, uh, your product pricing
can also change that day.
You can make a, for instance,
if you're, obviously you want
to learn something from that.
So, uh, if you want to, uh,
amplify the price, uh, that, uh,
you can do that automatically.
So basically you have a
mathematic formula, the, to, uh,
do the heavy lifting for you.
Now let's talk about the second issue.
And, uh, that is, uh, the fact that issues
can be really tricky to, uh, to detect.
Here we have Dan.
Dan owns a WooCommerce store and, uh,
he sells, uh, office equipment and,
uh, things are generally going well.
He's not complaining.
He's a very happy how the things
that are going however, after one
year of business, Customer calls and,
uh, uh, his customer says that, uh,
she cannot, uh, add product to cart.
If you had experienced the issue, uh, for
instance, then you add to cart and then
go to the cart page and cart is empty.
Then you know, that it can be really
annoying and, uh, uh, can definitely
dive state the sales of from a website.
Uh, When she speaks with customers
to find out how is it possible?
He finds out that the customer is
using Firefox as their main browser.
Uh, and, uh, obviously, uh, Mo uh, most of
Dan's customers, uh, used Google Chrome.
So he was unaware of the issue
until a customer reported it.
He paid the developer to fix the issue.
And once he did that, the
sales just went up by 15%.
Uh, however, obviously one year is passed.
Uh, so we lost 15% of,
uh, income for one year.
Obviously that's not a simple math,
however, uh, we can definitely see how
a simple issue, uh, basically, uh, a
stupid issue affected the business grade.
Uh, Is there any way we could help
Dan  , uh, prevent this situation?
What could help Dan spot the issue sooner?
And the answer to that question
is basically do whatever you can.
However, don't rely that.
That a specific technology will tell
you everything you need to know.
So if you do not receive animals, so
if you do not, uh, see any, uh, major
changes, uh, do not see any major
changes, uh, to, uh, for instance,
Google analytics results, uh, then,
uh, you might still have an issue.
One of the, the, uh, apps that the top,
the most efficient of, uh, for using,
uh, for improving the overall process
is customer behavior monitoring apps.
Uh, those apps are, uh, are mainly,
uh, Like a specific dashboard in
which you're going to enter and see
all your, uh, customers interactions,
whether it is a quick stream.
Some of those bathrooms also have a
recording features so that you can, uh,
see, uh, what, what customer was seeing at
the, basically it can help you replicate
the error that a customer got, uh,
Basically when we are working on, uh, when
we are working on a WooCommerce stores and
whenever we are carrying the product, we
are, uh, that, that we use, uh, regularly,
we are trying to put, uh, put ourselves
in the equation and think of a customer
as how would I purchase something and.
Sometimes sometimes that, uh, does create,
uh, that, that can create lots of issues.
Uh, and, uh, we cannot, uh, replicate
the purchase process of somebody else.
For instance, uh, we might
be using a trackpad somebody
else might be using a mouse.
Uh, we might, uh, be for instance, a
solo in cooking things while we have some
customers that very fast to complete,
but it just builds this, uh, To complete
purchase process is faster and, uh,
they're used to quick, faster than us.
Uh, they can easily expose issues at
break our websites, uh, does a lot
actually break the websites, but, uh,
they can the PC virus because they
are about using the, our WooCommerce,
uh, application the way it is intended
or the way it is, uh, designed.
However, obviously
customer is always right.
So you need to make sure that you
can handle those, uh, those, uh,
situations and, uh, be prepared
that, uh, your store can work even
in the, this, uh, in this situation.
Another way to, uh, easily spot some
errors is RD error reporting plugins.
Uh, some of the most common error
reporting plugins as he'd be all,
however, you all slowed that, uh, work.
This also has a, uh, reporting that,
uh, obviously can be, uh, can be very
effective if you have, uh, issue that
CA that actually built the website.
However, tracking time, if a
EOC get the Iris notices that.
Something is wrong or that something
is getting deprecated can lead
you to additional information, uh,
that can, uh, that can basically
prevent the issue, uh, before it
happens or, uh, if an issue happens.
You will be the first to know, uh, you
can have, uh, you can have the, uh, L
sock that reported in your dashboard,
or you can receive emails that are
going to, uh, if, if, uh, something
went wrong or some of the crucial
steps, uh, the purchase process.
Also, uh, another cool feature, uh,
another cool tool that you can use,
uh, uptime monitor platforms, uh,
those plugins you probably use the
already, uh, there are lots of them.
Uh, Jetpack also has, uh, also has, uh,
uptime monitoring system integrated.
However, uh, I also used
the, I also listed the.
These, these three platforms that, uh, I
personally had good experience with you,
you may, you might use something else.
Uh, however, when you have, uh, goes
down at the, I'm not going to say if
your website goes down because you know,
uh, that, uh, eventually it is going to
happen, but the question is how, or get
the, uh, how, how well are you prepared
to handle the issue and fix these.
Uh, either the case or you need to be
prepared to, uh, make sure that, uh,
issues popped at the instantly and
that, uh, you're not going to lose sales
because of, uh, uh, because of the issue,
uh, here we have, uh, lead management
difficulties and, uh, We are going
to meet with, uh, I forgot her name.
Oh, mic.
Yeah.
Maggie's a sales manager of a WooCommerce
store that sells office equipment.
Uh, oh, sorry guys, yeah, she, uh, and.
Basically an embarrassing thing happened.
Uh, she, uh, she did make real
checks though, but she noticed
that a checkout is broken.
Something is wrong.
She cannot checkout.
She cannot, uh, for instance,
get access to PayPal.
And, uh, uh, basically, uh, she knows
that, uh, whenever you have a, uh,
issue of this kind you're losing sales.
And she reacted instantly.
I, the developer who fixed the
issue, but, uh, uh, she, uh, noticed
that, uh, 15 sales have been lost,
uh, because 15 customers saw that
he reached to the checkout pages,
according to analytics, and they did
not complete the checkout process.
Now the question we have is.
Was there any way to minimize the
damage from the worst sales and, uh,
there, uh, quite a lot of tools that
are very simple to use don't require
any significant, uh, investments, but,
uh, can definitely save you, uh, or
lots of money if you implement them.
Correct.
First of all, If you have a WooCommerce
store that sells products, uh, then you
also need to have the abandoned cart.
Uh, basically, uh, abandoned cart system,
uh, is, uh, application basically accepts
that is going to capture information that
design to the checkout page, uh, before
the purchase is, uh, has completely.
Uh, if, uh, for instance, that can
capture notably if you have an issue, but
also in the situations where customers,
where there are two, uh, two's your
public and that they change their
mind, the public somewhere else, or
you can invite them shake, uh, yo you,
you still have a product to your cart.
Uh, and, uh, working,
look, utilize this technology.
Uh, we.
Which is very sad because,
uh, the implementation of this
technology, uh, basically costs
installing, uh, overcast park.
Here are some plugins that you can use
there are lots of plugins that the, uh,
made we used, uh, for abandoned cart.
Uh, let's, let's say like this, uh,
this technology is not foolproof.
You still need to have email address
to which, uh, customers will, uh, be
doing to complete the checkout process.
However, if you can arrange your fields
correctly, then you can capture, uh,
capture to the purchase information that
is needed, like, uh, email addresses
or, uh, Th this new information
that is, uh, that can be used to
recover basically those lost sales.
Another, uh, way to spot tissues would
be using a CRM system or, or a similar
solution, uh, for lead management here.
Some of the popular CRM systems at, uh,
I just thought to say those apps a lot
strictly CRM systems, because they have
up of additional integration tools.
Uh, however, what I noticed the
most, uh, is that, uh, having a chat
integration is very important, uh, to.
To basically collect information, uh,
from customers, uh, and to reach out to
them in case of, uh, in case of issues,
uh, therefore, uh, heavy, heavy, the CRM
that collects that, uh, that information.
is the key to, uh, notice
if there are any problems.
And if customer did not have all
the old information, you might have
said, customer, they're just going
to be a web city area and that you
can, the, uh, they actually, uh,
correct this information to customer.
Uh, they talked to him to see if,
uh, uh, to him, for instance, that
the, she is fixing the, that, uh,
he can complete the checkout posts.
Also, uh, you make, have noticed that,
uh, uh, abandoned cart is, uh, uh,
Michael, uh, system for, uh, basically
a bad guy is also my microsystem for,
uh, with the generation, uh, However,
uh, you will, you will sometimes
need to integrate both of them.
So basically both the bad guy in CRM
and the, there are some small events
solutions that you can use here is
called probably some that, uh, I
have personally used Rico forever.
Uh, those two solutions I've heard
very, uh, HubSpot, that guide stack.
I've heard the odds of.
What's useful information, uh, that can
basically help you out and, uh, and,
uh, allow you to manage your reads more
easily at the Cabo deformations about
their bad guides, about, uh, the, uh,
purchase bills that has not been completed
and to know how to handle that properly.
Finally, we go to a
manual date to translate.
And for this case, we're
going to meet Gary.
Gary has a very successful, uh, online
bookstore and the business is going
well, actually, so well that it, that,
uh, it actually is not going well
because, uh, he has two Bob's customers.
Uh, two books are sold.
Uh he's uh, His staff is unable to add
to all the changes and the days lots
of fill station at the KP workers.
Uh, they're, they're leaving their space
because of the stress and, uh, that, uh,
obviously, uh, although he he's, uh, he's
always selling, uh, his, uh, his books.
Uh, he, he's not happy because he's losing
valuable customers that, that can the
w w he's using valuable staff at the.
And the debt can easily cure business.
Uh, even though it is successful though.
And, uh, obviously when you have
a lots of manual work, mistakes
captured in his case, uh, he sold more
books than he has in stock because,
uh, somebody basically had a back
study to add that case to the best.
How can we rectify the.
How can we, uh, actually, uh, prevent
those mistakes and, uh, uh, overall,
uh, how, how else we can save time?
There are a couple of ways I'm not
going to say that these ways are
exclusive or, uh, that, uh, there
are a lot better ways to do that.
Uh, you have a lots of cool
technologies that you can explore.
Uh, first source and the,
the cheapest deepest of the
Mo is to just to emit stock.
There are lots of pockets that you can
use to, to weed stock, uh, and those that
can be done for WooCommerce directly.
Uh, therefore, uh, I would say if you
D if you have lots of stores, then the.
Then you will need more, more events
to solution, uh, that the emitting
stock, therefore you need to, you need
to see, uh, what works the best for
your business and twos to the topic.
So should, uh, other way to
basically remediate the process of.
A manual data entry would
be automatic updates.
Uh, I don't that many, many
companies still use Google
sheets for managing stock.
Uh, at the via Google sheets is very,
very useful as technology, uh, can be
expanded, uh, basically, uh, As much
as it is evolved using Google script,
which is a technology that you can use
to write a script that they're going
to, uh, affect, uh, the , uh, table.
Uh, it is not the most efficient way.
And, uh, if you have all the folders
that that's going to quickly pile up and
become a sole table, that's going to cash.
I know this from.
Uh, if you can automate the process of
entering golden standard, you can, the,
for instance, if you're already using,
uh, uh, ex uh, exosuits, import them to
Google sheets and, uh, you can connect
that directly to have a cover story.
And the once you make change there,
the page is going to propagate.
They actually are used for
another, uh, another system that.
Probably, uh, needs to be spoken
more than, than it already is,
is a stock management system.
Especially if you have multiple
stores, uh, there are lots of,
uh, stock beds with systems.
Some of them are completely feed.
Some of them are paid.
Uh, my personal advice regarding that is
five to what best works for your business.
Start small and then go big.
Now he agreed to talk
about advanced automation.
Uh, and yes, this is where
developers come into play.
Uh, colleagues will probably
staple to be, uh, be customized,
uh, using different technologies.
Well, recovers is a very, very
flexible in that guide has multiple
fixed features, uh, that can be used.
We'll call the subject is, uh, One of
the easy methods to collect the data.
If you're there, they actually, from a
working from a workplace environment.
And for instance, you have a custom
parking that you need to, uh, for
which you need to pull the data.
Uh, we'll cover a subject
is very useful, uh, as.
W, uh, as long as you have a WooCommerce
pocket active, that you can pull the
data that is stored in the object.
A rest API is, uh, probably underused in
the circumstances, but it is, uh, one of
the fastest ways, ways to pull data from.
Uh, what the swept state, uh, if you
have a rest API connection, then you
can make us API requests to, to pull
the data that is, uh, that is needed.
So, so to these data, uh, any way
you want, uh, using, uh, the cusp
of technology, are you using at
the, you you're basically, uh,
you basically see the limits in
the, in terms of, uh, technology.
So Gabby going with you, see you.
Uh, you also can, uh, manage your,
uh, your tasks using, uh, uh, WP, uh,
CRI, which is a, basically a shared
application, which allows you to put
the, if you use the T you know, what
I'm talking about, but it's a shallow
application used to, uh, to automate
some of the tasks and basically to, uh,
Uh, make to, to work with them as if
you're a Linux system administrator.
So if you like command lines that the
school, uh, also, uh, jobs and web
hooks are useful com jobs, because
if you can schedule tasks, you can,
uh, you can, uh, write the contract
that is going to complete that task,
uh, at specific periods of time.
Web hooks are made useful.
If you need to pull data from another
technology, do you need the, basically a
point for which you can, you can do that.
If you're, if you're a specific third
party providers, it has the ability
to, to pull data for vocables that you
may, uh, you may need to use that for.
Uh, other than, uh, the technologist that
they most used, uh, they're also dedicated
to covering cyber is a beta on the
to the official, correct me if
I'm wrong, but, uh, there are
also many more libraries that.
Community, uh, basically councils to
libraries, uh, created by community,
uh, that can also be implemented.
And also as a developer, I always have
to, uh, but if you can, uh, resources
to do that, that if you have, uh,
ways to do that, always create the
custom source called customized.
The customer is the source of that is
going to be best suited for your business.
Uh, and, uh, and, uh, probably the,
the, the fastest way to, to pull data
would be to use the custom source,
uh, that, that you can, the, that you
can modify per your personal needs,
especially if those needs change.
And if you're using a custom solution,
actually not only custom source with the
30 other solution, mind security and the
data protection, uh, because sometimes,
uh, when you, you need, uh, I'm, I'm
actually encouraging you to, to check
your, uh, local legislation to see if
any of the technologies you're using some
colleagues, iwi go in your countries.
In most cases, it's five because the car
is wide spread, especially the webs that
the, uh, that the publicly available.
However, we go advice is a absolute,
absolute must in this case.
And, uh, I just thought to image about
the basics, make sure that you keep your
workers' comp up to date pockets teams.
And, uh, and so that your story is
protected, that, uh, that is secure,
uh, most of Marvel infections that get
the debit, your website are, uh, of
course by a cop that is out of date.
I only to overuse the WooCommerce
pockets that can pile up at that,
uh, that can, uh, Kate performance
issues also make sure that you . Yeah.
Uh, not getting tripped
on your hosting server.
Find the server that is going to, uh,
be able to support all the old you have,
uh, all the world, uh, that, uh, your
customers may, uh, make the eight on it.
Optimize your e-commerce store, uh, use,
uh, tools like geomatics or Google page
page to find the ways to optimize your.
As I already mentioned, the legislation
needs to be top of your mind.
There are some pockets that can also
help you with that as you can see,
but, uh, I do still advise you to,
uh, talk to, uh, your legal advisor at
the, see if you're in compliance that
you have the local, uh, regulations.
And the most important thing, uh, as
somebody who works in the tech supported
to see, I can say that scheduled
backups save lives trust me on my word.
Michelle Frechette: At
least they save websites.
Right?
Dan Maby: Absolutely.
And I'm afraid we were going to,
unfortunately, to wrap up, we
are rapidly running out of time.
Um, did you have a quick two
minutes summary before you, uh,
before we take off your slides.
Andrija Radojev: Yeah.
Yeah.
Uh, actually that is my last slide.
So a lot of our key takeaways, I'm
going to split it up basically.
We're faster time to, uh, try to
find ways to improve the business
process, uh, automate crucial tasks.
Correct.
Quite though deformation, you need to.
Uh, adaptive, uh, social style
preferences, and obviously the resources,
the budget you have start small, uh, that
the go big, uh, and, uh, obviously, uh,
issues and ensure you're is up to date.
My, my final advice is, uh, always
try to think for the future.
And you're going to thank yourself for.
Dan Maby: A great piece
of advice to end on there.
Thank you.
Thank you very much.
Uh, clearly an enormous subject
and obviously a lot that
can be covered across this.
So really appreciate you, uh, giving the
time and bringing that, bringing that
session to us here at WordPress live.
Um, unfortunately,
Michelle Frechette: Okay.
So Maya says that you're going
to be at my essence, you'll be
over in the GoDaddy pro table.
So if people do want to continue the
conversation and have questions for you,
they're going to look for you over there.
We really appreciate the time
that you've given us today.
Andrija Radojev: Thanks guys.
Sorry if I was a bit nervous.
Uh it's like, uh, it does good,
you know, Continuous side that I
wanted to cover lots of topics.
So I apologize if I made something
like a, you know, uh, if something
was not clean, I will be happy to
answer all the questions either book.
Yeah.
Dan Maby: Excellent.
So if you are, if you have, if you
do have questions, head over to
the community tent to jump onto the
GoDaddy pro table, uh, and the can
continue the conversation about.
Michelle Frechette: Absolutely.
In addition to thanking our sponsors, I
do want to just point out other things
happening in the community tent to the
next hour Cloudways has their WP builds
tent takeover with Nathan Wrigley, GoDaddy
Pro are going to be running a panel on the
WooCommerce automation again with Andrija.
And Yoast are running
games with a Yoasters.
We'd love your support.
Hit that donation button, but
it's part of the menu on here.
We'd love to have you be part of the
solution of helping us reduce the feelings
of isolation in a remote community.
And at the top of the hour, which
is rapidly approaching, uh, we are
going to be meeting with Samuel
Femi Taiwa  as he is presenting on
dealing with epilepsy and mental
disorders in the tech space community.