Yoast: Do you know the Yoast SEO plugin?
They're red, orange, and green
feedback bullets that help you
optimize your posts for the web.
It runs on millions of websites.
We tried to make SEO understandable
and accessible to everyone.
Bluehost: Who says building
an online store has to be hard
with Bluehost website builder.
It's more than just easy.
It's tell us your thing in smart AI.
We'll take it from there.
Easy it's WooCommerce friendly.
So you can add one of these
or swap this for that.
It's set up shop in minutes
with unlimited products easy.
Whether you sell boots, books
or bowls, it's create an online
store with Bluehost easy.
Build beyond boundaries with Bluehost.
Nexcess: Oh, great.
My website crashed again.
I give up.
Don't give up on your dreams, Jordan.
Who are you?
It's me.
You from the future.
Your professional website
is not out of reach.
You just need Nexcess with Nexcess
managed hosting you get lightening
fast load times built-in performance
monitoring and updates, and always awesome
support 24 7 365, for all your projects.
Whoa.
Yeah.
Weglot: Discover Weglot  the simple
translation solution for your website.
All you have to do is add Weglot to
your website, select the languages
that you need, and that's it.
Your website is now available
in multiple languages.
Kim Coleman: We're back.
Welcome back everyone.
I hope you had fun in the community tent.
I hope you want some cool stuff.
Um, I'm excited to introduce
our next speaker, Hannah Smith,
presenting how can we make digital
technology more sustainable.
Hannah is a freelance WordPress
developer from the Southwest of the UK
with a background in computer science.
Before freelance life,
amongst other things.
She honed her management skills at
the environment agency where she
managed large business change projects.
She's now co-founder of green tech
Southwest founder of the hashtag
let's green the web campaign
run with climateaction.tech and
a green web foundation fellow.
Aside from helping other technologists
take action on climate change, she also
likes dogs, plants, and snow sports.
Hannah Smith: Fantastic.
Hello, Kim and Lindsey.
Hello, everyone watching.
Lindsey Miller: Welcome Hannah.
Hannah Smith: Thank you.
All right.
Okay.
I have the screens.
I have a few screens in front of me here.
I can see what's going on in my left eye.
My slides are in front of
me, so let's get going.
I'm just going to check my
clicker works and then let's
get talking about today's topic.
Okay.
Great.
Well, thank you to WordFest, um,
for accepting this talk and thank
you so much to all of you that
are here, um, in difficult times.
Um, it's really nice to know that
you have the head space to come
along and learn about how we can make
digital technology more sustainable.
Let me introduce myself.
I'm already had a very nice
introduction so I guess I don't
need to say an awful lot more.
Um, I live in bris.
Uh, I live in the Southwest.
I'm a freelancer who works with
WordPress and I liked dogs.
So if you're not into digital
tech, you can always talk
to me about dogs or plants.
That's absolutely fine.
I run a meetup group in the
Southwest called Greentech Southwest.
Um, I also used to run the
Bristol WordPress meetup.
Um, and as mentioned, I'm a fellow
with the green web foundation too.
And co-organizer of, uh, uh, sorry,
co-founder of an, uh, an online campaign
we did on Twitter called let's green
the web run with climateaction.Tech.
So today's talk.
I'm just going to reset my timer.
There we go.
So today's talk.
What am I going to cover?
Well, the first thing I'm going to talk
about with you all is I'm going to give
you an overview of what sustainability is.
We've all got probably different
ideas of what that word means.
So I'm going to talk about that.
I'm going to talk a little bit about
areas we can focus our efforts on,
particularly for those of us working in
the system with digital technologies.
And all throughout the talk.
My plan is to litter um, talk
with approaches and ideas that you
might find useful to investigate.
I think when you talk about
what something is, it's useful
to talk about what it isn't.
So let's just get that bit
out of the way straight away.
So what this talk isn't I'm not hating on
digital tape, WordPress or the internet.
They bring some significant
possibilities and solutions, um, but
they do have an environmental impact.
So we're going to talk about that.
Um, this is not a masterclass
on the whole topic.
We've got half an hour.
Um, I think you could literally, um, you
know, run a whole week's worth of content
on, on what we're talking about today.
So the idea with my talk is to give
you a food for thought introduction
to kind of get some conversation
started and maybe to get your brain
whirring in a different direction that
perhaps it hasn't worked in before.
And ultimately my goal today is to empower
you with some knowledge that you might
take away, uh, you might choose to, to
use, um, or talk to other people about.
Okay, so that's the intro
let's get to talking about how
do we define sustainability.
Um, so this is how I tend
to think of sustainability.
It's meeting the needs of the present
without compromising the ability of
future generations to meet their needs.
So it's about not taking more today than
those in the future, uh, can sustain it.
It's about taking our fair shares.
Um, and there's three pillars,
uh, with sustainability.
Um,
So I tend to think about these three sort
of facets, which all interconnect and
you definitely can't sort of draw these
very clear, fine lines between them all.
Um, but you can broadly think about
sustainability in three buckets.
If you like.
The environmental considerations, economic
considerations and social considerations.
So that's three areas to think of.
And I think the first thing that I
really wants to get across to you in
this talk is if you're here wanting
to learn about sustainability,
Yeah, as I say, the first thing to
take away is that sustainability is
way more than just carbon emissions.
So a lot of people come to one thing
to make things more sustainable or
wanting to tackle climate change.
And they're very focused on carbon
emissions and that is a fantastic
starting point, but I think it's really
important for us to all understand
that real sustainability is going to
be work across those three sectors.
So carbon emissions falls into
environmental, but we've got economic
and social to think about as well.
So that's my first tip for you
from today's talk is sustainability
is a lot more than just thinking
about carbon emission reductions.
Okay.
What I'm going to do for the rest of
this talk is get into each of those
three pillars and talk about how
those relate to digital technologies.
So let's start off with
environmental pillar.
Um, now I tend to think of this
pillar as natural resources.
And, uh, many, many of you
may be aware of this already.
Many of you may not know this already,
but digital tech does actually
use a lot of natural resources.
First of all, we actually have to power
our digital tech and a lot of that
power still comes from fossil fuels.
And we'll talk about that a
little bit more in a second.
We also have a lot of rare raw
materials in our digital tech,
for example, cobalt and lithium.
Um, both of which do
used in mobile phones.
Lithium is a very important
component in battery.
Digital tech is also using
an increasing amount of land.
Now you might be wondering what,
where where's that land coming from?
Well, data centers are taking up
an increasing amount of land land
that could be used for other things,
of course, and water as well.
A significant amount of water is used in
the production of our digital technology
and also use for example, for cooling,
um, power, um, uh, data centers.
This is not an exhaustive list of all
the ways that digital technologies
use natural resources, but I wanted
just to put across to you that digital
tech uses more than just energy.
There are some other things that
digital tech also consumes as well.
Now, one of the things that we
need to bear in mind is that
the misuse of resources leads to
interconnected ecological problems.
You can see on this diagram that
there are nine points in this circle.
Now these nine points come from, um,
a bunch of academics at the Stockholm
resilience center and they are the
ecological boundaries defined by them.
And these slides will be made
available to you after the talk.
There's links all throughout these slides.
Um, and you can see at the bottom
of this slide, there is a link to
the Stockholm resilience center.
Um, The Stockholm resilience center have
defined these nine ecological services
or nine ecological boundaries within
which our environments, uh, works.
So can you see in the top right there that
we've got kind of, I'm pointing, obviously
you, you can't see what I'm pointing at.
Uh, still not got the hang of
online talks, um, after two years.
Um, so in the, in the sort of what,
just, I don't know, like five past 12
position, you can see climate change.
So climate change is typically where
the consideration of climate emission
falls in, but we have these eight other
points as well, which are all types
of ecological problems and they're
all ecological problems that the
earth is suffering with at the moment.
So again, just coming back to that
point, that sustainability is a lot more
than just thinking about the climate
change ecological problem that's hot
on everybody's lips at the moment.
There are other things to consider.
And it's an ecosystem.
It's complicated.
So an issue in one area will have
knock-on effects in others as well.
So this is why we need to take a
holistic picture and a holistic view
of the intergalactic interconnected,
ecological problems that exist.
Um, so this is, I think this
is a really cool diagram.
I'm really into diagrams.
So maybe this will resonate with some
of you watching, maybe not all of you.
Um, but this is taken again
from the Stockholm resilience.
And what they've done here is they have
rated the severity of these ecological
systems and the sort of taller and
more orange, the, um, the, the segment
that the more we're we're in trouble.
So novel entities, this is academic speak.
It basically means kind of like plastics
and chemicals that are in our ecosystem
that shouldn't really be there.
So you can see, again, that one
sort of it's five past 12, or sort
of between 12 and two that says
novel entities is, is very extreme.
We're in massive trouble there.
Interestingly enough, climate
change, which is just over
to the left, um, is orange.
So we.
Operating outside of the safe space.
And you're also noticed there,
maybe you can see the writing,
it says increasing risk.
And for any of you that are following
climate change news, you might
be aware of the recent IPC report
that came out this week that, um,
painted a rather scary picture as
far as climate change is concerned.
Um, so I wonder whether the Stockholm
resilience center might revise where that
climate change market is in light of.
Anyway, I just wanted to paint
a sort of picture for you of a
wider context of what's going on.
And I really strongly recommend if
you're into this kind of stuff, go
and have a look at the work that
they're doing there, it's fantastic.
But anyway, I want to sort of come
back to the world of digital tech
and anchor some points for you
that that will be relevant to you.
Um, so let's talk about
energy and greenhouse gas
emissions, which includes CO2.
And as I mentioned already,
this is a great starting point.
So if you're new to considering tech
sustainability and new to considering your
place within tech sustainability, this
is a great place to begin your journey,
and we've all got to start somewhere.
So what I don't want this talk to
do is to sort of almost paralyze
you with the enormity of everything.
Just be aware of the wider context
and hone in and start your journey.
And just consider it as entering one
part of one of those nine boundaries.
So w we're talking climate change.
Oh, and it's the point here that
it's worth me just mentioning.
I did talk about greenhouse gas emissions.
So the sub point here is that
greenhouse gas emissions do include
carbon dioxide, but there are some
other, um, types of gases as well that
are contributing to climate change.
You've probably heard about methane, but
there's also nitrous oxide and a couple
of others, which are very long words.
And I'm not going to try and
say right now, but you can read
those at the bottom of the slide.
So let's talk about digital services.
I mentioned already that digital
tech uses natural resources
and does use a lot of energy.
And that energy creates
greenhouse gas emissions.
And it's estimated that ICT, which is
another way of saying digital services.
ICT stands for information
communication technologies.
If you haven't heard that term before,
it's estimated that it creates between
1.2 and 3.9% of greenhouse gas emissions.
So you might be sitting there thinking
I've really no idea if that's a lot
or if that's not, not a, not a lot.
So here's some ways to think about
it, and maybe some ways you may
have already seen this talked about.
So we can think about the greenhouse
gas emissions arising from
tech, as bigger than aviation.
Now, this is often talked about, and it
is a sort of attention grabbing fact,
but I would say, please do consider
how many people have access to flying.
It's about 20% of the global population
versus have access to the internet
and digital services, which is about
60% and also the benefits of each.
So I might argue that digital tech
actually holds a lot more benefits for
people than perhaps taking a flight.
So just to put that into context,
but it is still bigger than aviation.
And if ICT or the digital services
was a country, it would be the
seventh biggest polluter in the world.
So again, just putting
that into context for you.
Um, I mentioned already.
I love diagrams.
Um, so I've popped this in very briefly.
We're not going to spend long on it.
Um, this comes from a fantastic
website called the, our world in
data and it's just there to show you.
Good.
What sectors are creating
greenhouse gas emissions.
Now you won't see digital tech or ICT or
the internet on this diagram, but you will
see aviation and aviation is bottom right.
So it's about what like five o'clock.
And you'll see that that says 1.9%,
but you can see the vast majority of
greenhouse gas emissions are being
caused by the creation and use of energy.
Agriculture and forestry
and land use is about 18%.
So anyway, just again, to
put things into context.
Now the other thing that we should
be aware of with digital tech is that
demand and usage for ICT is on the up.
At the moment we've only got
60% of the world who really
have access to digital services.
So there's that other 40% of the world
hopefully are able to join the rest of us.
We're going to see demand and usage go
up and we're going to see it go up for
all sorts of other reasons as we invent
new things, um, and as we're using
digital services more in our lives,
So again, I just want to put that
growth into some context for you.
Let's just say for argument's sake,
the internet was built in about 1987,
like it's roughly around that time.
Um, you can see that roughly then the,
the amount of global IP traffic was two
terabytes hop on 40 years later to 2017.
And it's 1.1 zettabyte.
If you're wondering how bit a zettabyte
is that a boat is it's that big.
It's got that many zeros at the end of it.
Um, so it's 21 zeros at the end of it.
So it's rather large.
We're a terabytes only got 12.
And the really mad thing is that when
this report was written, um, it was
predicted to grow again in a five-year
period to 4.8 zettabytes per year of,
of data flying around the internet.
Going to take a quick drink.
So that's quite a lot.
Let's move on then.
Lots to talk to you about, hang on.
I'm going to have a little cough.
Sorry, not COVID, but I am
just getting over a nasty cold.
Okay.
So I'm going to very briefly talk to you
about how you might calculate the CO2
emissions of a website that you have.
Now I'm going to do this briefly.
And the idea of this part of the
talk is to give you a flavor and
to send you off, uh, to find some
resources that you, you can look up.
Oh, dear.
I was worried I might get a
bit of a tickle in my throat.
Okay.
Let's talk about the
key considerations then.
If you're trying to calculate
digital carbon emissions, there are
three things for you to consider.
First of all, what device are you using
or what device is your user using?
Where does your energy come from and
how much data is being sent to the user
or being transferred, EG per page load.
So let's talk a little bit about devices.
What devices are you using?
Well, as we've mentioned already,
digital tech uses quite a
lot of rare earth materials.
And I mentioned to you cobalt and lithium.
And one way to think about it
is that manufacturing any device
literally cost the earth it's
has to be made of something.
And the majority of total pollution
from digital devices actually comes from
manufacture, not use, which is still a
very surprising fact for me, but it's
been corroborated by a number of different
places and smartphones are the worst.
Um, and these rare raw materials,
which are hard to find and very
destructive to find and extract and
do affect the communities from which
these things are being extracted are
also very hard to recycle currently.
So this is a cool report.
Uh, the energy and carbon
footprint of the global ICT and
E and M sectors catchy title.
Um, it was written in 2018.
Um, and I just picked out a nice
graphic from there, which shows you.
Um, for some of the main devices that
are manufactured, the gray bar is telling
you basically how much CO2 is embodied
in the manufacturer of that device versus
how much CO2 is, is, is admitted, when
uh, the device used or how much energy
is, is used over the life of that device.
So you can see TVs.
Okay.
TVs do actually generate a lot of
pollution when they're created.
And if you accept that it's kept for
seven years, you can see that the
energy use is really, really high.
So big, big screens, basically
guzzle a lot of energy to run.
Let's hop over to the
right-hand side of that diagram.
Let's have a look at smartphones.
So a smartphone generally will take a
lot less to manufacture, I think we're
looking at what, 70 odd kilograms.
And if you keep it for three
years, the energy consumption is.
Um, is much lower.
So something that we can take away from
this is try and use your phone for perhaps
shopping or watching content or, or doing
things on rather than a very big screen,
because you can see that you'd be using
a significant, less amount of energy.
Something else that I hope we could take
away from looking at a diagram like this
is how important it is to extend the
life of any device that you are lucky
enough to come into the ownership of.
The longer that you are able to keep that
device the less, um, the longer you can
make the, the carbon or the, the carbon
that went into manufacturing the device,
the longer you can make that work for.
So for example, what I'm talking about
is not switch, not replacing your phone
often, not replacing your laptop often.
So how can we reframe
how we value our devices?
Can we reframe to think about
these devices as precious
and not just disposable?
And I encourage you to do that.
Um, I encourage you to think about, do
you really need to upgrade to the latest
device or is it just effective marketing
making you think you need something
faster and bigger and, and flashy.
So, if you're thinking about digital
sustainability, something you can do is
just hold on to your devices for longer.
It's actually a really easy
thing, a really easy action to
do, and it will save you money.
So what's not to love hate?
Um, if perhaps your phone does break or
it does need, uh, to be a bit beefier,
maybe you could repair or upgrade it.
Now I know that that's a little tricky
with phones, but that's becoming more
easy across a whole suite of electronics.
Um, and I encourage you to have a
look at the right to repair movement.
Could you get a refurbed
or secondhand device?
And it is now possible, increasingly
possible to buy ethically made devices.
Now, these ethically made devices
do typically cost a lot more, but
the idea is that you hold onto
them for a lot time, longer time.
So Fairphone, I wonder how many of
you here have heard of Fairphone?
Um, a mobile phone manufacturer.
So, this is a tweet from someone I hold
in very high esteem, a lady called Kate
Raworth, um, who is the originator of
doughnut economics, which we're going to
touch on briefly in, in a few slides time.
Um, and once this tweet, this
tweet is getting on a bit
now actually is from 2020.
Um, but she was talking about
how fair phones are made, the
way that phones should be made.
Um, they're made to be repairable
upgradable, and there the
resources that are put into
them come from ethical sources.
So yeah, we do end up playing, paying a
little bit more for these things, but that
reflects perhaps the true cost to society.
I'm just going to talk very
briefly about e-waste as well.
So I mentioned in a previous slide
that it can be quite tough to recycle,
um, uh, that the resources that go in.
Um, and so what happens is that we just
I'm sure many of you will find that
the same, you don't know what to do
with your electronic waste cables or
laptops or phones, and we throw it away.
And 50 million tons of e-waste
is being produced each year.
And from 2016, that UN estimated that only
20% of that waste is actually recycled.
Um, and the EU parliament estimates
that obsolete cables generate over
51,000 tons of e-waste per year.
And I don't know about you,
but I've got a drawer of cables
I don't know what to do with.
And the key question to consider
is where does our e-waste end up
and who is ultimately paying for
the disposal of that e-waste?
Now this is a photo from an e-waste
recycling facility in Ghana.
It's called ACBL blushy.
It's now been closed down.
And if you're interested in climate
justice this is a fascinating case study
because on the one hand You could argue
that recycling facilities such as this
whilst perhaps not the most technology
technologically advanced do have some
social good because they're giving
people jobs, they're creating a circular
economy, but on the one hand, on the
other hand is unregulated and unsafe.
Um, so there's all sorts
of interesting issues here.
And I've put a few links in the
bottom of these, this slide.
Um,  is a fantastic reporter based in
Africa who has written some incredibly
insightful reporting about ag Bob blushy
and, um, raising the voices of the people
that, that live and exist on that site.
Um, as I say, it's complicated situation.
Worth looking into anyway,
I'm going to move on because I've got
tons of slides and time is ticking.
So let's talk briefly about that second
point where your energy comes from.
So worldwide 63% of the
world's electricity came
from fossil fuels in 2019.
So as a global society, we are still
burning fossil fuels far too readily.
But we should also be aware that
renewable energy is not a panacea,
so creating renewable energy still
requires natural resources and there's
still an issue of what to do with
the solar panels and wind turbines
when they reach their end of life.
But it is less than fossil fuels.
So it's the right
direction to transition to.
However we should be looking to
reduce the overall overall amount
of energy needed by addressing
consumption and efficiency issues.
And then once we've reduced the amount
of energy possible, we want to look
for the energy with the lowest impact,
which at this time is renewable energy.
This is a cool fact.
Apparently 80% is the amounts if
everyone in the ICT sector used
renewable energy, we could reduce the
car, the sector's footprint by 80%.
So that is a massive,
massive, uh, motivator to, um,
Switch to renewable energy.
So here we go.
Here's something that all of us
listening to this talk, all of our
colleagues can do is look for hosting
that runs on renewable energy.
It makes a big difference.
And the green web foundation, which I
do a lot of work with is a fantastic
resource for understanding what energy
sources, hosts, and servers are using.
And we've got plans to really expand
that data set and provide a lot more
information and cover a lot more than
hosts and servers so watch this space.
Another thing, if you're sort of a
bit more technical, perhaps you are
choosing a data center to work with,
um, also consider the PUE, which
is the power usage effectiveness.
And that basically determines how much and
how energy efficient the data center is.
So if it's 1.2, it's
considered very efficient.
So just a little bit for
you to think about there.
I'm going to move on to talk about
how much data are you sending.
So there's a third one.
So data transfer equals
energy consumption.
So we, if, well, I say we as developers,
I'm sure that many of you listening,
won't be developers you'll have other
roles as well, but for those of us
who are developers, something that
we can do is reduce the amount of
stuff, loading every single time a
page, um, is, um, is, is requested.
So this is yet another reason to
care ever so greatly about web
performance and optimization.
We know we should care about this stuff,
but sometimes it's easy not to, especially
if you're lucky enough to live in a
Western country with a fast broadband
connection, but not only should we
care about making services accessible.
We also have a climate change reason.
The more efficient our tech
is the less energy it uses.
And the better that is for the planet.
And the sustainable web design
has a great write-up about this.
And I've added some really
useful measurement tools at the
end of this slide pack as well.
So I'm going to rattle through a few tips
for you, how you can reduce data transfer,
sorts of things that you can think about.
So if you are a developer, How
about creating and storing the
data that you actually need.
So perhaps reduce backups
and archives and logs.
Not saying don't have them, but
maybe go back and think, do I really
need these logs from 12 years ago?
Reduce analytics, data.
Google analytics is very, very heavy.
And I would argue that Google analytics,
depending on the size of your site,
but Google analytics probably shouldn't
be your default choice for analytics
because of the amount of cruft it loads.
And also remove plugins and
any third party services that
we no longer written need.
Transfer media content on demand.
So ditch auto play videos,
they consume a lot of energy
because they run immediately.
And while there's lots of evidence
to say users don't like them
and lazy load images and video.
Other things you can do, especially
if you're a content editor is pay
attention to images, use the right
image format for the right type.
Compress and optimized JPEGs, and
display images of the right dimensions.
So don't have a 2000 pixel image in a 1000
pixel space, just load in the 1000 pixel
image when you're creating the content.
And do have a look at things like image
source set or the picture tags, which are
HTML tags, which really help you to serve
images responsibly and WordPress has some
helper functions as well that can help you
with installing, uh, with making use of.
Update the latest, the latest version
of PHP and WordPress, and as mentioned
disabled and needed code plugins and
dequeue scripts you don't need that.
It's basically a whistle-stop tour of
what Tom Greenwood has talked about
in his book, sustainable web design.
Now.
If you recall at the beginning of the
talk, I said that there were three
pillars to deal with sustainability.
We focused nearly all of our time
on today's talk, talking about the
environmental pillars, but I do want
to just briefly touch on the social and
economic ones as well, because the thing
is that making things more efficient,
doesn't always decrease consumption.
So actually there's a lot of research
that says that it can actually
increase usage because we make it
easier for people to use things.
So making our websites more efficient is
a very worthwhile thing to do, but it's
not the only thing we need to be doing.
We need to be asking
some bigger questions.
And if you're interested in this
concept that I've just talked about,
have a look at Jevons paradox.
So this leads us into why we
need to think about economics.
And a brief definition of economics
is it's a social science that studies
the site it's oh, I put science
twice in there, a social science that
studies the science of production,
distribution and consumption of wealth.
And it's basically the bit that
dues the other two pillars together.
And it is also a way of articulating
the systems, the decision-making
systems that we exist with.
Now I mentioned one of my absolute
heroes, Kate Raworth earlier, if you're
interested in this kind of thing, do you
have a look at donut economics, her book,
and there's also a fantastic website
called the doughnut economics action lab,
which I spend a lot of time on as well.
It's full of really interesting resources
about the wider questions we should be
asking about the systems that we exist.
Um, and also if you're really interested
in this, I'd highly recommend a book
called less is more by Jason Hickle,
which is actually suggesting that I
would desire to grow, grow, grow, needs
to be an inhabited if we're really going
to seriously tackle climate change.
And I bring that up here because I
do think that within the tech sector,
we are still a little bit beholden
to this idea of growing all the time.
More, features, more sites,
more clients, more, more, more.
And I think that this is a very
interesting concept to think of.
Okay, I've got a few more
slides and then we'll be done.
Um, so apologies to the, um, facilitators.
I might run over by a minute or two.
Um, social change.
Oh, so this pillar I wanted just to
make relevant to us as tech makers.
So those of us who are creating
digital services or are somehow
involved in the creation.
Now we need to change the way that we
are working if we want to make tech
more sustainable, if we want there
to be the same opportunities for
future generations that we have today.
We need to ask some
questions of ourselves.
We need to ask what do we create tech?
So I think of tech websites,
digital services are simply
an accelerator of solutions.
Intrinsically my personal belief is
that I don't think tech is good or bad.
It is a bit bad when it's used wastefully
is, as I talked about in my previous
slides, but on balance, essentially,
it just accelerates solutions.
So we have to ask ourselves, well, which
solutions are we choosing to accelerate?
Who are we choosing to lift up?
And most importantly, who is benefiting
from what we're accelerating?
Who benefits from these solutions?
Who's standing to lose out
from what we're creating?
Whose needs are we ignoring?
Who has the decision-making power?
And I think within the WordPress
community, that's a really
interesting question at the moment.
Um, more.
I was getting Morton's full name,
wrong Morten Rand-Hendriksen.
I'm sure y'all know who, I mean has
just done a really interesting podcast
with WP Tavern talking about this.
So I think this is an issue
within our own community that
we could be addressing as well.
And who feels the
burdens of our decisions.
So, what I want to say to you is that
if you're interested in sustainability,
you are going to, by default, end up
going down a road of realizing that
climate justice equals social justice.
And you're going to realize that
social issues are completely wrapped
up in making things more sustainable.
So it's a core concept of climate
justice to think about social justice.
And as I mentioned before, it may
be difficult doing these things
because we exist within systems
that don't make it easy for us.
So we have to think beyond current
paradigms that we're in and you
might hear the phrase system
change, not climate change.
And that's what that means.
It means that the systems that are
making the decisions around us are
not fit for purpose at the moment.
They don't allow us to tackle
social injustice in the world.
Okay, I'm going to skip this slide.
That's a terribly scary diagram.
So as technologists, we need to
challenge how we think and behave as
individuals as well as challenging
the systems we exist within.
So summing up, this is a diagram
I've been working on recently.
Two highlights what it means to
build a sustainable internet.
Um, a lot of people may have come to
this talk, expecting my talk to talk
loads about efficient tech and renewable
energy and maybe even buying offsets.
So the stuff on the left-hand
side of the diagram.
But actually, if we're interested in
sustainable internet or in sustainable
digital services, there's a whole
myriad of interrelated, social and
economic factors that we need to
think about as well as efficient
tech and using renewable energy.
And again, I just want to stress to
you if you're new to this journey.
Because it is a journey
and it's a journey.
We're all going to have to go on.
If you're new to this and your starting
steps are to make the tech that you're
using more efficient, then good for you.
That's a fantastic thing to be doing.
Once you've done that and you're ready
to move on there's a myriad of other
things that you can put your time and
energy into that will make a difference.
And of course, there's
lots of co-benefits.
So improving the sustainability of
digital services creates all sorts
of lovely side benefits to humans and
the planet we can reduce resource use,
improve accessibility in UX, improve
performance and speed, and ultimately
make us more fulfilled and happier
humans, which is good for everyone.
It's good for the social good.
So there's lots and lots
of reasons to do this.
Um, and I look forward to hearing
any questions, any reactions to what
I've talked about today and hopefully
meeting some of you in the communities
that are seeking to make these kinds
of changes for everybody's good.
So, thank you very much.
That's the end of my talk.
Thank you for bearing with me
and apologies to the organizers
for running a few minutes over.
Um, my slides will have been
published on Twitter by now.
So my handle is hanopcan, so
you can find the slides there
and there's loads more to go.
There's all these sort of resources that
I've put at the end for you as well.
So you can have a look through
those and kind of go on a really
fantastic journey of discovery.
Thank you very much.
Kim Coleman: Thank you so much, Hannah.
Lindsey Miller: Great Hannah.
Yep.
We're both excited way to go.
That was really awesome.
Hannah Smith: Good.
Good.
Okay.
I'm just going to stop sharing my
screen a second and I can come back
to you and like look at you square on
because otherwise you're on my profile.
I'm a big Roman nose right.
There we go.
Hello Kim and Lindsey.
Kim Coleman: Awesome.
I'm going to kick off the questioning
with just kind of a background.
How did you personally get invested
and involved in this topic and the
topics in general that you presented?
Hannah Smith: Yeah.
I mean, I've always been really
interested in environmental
issues ever since a little kid.
Um, I worked for the environment
agency is, as you mentioned in my
intro, um, and then about two and
a half years ago, I went to word
camp Europe in Berlin and heard Jack
Lennox give a talk at WordCamp Europe
about making websites more efficient.
And I'd been thinking for quite
some time, I didn't think that
the WordPress community had been
doing enough around sustainability.
I wasn't hearing enough conversations.
Um, so love to hear Jack's talk,
Jack and I, and our good friends.
We've been working on a
few projects together.
But it was that, and the work of whole
grain digital that really made me realize,
Hey, they're all people in the WordPress
community who are talking about this.
Um, and you know, there's hope for us.
We can, we can do this.
Um, so yeah, so it was sort
of other community members
really that, that kind of.
Really pushed me on this direction.
And then I've sort of been finding
my own path, um, since then as well.
Lindsey Miller: Absolutely.
I see that you're not alone.
Oh, sorry.
We're not good at this.
I know they have so many things to
say, like, Hannah, I was slacking
Kim, as you were talking, like, I just
felt like my jaw dropping through so
much of your talk and I can't wait
to download the slides on Twitter.
Um, cause it really was
absolutely fascinating.
And as you mentioned, there are other
people in the community that are
interested in leaning into this area.
Um, but I haven't seen it presented
in quite the way that you had.
So, um, thank you for that.
Hannah Smith: Um,
Lindsey Miller: no, it was really good.
Um, at least, I mean, even as I was paying
attention and wanting to like learn more,
so, um, Um, so I have a question from
from the chat she asks, does recycling
e-waste with our, does recycling the
waste also increase the CO2 and if so,
what is the best way to dispose of it?
Hannah Smith: Oh, that's
such a good question.
And thank you for asking that.
Um, there's no easy answer.
So, so recycling something.
Any kind of e-waste, as I mentioned,
e-waste will, um, contain these
rare raw materials that are hard
to find and extracting those from
the earth and producing them in the
first place is crazy, crazy, bad.
Like it's not good.
So any way that you can find to
recycle or reuse those things.
It's definitely going to be better for
carbon emissions, because if we were to
extract the same amount of resources,
again, that's going to be way more
policing than recycling and reusing.
The second part of the
question is to how we recycle.
Well, that's not easy.
There are some companies that now allow
you to send electronics back to them.
Um, certainly the bigger manufacturers.
Depending on where in the world you live,
maybe you have a local council that's good
enough to accept those resources for you.
But honestly, there's no easy answer
and it's kind of the tragedy of,
of a lot of this that we, we don't
know, and we're producing all this
stuff and it just goes into landfill.
So, um, it was so [audience name],
I think that asked the question.
I'm sorry that I can't give you like
an awesome answer because I don't think
there is one, um, just consume less
buy secondhand if you possibly can
and reuse what you can, you know, if
you've got that big drawer of cables
or that big drawer of stuff, see if
you can donate it to somebody else to
a local school or a community group
that that maybe could make use of it.
It's a great question.
Thank you for asking it.
Lindsey Miller: It may not have an
easy answer, but that's the point of
having this conversation, I think right?
Is continuing to bring this topic
up, um, until we do have answers.
Um, so anyway, just wanted
to throw that out there.
Um, what's our next question.
Kim Coleman: Oh, great.
I was just going to add my
son at their school they have
an interesting wall hanging.
That's a weaving and there's
kids brought in found objects and
they included an old keyboard.
And I think like a computer
mouse, some interesting things.
So while we won't all make art out of
our unused cables, it's an option and
something that kids are even seeing, you
know, as beautiful and, and recreate.
So cool thanks.
Um, add this question from Fahim,
uh, what are some alternatives to
Google analytics you mentioned, um,
that it may not be needed and it's
kind of a heavy load on a site.
Do you have some preferences
you can recommend?
Hannah Smith: Absolutely.
I do.
Thank you for the question Fahim.
I wanted to put it in my talk, but
there was so much to talk through so I'm
glad that we can talk about this now.
Um, A couple of options.
There's plausible analytics
and fathom analytics.
Now I believe that both are paid for
services, but the thing is with Google,
like they are giving us stuff for
free, but it's not free to society.
Somebody somewhere is paying for that
society as a whole is paying for.
Now that's a real moral thing.
Um, It's not always something that a small
startup or a small charity wants to hear.
Um, so a free option at the
moment is called cabin analytics.
I love cabin analytics, their
analytics loads in like, I think
it's less than two kilobits.
Whereas I think Google analytics
is like somewhere between 60 and
80, like massive, big difference.
Um, so having a look at a cabin
now they're in beta at the moment,
which is why the service is free.
If you get in there quickly, and then an
open source option is  matoma analytics.
I think I've said that, right?
My tone, my Toma Miitomo it's either
an OER and a at the end, their
analytics is entirely open source.
So you can actually run that
yourself, but it requires a lot
more effort than Google analytics.
So if you're techie, you might get
on well with Miitomo Metova I hope
somebody will correct me on which it is.
Um, I think they do also offer
a subscription as a service
type type thing as well.
So there are options out there and
within the WordPress community as well.
There's one more that I should mention,
which is Koko analytics, which is a
free plugin, um, written by the same
guy that does the main MailChimp plugin.
Ah, his name's gone out
of my head at the moment.
I remember on my drive home.
I'm sure.
Probably have a look at Koko analytics.
If you just want simple information
about page loads, Koko is a really
great choice, but you need something
more in depth than more complex.
You're probably looking
at plausible or fathom.
I mentioned that at the beginning.
Lindsey Miller: Perfect.
Thank you so much for
answering that for us.
There's a lot of you mentioned,
I hadn't heard of any of those
analytics programs, so, um, thank you.
I will definitely be
Googling them afterwards.
Hannah Smith: Um, and we'll do.
Uh, just say Lindsey on that point
as well, that not only have a
more efficient programs to use,
but they also care a little more
about privacy as well in Google.
So for those of us, and, you know,
in Europe, thinking about things
like GDPR, we're being pushed a bit
more in that direction, but there
is that added benefit of privacy.
Um, better privacy, um, handling as well.
Anyway, we could like do analytics.
Lindsey Miller: We could, and the
WordPress person is Danny Van Kooten.
You're welcome.
Kim Coleman: Yeah.
And I'm going to close that tab
down so that I'm not loading
any anymore on that tab.
Like Googled it.
And I closed it.
Lindsey Miller: Which gets us into the
next question, which is how do we begin
talking about this with our teams, our
colleagues, and anyone else, especially as
we're talking about really changing entire
workflows and what people are used to.
So what are your suggestions, um,
to approach those conversations?
Hannah Smith: I think that's
an excellent conversation.
And I think one of the key
things that I've learnt is that.
Often, if you just talk about
sustainability for sustainability
sake, you'll only get a very small
amount of people that are really
interested in making a difference.
But if you talk about it as
sustainability plus performance,
plus cost-saving plus making it more
accessible plus improving the UX.
If you talk about it in all of
those ways, you are far more
likely for people to go, right?
Yeah.
So basically we just need
to kind of do better.
And I find that that's a really great
way to get the conversation going.
I didn't get time to really talk about
all the tools, which is a shame, but
there's a fantastic tool called website
carbon calculator, websitecarbon.com.
And the creator of that Tom Greenwood
was giving a talk this morning.
Maybe it came up in Tom's talk.
I bet it did.
Um, a really fun thing that you can
do as a team is just put your website
in that tool and it will tell you what
the carbon emissions are of that site.
And again, I think like when I've tried
to engage people in the topic for the very
first time using that little measurement
tool is great because it tells you not
only does it give you a number, but
it tells you how good or bad your site
is compared to the rest of the world.
And it's green, if you do well, and
it's red, if you're not doing so good
and, and people often go, oh my gosh,
like we had no idea it was this bad.
Um, and that can galvanize a bit
of motivation and action as well.
Lindsey Miller: Yeah, it reminds
me of, um, there's a WordPress
agency in Texas called cause
labs that Cheryl Gillihan owns.
And I wonder if.
She and others, like her could make that
part of their process, even with our
clients is like in the, um, discovery
phase or the pitch phase of saying
we ran it through this calculator
because that therapy court right.
And so.
That's what they're, um, part
of their mission is focused on.
And so adding that as part of your,
um, space could be really interesting.
So thanks for sharing that.
Hannah Smith: An absolute pleasure.
And the other thing that website
carbon calculator have as well
as a little badge that you can
put in the footer of your site.
And we'll give you, um, a
carbon emission in the footer
for each single page as well.
So is ongoing measurement.
That can be quite useful too.
And just making sure.
Um, yeah, your emissions, are you
keeping an eye on, but yeah, I love
the idea of including, including it in
the delivery, in the discovery phase.
I think that's a great suggestion.
Kim Coleman: Awesome.
We might have time for one or two more.
So I'm going to throw this one in,
um, since we're all more working
remote these days, have you seen any
positive or negative impact on the
sustainability and digital technology
as we've moved to working from our
independent homes and environments?
Hannah Smith: Hmm.
That's a really great question.
And I don't think anybody's
really asked me that before.
Um, I do wonder whether we have
started to question how much
digital technology is in our lives.
Certainly for my own experience in lock
down, I existed entirely in the digital
arena, as I'm sure many of you did.
It's the only way I was talking
to people and the only way I
was speaking with my clients.
So I wonder perhaps whether there's been
a bit more of a wake up of gosh, you know,
digital technology everywhere in our life.
And certainly we're having more
conversations and, you know, Big Orange
Heart are having those conversations as
well about mental health and the impacts
of digital technology on mental health.
Mental health does have
a link to sustainability.
You know, I was talking
about these social issues.
It may not be like a really like
obvious, strong link, but there
is a relationship there as well.
So I mean, Beyond that I, I
couldn't really say whether I'd
seen a sort of specifically.
Um, specific spin one way or the other,
but it's an excellent question and one
I'll have a little think on, um, might
pop back up with a blog post on that.
Kim Coleman: And if you love to read
that, I would love to read that.
I think a lot of people during the
pandemic, while they did absorb
themselves in more technology,
I think they found these like
non-tech hobbies that they nurtured.
And, um, I've seen more
conversations about that stuff then
bingeing, Netflix every day, so.
Hannah Smith: Oh, good.
Well, that's good for everyone.
I think.
Lindsey Miller: Well, awesome.
I think we're out of time.
Um, Hannah, thank you so much
for your presentation today and
answering all of our questions.
Um, and we'll continue the
conversation on Twitter.
Hannah Smith: Excellent.
I hope so.
Tap me up.
If you want to chat any more about surf,
if you want advice on things I'm always
happy to share, um, and always happy to
strike up conversations with people too.
This is an important topic.
So, you know, let's chat as a
community and, and, and make some
moves in the right direction.
Lindsey Miller: Yep.
Perfect.
Thank you so much.
Thanks.
Okay.
We want to make sure that.
And tell our sponsors.
Thank you one more time.
So that is thank you.
A big thank you to BlueHost Cloudways
GoDaddy Pro Nexcess Yoast and Weglot.
And please be sure to visit their
tents and chat with them, and you
may even win some prizes and also
get your photo snapped and the photo.
It's sponsored by multi
collab and DreamHost.
And don't forget when you take your
picture to tweet it out with the
hashtag #WordFestLive, and also a
big thank you to all of our media
partners and micro sponsors that
are helping put this on today.
Kim Coleman: We're going
to take a short break.
Um, we'll be back at the top
of the hour, but you can head
over to the community tent.
Um, for the next hour, you'll be able
to meet with Cloudways and have their
QBO tent takeover with Elena QBO.
GoDaddy pro are running a
panel on web security with
Nestor and Gullo  and guests.
Uh, you can join Nexcess, uh, with a
chance to win a mystery prize and Yoast
are also running games with your sisters.
Uh, thank you so much.
Enjoy the break.
We'll see you in a bit.
You make our Big Orange Hearts full.