Nexcess: Oh, great.
My website crashed again.
I give up.
Don't give up on your dreams, Jordan.
Who are you?
It's me.
You from the future.
Your professional website
is not out of reach.
You just need Nexcess.
With Nexcess managed hosting, you
get lightening fast load times
built-in performance monitoring and
updates, and always awesome support.
24 7 365.
For all your plans.
Whoa.
Yeah.
Weglot: Discover Weglot the simple
translation solution for your website.
All you have to do is add Weglot to
your website, select the languages
that you need, and that's it.
Your website is now available
in multiple languages.
Yoast: Do you know, the Yoast SEO,
plugin, they're red, orange, and
green feedback bullets that help
you optimize your posts for the web.
It runs on millions of websites.
We try to make SEO understandable
and accessible to everyone.
Bluehost: Who says building an
online store has to be hard?
With Bluehost website builder
it's more than just easy.
It's tell us your thing in smart
AI we'll take it from there easy.
It's WooCommerce friendly so you can add
one of these or swap this for that easy.
It's set up shop in minutes
with unlimited products easy.
Whether you sell boots, books
or bowls, it's create an online
store with Bluehost easy.
Build beyond boundaries with Bluehost.
Cathy Tibbles: Welcome back.
Next we welcome Karen Tompkins with
move on, dealing with anxiety and anger.
When Karen's first child was born,
she stopped breathing due to a
rare disorder, affecting her brain.
It became Karen's and mission to learn
all things neuroscience in order to help
her daughter reach her full potential.
Drawing on her 30 plus years experience
as a teacher, administrator and
curriculum developer, she then taught
thousands of students, educators, and
parents, to understand the power of
their narrow chemistry and how it drives
behaviors due to anxiety and anger.
She shares simple but effective
techniques to trick your brain to move
on past these intrusive behaviors.
Karan Tompkins: Hello.
I'm glad you're here.
And, uh, without further
ado, I am Karen Tompkins.
I'm just going to get my slide deck
rolling and we'll get started and
we have a good 45 minutes together.
Uh, the last five we will try
and, uh, reserver for Q and A.
All right.
So, um, I would like to take
this opportunity to thank the
organizers for having me here today.
I'm honored to be able to share my
experiences with you and thankful.
Yeah, just kidding.
It's so not going to be like that at all.
Now I can't see or hear any of you.
So I'm just going to assume that you are
laughing because I thought it was funny.
Some of you just in those 20 seconds may
have thought I need to get out of here.
Or this is crazy.
I'm not staying here for this.
Um, or you just felt really uncomfortable
and that's an anxiety, anger response.
When the fright flight fight response
kicks in because their stress
that suddenly you have to take
care of and it happens like that.
So that's what we're going to talk
about today is how that happens.
Um, and then a few things that
we can do to offset those.
Things that happen to you.
So at this point, it's important that
we identify our baseline behaviors.
And what I mean by that is what
is it that you do or your body
does, um, and when this happens,
you know, I'm really stressed.
I am on the edge.
For example, for me, I eat a lot
of cookies, so, you know, I kind of
get through a half a bag of cookies
and I go, yep it's a bad day.
Um, maybe you chew your fingernails,
you snap at your partner
or, um, you have indigenous.
Issues, irritable bowel
syndrome, things like that.
Uh, we'll learn later in, in our time
together that your gut is directly
attached to the neurochemistry
that drives your behavior in
an anxiety, anger response.
So we're going to talk about that.
So think about the one or two things
that happen for you and you know,
that, that means that you're stressed.
And I'd like you to
actually jot that down.
If you have something to write
on or, you know, memo in your
phone or something like that.
Uh, because we're going to come back
to that in about 40 minutes time.
And indeed, I'd like you to take a
look at it again in about three months.
Okay.
So writing it down would
be very helpful for them.
All right.
So, um, I am a speaker cause I'm
speaking an author, I'm an educator.
Um, if you want to know more
about my credentials and why I
think I maybe know something.
Hop over to my website.
ktomkins.com and there's a lot there.
You can email me if
you have any questions.
I have two books, one
is called purple stew.
It's out of print.
So it is now a free download at
lulu.com and that's the story of
my journey to a diagnosis of a rare
disorder for my oldest daughter, Erin.
And it's because of that journey that
I have studied and found these answers
that I'm sharing with you today.
I have another children's book,
different is just different.
It has lesson plans and stuff
that's available on my website.
That's Aaron.
Okay.
So Aaron is now 28 years old.
And when she was born,
she stopped breathing.
Which you know is a problem.
And so they've ran all kinds of
tests and couldn't figure out
why she kept stopping breathing.
Now they didn't have to open an airway.
We just kind of physically stimulated
her and she'd start breathing again.
But, um, The breathing was
definitely not rhythmic.
So this is Aaron at a few years
old with her little sister, Sarah,
Sarah is only a year and three weeks
younger and that was by design.
Uh, so Sarah is now 27 and she has a
degree in neuroscience and biology.
So we really like to talk about brains.
Um, and, um, she's actually
at the FAC ed, um, doing a
master's in education right now.
So we have a lot to talk about, anyway,
this is Aaron a couple of years ago
and, uh, she doesn't stop breathing
anymore, which is really good.
We found out when she was about
three and a half, that the reason
for that Rocky start was that she has
something called you bear syndrome.
And that's a very rare disorder.
We know of about 2000 people in the
world that have to bear syndrome and
it affects the part of the brain that
regulates breathing and motoric things
and really anything sensory, um, And,
uh, w well, we've also discovered that
for you science guys or people it's a
celiac disease, so there are actually four
other organs that are involved, but today
we're just going to talk about the brain.
So it's okay to feel badly when
bad things are happening to you.
In fact, we are wired that way.
My daughter, Sarah has told me that
over the years and, um, she's right.
I mean, if we.
If bad things are happening
and we're not feeling bad, I
think that's a bit of an issue.
Um, but through my studies in sensory
processing therapy, I can also tell
you that we need to get our brain
juice, our neurochemistry back to
an optimum level in order to move.
Um, so I did a really quick Google search
about, uh, stress, daily stress, and
very quickly I got thousands of hits of
research and they all tell you that yes,
there's a lot of stress in our lives.
Um, but let's get our
terminology, um, together.
Okay.
So quite often, and I'm guilty of this,
I use stress and anxiety interchangeably,
and it's actually not the same thing.
Uh, when we're talking about it,
in terms of your neurochemistry.
Um, several years ago, there was a really
good article in reader's digest and the
Canadian version because I'm in Canada
and it talked about the differences
between worry and stress and anxiety
and worry, worry, that's a feeling.
Okay.
I feel worried.
I feel hungry.
I do something.
And that feeling goes away.
Whereas stress, our thoughts.
I can't stop thinking about it.
Like, you know, last night I've
got this big presentation going on.
Right?
And so you think about it and
it's hard not to think about it.
Um, but.
It does go away when that situation is
resolved, you stop thinking about it
and, and, uh, there's lots of things
that we can do in terms of mindfulness
and meditation, um, regulating
your breathing, things like that.
Um, that definitely helped.
Ignore those thoughts until
the stress has been resolved.
But when we're talking about unresolved
stress, now we're getting into a
physical response and that's anxiety
and that's completely different.
You didn't think your way into anxiety and
you can't think your way out of anxiety.
Let me say that again.
Anxiety is your body's
reaction to unresolved stress.
You didn't think your way into it, and
you can't think your way out of it.
It's a physical response.
You will have to physically change
something in order to move on from,
um, that anxiety state that you're in.
So, is it worry, stress or anxiety?
Because, you know, sometimes we think
something is, you know, maybe somebody's
personality or a habit, or maybe
they've just been, um, dealing with
unresolved stress for such a long time
that these behaviors have just become
routine and they don't realize that,
um, they, that you can actually do
something to move on from these things.
And anger is actually just one
way that anxiety expresses itself.
All right.
So when we're talking about anger, we're
not talking about something completely
different or two sides of the coin.
It is the same thing in
terms of your neurobiology.
So when I was in Arizona, learning
about sensory processing, my, uh,
teacher, um, uh, Bonnie, she, um,
would talk about people with special
needs are like a rose within an onion.
You can see that beautiful sweet
person inside all these layers.
Uh, things of stuff that gets in the way.
And so with different therapies, we
can address different layers until
we get back to the real person,
that person who they truly are.
Uh, so when we're talking about
working with people with exceptional
needs, um, sometimes you do a therapy
and it only works for a little
while, and then it stops working.
And that's your cue that you need
to do a different kind of therapy.
All right.
So that layer has been addressed.
Let's go on to another layer.
And so what I'm talking about today
is that layer of neurochemistry.
Uh, and if you've been trying lots of
other things, um, like mindfulness or
behavior therapy or things like that,
and it's not working for you anymore,
maybe you need to be addressing the lady.
Of the onion that is neurochemistry.
And so psychologists have
all kinds of theories about
why we behave the way we do.
Um, so behaviorism, if I reward or punish,
then you can learn to stop doing that.
Cognitive, I can explain to you
why we do certain things and why,
what you're doing is wrong and
you can choose to not do that.
Um, developmental, you know
what, she's only three.
She's not going to be able to do that yet.
Okay.
So it's just, we're
waiting for that stage.
And then there's humanist and
there's personality theories, and
there are social psychology theories
and there are learning theories.
And then there's your actual brain.
Okay.
So this is your brain on slides.
And this front section here
is the prefrontal lobe.
That's where all the thinking happens.
So this is known as your thinking
brain, all the information from the
environment comes in through your senses.
Is gated by something called the
cerebellum, which I'll get to in a minute.
And it goes into the thinking
brain where it's processed.
You decide what to do with it.
You send that message back out to
your body and you have that behavior.
That's what you do.
Now, the hind brain or the lizard
brain is a reactionary part of your
brain and, um, for my daughter, she,
uh, because she has to bear syndrome,
this is an MRI slice of her brain.
These are her eyes and these places
in here where it's dark, that's
where the brain matter is not.
So, and.
It makes it look like there's a
molar tooth formation in there
and all people with GBR syndrome
have this molar tooth sign.
Um, so this is happening because
she's missing the  in her brain,
that gates all that information
in and out of the cerebellum.
Okay.
So kind of like you're at a horse race
and all the horses are in the gates
and the gun goes off and the gates open
and all the horses are on track and
they go where they're supposed to go.
Well, actually people with autism,
according to MRIs, um, have problems
with their seventh and eighth
ventricles of their vermes and
those are responsible for language.
My daughter, Erin doesn't
have a vermus at all.
So as you can imagine, things were
very, very stressful and it's not
a stress that she can resolve.
She's just not going to grow
back that part of her brain,
it's just not going to happen.
So there was a lot of anger and anxiety
going on with her, just trying to process
her environment and be able to organize
things in order to, to live her life.
So then we have the, the middle
brain, which is your feeling
brain with your hypothalamus and
the thalamus and hippocampus.
And what's, what's really important
to remember is all of these things
in your brain and your body, they
all happen together at the same time.
It's kind of like, um, like baking.
Okay.
So like I could have sugar flour and
water and I could make bread or I could
make cookies or I could make paste
depending on how much of each I put in.
So when there's a actual
recipe, that's great.
Um, and you know, it doesn't work so
you check the recipe and you try again,
but in our bodies and in our brains,
we don't actually have a user manual.
There's no, Recipe, we can't find
out how many more drops of this will
stop you from doing this, or how
many more drops of this do we need
so that you, um, can do these things.
It's it just doesn't work that way.
So we know that these things exist,
but we're not sure exactly what levels
are what each level is at and how to
measure those levels so that you have
a recipe to make yourself feel better.
Um, now, uh, this video, um, and
I'm just looking at time and I'm
actually not going to play it.
It's two minute neuroscience
and it's available on YouTube.
And basically it just tells you
more about this whole thing.
Because what happens is this
stressor comes into your life.
Everything in your body works together
so that you have cortisol released into
your system and that cortisol, which
is one of many different chemicals in
your body, that cortisol, it gets you
into the fright fight flight response.
It increases your heart rate and make
gives you more energy cause you use your
sugars more effectively, things like that.
And so that cortisol response,
when everything is working
optimally and the stressor is
resolved, the lion has run away.
Um, The, your neurochemistry ha
comes back to normal, which signals
the cortisol to say, oh, okay,
everything's great and the rest of you
goes back to an equilibrium as well.
So how do messages get through your brain?
And this is just a couple more minutes
of science and it's, it's really okay.
If this is way over your head or
you're having problems concentrating,
because I'm going really fast.
Feel free to email me.
I can send you an article about it.
Um, you can request more, uh, actual
research that other people have done.
Um, but the really important things and
I'm going to repeat a few times like this.
So in your brain, the messages.
The environment come in and they go
through your brain through nerve cells.
Okay.
But the nerve cells don't
actually touch each other.
There's this little
space called the synapse.
And so what actually carries the
message between from one to the
other, are these little things called
neuro-transmitters or biogenic and means.
As I say brain juice.
And there are lots of those.
We're only going to talk about dopamine
norepinephrine and serotonin, that's it.
So let's go back to the beginning where
there are all these worries and the
thoughts and there's mindfulness and yoga
and prayer and meditation and breathing
and all these things that you can do to
help those thoughts and feelings subside.
And then there are all these psychological
theories that can help you change the
behaviors that you have that are sometimes
due to, um, unresolved stress, which
we can also call anger and anxiety.
And then, the cortisol response you
get, the stress goes into, goes into
you and the cortisol kicks in and these
three neuro-transmitters say, oh wait,
wait, wait, we need to fix this problem.
So all these things.
And I'm going to talk about the layer
of just those three neuro-transmitters,
because I believe that if you've
tried all kinds of other things,
this might be the layer of the
onion that you need to address.
So how does this all
work, in real language?
So you're at your laptop and your
little brother comes in behind
you and says, boo, and one of
three things is going to happen.
Well, first of all, you're going
to get this rush of cortisol.
Cause there's this unexpected stress.
And then you're going to have
a fright response, flight
response, or fight response.
And you, you do that with, without
even thinking, because it's your
hindbrain that's causing this reaction.
That's what's going on.
You're not thinking about it and deciding.
So in my years at, um, at a high school
teaching, I used to talk to my students
about this and I would say, so if
this happens at your house and you hit
your little brother, you can tell your
parent your cortisol made you do it.
And if they don't believe you, um,
they can call me and I'll back you up.
But we can only use that excuse once,
because if the little brother shows
up the third time and you're just
sitting there waiting, cause you know,
he's going to say boo, and in fact
you hit him before he even says, boo.
So that's a cognitive.
That's a learned response.
You've decided that you're
going to do that, which means
you can choose not to as well.
Whereas that fight,
fight or flight response.
Um, isn't a choice.
So when you're red lining, let's
say a your walking down the road
and this big truck comes at you and
you have a fright response, a flight
response, or you have fight response
and you've seen this happen, right?
It's like that doesn't make sense.
Why is he trying to beat up
the truck that almost hit him?
And that's my point.
It doesn't make sense.
These fright fight flight
responses have nothing to do with
thinking it through or deciding.
It just happens.
Now in a regular situation, in a typical
brain, uh, you get out of the way of the
truck and suddenly the serotonin floods
into your system and says, okay, okay.
Nothing to see here.
Everything's fine.
The problems resolved and dopamine and
norepinephrine say, oh, okay, well, good.
It's resolved.
And they go back to normal and the
cortisone goes back to an optimum
level and you can feel this happening.
You can feel your heart rate slow down.
Um, you, um, can.
Um, you're aware of your breathing.
You start being aware of your environment
again, and, um, you, you can feel
this return to, um, to equilibrium.
So while you are in that
stressful situation.
The nor epinephrine's job is to keep you
focused on why is there all this dopamine,
or why is there all this cortisol?
Why is there all this cortisol, which
is really, really important if you need
to get away from a truck because you
know, you don't want to hesitate and
say, oh, that would make a great nail
Polish or, you know, shoes or something.
Um, you want to stay focused
on solving the problem.
But some problems can't be resolved, like
regrowing, a piece of your brain, or like
what I used to tell my students, when
your parents don't act like grownups,
or you have a boss that just isn't
rational or there's a global pandemic
or uh, the world's on the brink of war.
These are things that are very
stressful and can cause you to go into
a physical response of anxiety, but
they are not things that I can resolve
in order for the serotonin to show up.
And that's what needs to happen in
order for you to go back off that
red line and back to an equilibrium.
Let's kind of go that
through that one more time.
You're you're sitting around, you're
very relaxed and everything is optimal.
And then, um, it's green.
Everything's a go.
And then a lion shows up in your room.
And so you have this.
Fright fight flight response,
your dopamine, and nor upfront,
nor epinephrin kick in because
the cortisol has come online.
It's like I have to, I
have to attend to this.
I have to shelve this.
I have to solve this.
And then once you've gotten away from
said lion, then you stop red lining.
The serotonin comes back in and
says, okay guys, we did our job.
Everything's good.
And you go back to an equilibrium.
But what happens when the line is
just in another room and you're really
not sure what's going to happen next.
And you get into this, I'm walking
on eggshells kind of thing?
Like.
Kids who don't have, um, a good home life.
Um, am I going to have food?
Is there somebody going to be there?
Am I going to get hit?
All of these things are building up.
It might not be happening at that
exact moment, but they are still
dealing with those kinds of things.
And it's the same for us in our,
um, out of school situations where
we're dealing with unresolved stress.
It just never.
You just never seem to be able to relax.
You get this gray fog or, you know, you
just feel like at any moment, you're,
you're going to explode and that is PTSD.
Post-traumatic stress disorder.
So PTSD is not just being unable to
move on from a tram one traumatic event.
Okay.
I mean, that is true.
It's absolutely that, but it's also,
if you deal with unresolved stress
on a chronic years kind of level.
Then you are, you have depleted your
body of the serotonin, that it needs
to bring you back to an optimum
level and you are on that cortisol
high and you that's PTSD that.
Re you can't think your way out of that
because you didn't think your way into it.
You have to physically do something thing
to change the neurochemistry so that
you can move on past those thoughts.
Um, because after a while, you're not
sure if that's a kitten or a lion.
Um, so another really quick recap,
something stressful happens,
cortisol comes into the system.
Dopamine says, Hey, what's going on?
I want to be rewarded.
What's happening here.
Nor epinephrin says focus, focus.
We need to solve this problem.
What's going if we focus, focus,
and when it's resolved, serotonin
floods in and says, okay, no worries.
We got this it's solved.
And everyone goes back to normal levels.
Let's go back to that truck.
So a few hours later, um, you're
telling somebody that you almost
got hit by a truck today, and you
can feel your body have those same
physiological responses that you,
that you did in the real situation.
Just the memory of a stressful
situation can put you back into
a fright flight fight response.
Now in that truck memory,
you got out of the way.
And so serotonin showed up and so it
will show up again, but you will have
that same visceral response that you
did just with the memory of that event.
In fact, David Rock talks about the
scarf model, where there are human
social experiences that can also
put you into a fright flight fight
response, just like a lion in the room.
So, if you feel that your status
is threatened, you're uncertain
about outcomes, you don't feel
like you have a sense of autonomy.
Things don't feel related
or they're just unfair.
It can also get the cortisol going
into a fight, fright flight response.
And I don't know about you, but I've
had a couple of bosses that, you
know, I've definitely created a work
environment that this kind of thing
is, is very real and don't dismiss it.
It is just as real as
if a lion has shown up.
Quick, quick, um, Story in 2018.
Um, my husband had a seizure at work
and we discovered that he had a tumor,
a meningioma on the top of this brain.
Uh, we had no idea that it was
there until he had this seizure
on a Saturday after Saturday
evening, they did surgery on Sunday.
They got.
It wasn't cancerous.
It didn't need radiation
Tuesday he came home.
Yeah.
Three days later.
Okay.
So my daughter, err, my
daughter, Erin was here.
My daughter, Sarah came home from school.
She was about eight hours away.
And of course she was studying
neuroscience and biology.
In fact, she was also a first
responder for, um, like a local like
St John's ambulance, which is, um,
You know, like medics paramedics.
Um, and so I thought on Tuesday evening,
well, he's home and Sarah is way more
qualified to watch him breathe then I am.
So I went back to my teaching job.
Yeah.
Kind of silly, but I really felt
like there were all these things
that I had to get done and it had
to get done by Friday because then
Sarah was going home on Sunday.
And what would I do?
Anyway, I went to work.
And this woman talked to me
in the hallway and I, I can't
remember exactly who she was.
Um, but she said, oh Karen, I'm so
sorry to hear about your husband.
She said, I was feeling
really bad about me.
And then I heard about
him and on just so sorry.
And I was like, oh, You're welcome.
I'm glad the stress of my
life helped yours feel better.
But see, that's not really what she meant.
What she meant was, um, I
was feeling really stressed
and feeling sorry for myself.
And then I heard about your situation
and I just kind of had to shake my
head and say, it could always be worse,
but I wish that I could remember who
that person was because I need to
tell her you can't compare stuff.
What's on my plate is
what I'm dealing with.
And what's on your plate is
what you're dealing with.
And whether it's a burger or a
steak, we're still dealing with
our stuff and you can't compare.
You can't say, oh, they have it so much
worse, why can't I get my stuff together?
Well, you, you don't know what's
going on with that person.
I mean, I go to a psychiatrist.
I take really good drugs to make
sure I have enough serotonin to,
uh, offset all the stress that is
unresolved stress that is in my life.
Um, I do other physical activities
to naturally increase my serotonin.
But what I've got is what I deal with.
Just like somebody with diabetes who
doesn't have enough insulin to deal
with the sugars in their system, because
their sugars and everything, some people
need more serotonin to deal with all the
stress unresolved stress in their lives.
So it's okay to feel badly when
bad things are happening to you.
In fact, we're wired that way.
If you didn't feel bad, I think
there was something wrong that
would be way more concerning for me.
Um, and we need to, uh, get our brain
juice back to an optimum level so that we
can move on from this unresolved stress.
Okay.
So the best part.
All right, that's great.
What do I do about it?
Well, we need to increase our serotonin
and, and, uh, first you need to
remember that this is not your fault.
It's not your fault.
You didn't do anything to ask for this.
This is not a test.
This is not something you deserved.
It is not your fault.
It's just the way you're built.
People don't choose to have diabetes.
People don't choose to
have chronic anxiety.
Um, so.
If you have a little bit of stress,
you need a few drops of serotonin.
You can be out in the sun, look at
the color green, listen to some music.
Um, those were like little
droplets of serotonin.
I mean, it's not really.
It's just an analogy.
It's a comparison.
It's not really drops, but
that's what I'm going to use.
Because if you have a little more stress,
maybe you need a shot glass of serotonin.
And so that would be your tactile sense.
Um, um, a massage or a warm bath or
a weighted blanket and a weighted
blankets are really in right now.
People are very aware of the
benefits of that kind of therapy.
And that's good because we
need to be aware of that.
But sometimes you need
even more than that.
And so then you need to use one of your
internal census called proprioception,
and that's where your body is in space.
And, um, when you do joint compressions
from running or lifting weights or
things like that, then you get like
a glassful of serotonin and that
will last in your system for like an
hour or so um, according to studies.
But the biggest bang for your
buck is the vestibular sense
or where your head is in space.
So if you can get your head moving
around, It's going to be like a bucket
of serotonin going into your system.
And so that's like swinging or jumping
or being on a roller coaster, or
I don't know if any of, you know,
people that have a boat and they say,
once I'm on the boat, 15 minutes,
I don't have a care in the world.
And I can tell you that it's true.
And it's not because of the beer.
It's because that gentle,
rocking motion is increasing
their serotonin exponentially.
And so the dopamine and norepinephrine
go, oh, look, there's all this
serotonin, I guess we solved the problem.
And everything goes back to an optimal
level and that's what we need in
order to move on from those behaviors
caused by chronic anxiety and anger.
So there's, um, there is
peer research behind all this
stuff that I'm talking about.
And, um, if you would like a
copy of a list of those research
articles, please email me.
I can send that to you.
I also have an article which kind
of recaps everything I've just
talked about in the last 40 minutes.
Um, but please don't let
people burst your bubble.
Don't just suck it up.
I mean, that's, that's what I was
raised as you know, like this baby
boomer thing where, oh, suck it up.
Don't let them see you sweat.
Well, that's not healthy.
And my kids who are millennials will
tell me, no, you have to take a step
back and deal with your mental health
otherwise it will affect your physical
health and you can't just get through it.
And you know what?
Everybody has stuff.
Everybody.
It's okay to not be okay all the time.
That's the way we're wired.
And it's good to need someone else.
I mean, I wish we could be
doing this live and in person.
Okay.
Because then you could look around at your
colleagues and say, I'm not the only one
that feels this way because you're not.
You're not the only one and
their safety in numbers.
It's good to need somebody else.
Um, exercise is really important.
Um, listen to your body.
If you have like irritable bowel
syndrome, you had indigestion
those kinds of digestion issues.
That's because there's a whole
lot of serotonin in your gut that
keeps things running optimally.
So if you're low on serotonin in
your brain, you're probably going
to be low in serotonin in your gut.
And you're going to, um, you're going to
be off things aren't going to be working.
But more importantly, play.
You know, um, swing on a swing.
I bought a little hammock swing for $60
and I have it hanging in my basement.
And I go use that when I know that
things are stressful, I'll go on a
roller coaster dance, things like that.
But, what will you do?
Pick one of these things that increases
your serotonin and, and try it.
Make room for it, put it somewhere
on your plate or take something off
your plate so that you have that time.
And then in three months, go back
to that baseline behavior that we
identified at the beginning of our
time together and theoretically,
it shouldn't be happening as often.
I'd love to know how that works for you.
Email me and let me know.
That's really what it's all about
is being with other people and
knowing how your system works
and what you can do to help it.
Um, we have about three minutes for
questions, uh, but we can absolutely go
into the community tent and have a longer
discussion if people would like that.
Mike Demo: Hello and welcome back.
So that was, uh, an amazing talk, Karen.
And, um, we actually don't have
time for questions, but you'll be
in the community tent where you, um,
you'll be hosting an intimate, um,
Q and a where people can learn more.
And it's funny, you talk about breathing.
I have on my desk, it's a little inhaler
type device which, um, counts my breaths
and tries to slow down your breathing.
So you breathe into it, vibrates
you, then you breathe in.
And so, um, this is an FDA device
that I use with my, um, therapist.
And, um, so when you were talking
about breathing, I looked down at that,
I'm like, oh, he reminds me of that.
So, um, And we have lots of questions
so please go over to the community tent.
We actually have a 15
minute break right now.
So please head over to the community
tent and chat with the sponsors.
We want to thank all of our
sponsors, Bluehost Cloudways.
GoDaddy Pro Nexcess Yoast Weglot.
Be sure to visit their tents.
You might even win some prizes.
If you get your photo taken at the
photo booth, tweet it out with hashtag
#WordFestLive and thank you to our
media partners and micro sponsors.
In the next hour in the community tent
Cloudways will have their hourly giveaway
with another special guest activity.
Nexcess will have a chance to win
and Bluehost will do a demo of their
builder and building a site live
with the Bluehost Website Builder.
Of course, if you want to donate,
click the donate button and, um,
give to Big Orange Heart, um, to
support this wonderful organization.
Um, that's it for myself.
I just want to say thanks
to my amazing cohost, Cathy.
Um, it's been a pleasure, um,
hanging out with you for a few hours.
Cathy Tibbles: Thank you.
Thanks.
Mike Demo: Excellent.
So again, we're on a 15 minute break,
go head over to the community tent,
and then we're going to send it over
to the North American Continent.