Yoast: Do you know, the Yoast SEO,
plugin, they're red, orange, and
green feedback bullets that help
you optimize your posts for the web.
It runs on millions of websites.
We tried to make SEO understandable
and accessible to everyone.
Nexcess: Oh great.
My website crashed.
I give up.
Don't give up on your dreams.
Jordan, who are you?
It's me.
You from the future.
Your professional website
is not out of reach.
You just need Nexcess.
With Nexcess managed hosting, you
Git lightening fast load times
built-in performance monitoring and
updates, and always awesome support.
24 7 365 for all your projects.
Whoa.
Yeah.
Weglot: Discover Weglot the simple
translation solution for your website.
All you have to do is add Weglot to
your website, select the languages
that you need, and that's it.
Your website is now available
in multiple languages.
Bluehost: Who says building
an online store has to be
hard with Bluehost website.
It's more than just easy.
It's tell us your thing and smart AI.
We'll take it from there.
Easy it's WooCommerce friendly.
So you can add one of these,
or swap this for that easy.
It's set up shop in minutes
with unlimited products.
Easy.
Whether you sell boots, books
or bowls, it's create an online
store with Bluehost, easy build
beyond boundaries with Bluehost.
Matt Graham: Welcome one
and all to WordFest Live.
We are just Gitting started with 24 hours
of celebrating the people, the technology
and the Big Orange Heart of WordPress.
Rachel Winchester: WordFest Live not
only delivers a festival educational
content, wellness sessions and
networking opportunities, but it's
also a fundraiser for Big Orange Heart.
Please visit that donate link at any time
to support the mission of our organism.
Matt Graham: WordFest Live as a 24
hour opportunity for the WordPress
community to come together, to feel
less isolated, learn from one another
and be present with each other.
Rachel Winchester: Our first speaker
today is AmyJune Hineline with
Git Into The Groove, moving from
freelance to collaborative workflow.
AmyJune is an active
contributor in the open source.
As the open source community
ambassador, she is uniquely positioned
to help individuals become more
comfortable and confident as they
contribute to their communities.
In addition to her work, building
community connections, AmyJune is an avid
geocasher noted Volkswagen enthusiasts
and eights with her elbows on the table.
AmyJune Hineline: Hi, thanks
for that nice introduction.
Um, I love going first.
It's nice to Git kind of
things out of the way.
There's a little bit of a
hiccup, but that's okay.
That's what happens when
we, um, work in tech, right.
We know that.
Um, so I am going to be talking
about, um, collaborative workflow
and git today, um, all to the, kind
of the theme to the eighties, which
makes it a little bit more fun.
Uh, before I start, I like
to do some housekeeping.
There are images in the slide deck
and I am an accessibility advocate.
So I do understand that some folks
watching or participating today
might not be able to see the visual
assets, if there's any pictures that
add context or are, uh, need to be
explained, I will, uh, I'll I'll explain
those as I go, but some of them are
decorative and I won't describe them.
Um, for the sake of brevity, I
usually include a link to the
slide deck, but I accidentally
put it in a red hat, uh, drive.
So I'm going to redo that
after the presentation and make
those, uh, slides available.
And I'll post those online.
I.
And presenting today, um, on the
Aloni Lands in Northern California.
And I'd like to acknowledge, um,
that I do live on a traditional
ancestral unceded territory.
Uh, it's important to understand the
longstanding history that we all have.
That's brought us to live with.
Um, and land acknowledgements
don't exist in the past tense.
Uh, they are current, uh, colonialism
is an ongoing process and we
need to build our mindfulness,
um, of our present participants.
Uh, my name is AmyJune.
All one word title, camel case.
Uh, my pronouns are she and her.
I'm the senior community manager over at
https://opensource.com and opensource.com
is under the red hat umbrella.
opensource.com is a website dedicated
to sharing information about open
source along with open culture.
If you ever want to write for
opensource.com, you know, Git ahold of
me, um, you can see my links are here.
It's VolkswagenChick across,
you know, LinkedIn and Facebook
and Instagram and Twitter.
Um, I.
I want to acknowledge that.
I really believe in reducing the
barriers to entry for tech, not only
with contributions, but tech in general,
I lead contribution days, um, at the
local regional and national level.
Um, because everyone, uh, can contribute
back to our projects, not just with code.
Here's my friend Spotty.
He lives with me.
Um, you might see him.
So I just want to introduce
him ahead of time.
His long name is Spotty MacSpotsALot,
but we can call them spot for short.
He is named after the star Trek cat.
And what are we going to talk about today?
We'll talk about what it's like in
freelance world versus agency life.
Um, and one of the things that I
really want to concentrate on are
the tools that makes it easier for
us to collaborate with other people.
That's version control, but I'll
also talk about, uh,git clients,
um, uh, local environments.
And I do have up here that I'll do a demo
if slack, if time permits, but I do talk
a lot, so that doesn't usually happen.
Moving to agency from freelance
has definitely has its advantage.
Um, What are some of the
things we love about freelance?
We love the freedom that
working alone gives us, you
know, we work at our own time.
At any time.
We don't have to worry about
bothering a team and pinging them
or emailing them in the middle of
the night when we Git up, because
we have a revelation about our code.
But along with that freedom, Come some
difficulties too, you know, uh, there's
no one around to bounce ideas off of.
There's no one to help
you with code review.
There's no one to help you
with any sort of conflicts.
Um, sometimes you just do what
you need to do to Git the job
done, and it can be detrimental
to not have that accountability.
Sometimes I like to equate
it to the wild, wild west.
Because we're juggling all the
roles, you know, you're the person
in charge of absolutely everything.
You're the project manager, you're
doing quality assurance and, you
know, a user experience, QA and UX.
Uh you're you're the designer,
you're the product owner.
You're all of those things.
But many of the advantages that came
with freelance work historically has
started to be encompassed into agency
life with the onset of the pandemic.
You know, um, we see companies
and agencies moving to more,
uh, remote friendly conditions.
We're not going into the office as much.
And we're also being more inclusive about
time zones these days, and teamwork offers
diversity of thought and diversity of.
Creativity, having a team around
having that team environment,
everyone brainstorms together, which
in turns really increases problem
solving and we're more efficient and
effective at arriving at solutions.
Effective teams also allow more
room for innovation, uh, in turn
it creates, you know, a competitive
edge, you know, uh, there's uh,
Accomplishing goals and objectives,
uh, uh, objectives, you know, sharing
differing opinions and experiences really
strengthens and holds us accountable.
You know, we can make decisions
faster and team effort increases, you
know, um, you can do the, you can do
the stages of designing, planning,
implement implementation, and much more
effectively when a team is there to help.
And also working in a traditional
full-time web development role at an
established company or agency can give
us the opportunity for more structured
learning, you know, and free learning.
You know, we have professional
development budGit that we can rely on.
Um, plus we have everyday exposure
to experts and mentors and best
practices that you don't always
Git as a freelancer or maybe.
There's a barrier because of cost.
When you're on your own, you assume every
role, like I said, on a team, there's a
place for everyone to contribute based on
the roles and their specific skill sets.
And this really adds accountability in the
forms of checks and balances on a team.
You know, we have those project
managers, they help assign tasks
and they act as in-betweens for
developers and stakeholders, they
help translate jargon and find out
what specifically needed tickets
are submitted and they're assigned.
Um, developers and
designers work on the tasks.
And then, you know, they're collaborative,
which leads to improvement and more ideas.
There are technical leads
that help us merge code and
settle conflicts in our code.
And then after changes in
conflicts are resolved.
We have folks who perform that
user testing for us and the quality
assurance and regression testing.
You know, when we write the
code, we really shouldn't.
Um, Be reviewing our own code.
Um, and then after the pro, after that,
the project manager takes over again
and decides if the changes are ready
for the stakeholders and it's a rinse
and repeat, and it's so much easier
within a team code, workflow management
becomes a great deal easier when we have
tools in place like version control.
Version control is a system that records
changes to a file set or a set of files
over time so that we can go back and we
can recall those specific versions later.
So this is more about the code
workflow management version
controls are a category of software
tools that help a software team.
Manage changes to the source code over
time, uh, version control, software
tracks, every single modification to
the code and a special kind of database.
Uh, if mistakes are made developers
and project managers can turn back
time and make comparisons to earlier
versions of the code to help really
remedy any mistakes or blunders without
a lot of downtime for the whole team.
What are some of the requirements
for implementing version control?
Because there are some prerequisites first
you need a computer equipped for the task.
You want to make sure we install.
Git locally.
Or globally, you know, even if it's
already installed, which may be, it
could, it could be installed because
maybe you have dev tools already
installed, but it's always a good
idea to update to that latest version.
And this can be done, you know,
through a package or another
installer, or you can download the
source code and compile it yourself.
If you're confident enough to do.
And then also basic knowledge
of the command line.
If you're a beginner, a Git client
can be used, but you should really
be acquainted with some of that basic
command line knowledge, not a lot, but
it really helps to know what's going
on behind the scenes of the client.
When you use one.
And there are graphical user
interfaces for the command line.
Sometimes we hear them called gooeys,
you know, GUI graphical user interfaces.
And I want to introduce this concept
because in the next few slides,
I have some images for reference.
Um, and after I introduced the commands,
um, what they look like in the Git
client and the client simplifies the
commands into buttons and drop downs and
window, um, interfaces for the workers.
This is an image of a client.
You know, we're looking at the
source tree and a log across the top.
You can see there's some
buttons down the sides.
There's more buttons.
Uh, some of them aren't available.
If there's nothing to do, for example,
um, the merge button across the top
in the middle, um, it's grayed out
because there's nothing currently
to merge, but the checkout, the
ad branch, the cherry pick, the
revert functions are all available.
And along the left side, there's
checkboxes to add branches, um, uh,
tags, you know, you can view those
the source tree, um, and then across
the, you know, the very, the very, uh,
left side, there are, you can choose
what files are open in the log when.
And there are a lot
ofgit clients available.
Some are free, others are not, some
have free versions with limited access.
Others are free with full access.
Some free versions only allow us to
work on repositories that are public.
So that can be limiting sometimes
if our client's code bases are
private or have limited access.
So make sure you do your homework,
you know, try some out, make sure
they have features that you need.
And then something to be aware of
too, is sometimes agencies have shared
licenses and would like everyone to
use the same client, because that
makes troubleshooting a little bit
easier when everyone's using the same.
Many developers, developers turn to
integrated development environment.
Those are IDEs for short, um,
integrated development environments.
And most of these, um, IDE clients,
uh, they have a learning curve.
Um, so sometimes the IDE
might not be accessible for
you but much likegit clients.
Some are free, some have trials and some.
And some agencies again, like
have everyone use the same tool,
so make sure your machine can
handle the load of running an IDE.
Uh, sometimes the combination of having
some applications open can affect
runtime and really slow down the machine.
I know until I started working with a
stronger machine, if I had Docker open
with a complicated spreadsheet with
like lots of things going on in that.
And then if I turn on my slack and
then, oh my gosh, if I had zoom
on my machine would really start
whining and the fan would spin up.
Um, so be mindful of, you know, how,
how, how much workload it takes to
run some of these things altogether.
So why Git and not
subversion or another tool?
A lot of us use Git, because
Git, has become the industry
standard for web development.
It has a very rich set of commands
for tracking cloning and workflows.
And many of these basics can be carried
through to other versioning workflows.
So here's where my eighties
references start to come into play.
Um, forgive me ahead of time.
We have never going to Git you up.
I'm never going to Git you down.
So we're going to start talking
about some basics of Git, um, I have
some listed here, but we're going
to go into most of them in a little
bit, but, um, we have Git in it.
Uh, it starts a new repository.
Git status is my absolute
favorite command.
It will list all of the files
that have been changed and
are waiting to be committed.
It's a good command to run
before running any other command.
And maybe that's why my
faith it's my favorite.
Cause I do it the most.
Um, it works is.
It reminds you of what
you've been working on.
There's branching that lists all the
local branches in your current repository.
You can also visually indicate what
branch or what branch you're currently on.
And depending on how you have your
terminal, you know, it might be
highlighted green or have an asterisked.
Git diff shows the file differences,
which are not yet staged.
Git logged.
This command is used to list, uh, the
version history of the current branch.
You're on Git push since the
committed branches of our main
branch to our remote repositories.
Again, I'm going to be talking about
these in depth in a little bit.
Um, so don't feel over.
Git pull fetches and merges,
you know, changes to your remote
server on your working directory.
Git add.
That's where we add our files
that we've been working on.
Um, we put them in a staging
area, Git commit, actually commits
those changes, um, Git merged.
This is when we're working with others
and we merge our workflows together.
So let's Git into the groove and talk
a little bit about working locally.
This means on your machine and
not in the browser or in a cloud.
So the basics of working locally,
one of those main commands that we
want to talk about is Git clone.
It creates a working copy.
Of a, of a repository
locally on your machine.
And from there you start making
your changes, um, Git remote.
If you haven't connected yet to your
local repository, to a remote server,
um, you add the server, so you're
able to push it, your changes up.
And this is used when you have
created initialized a code base
locally first, when we talked
about that, Git in it to me.
Git pull.
And I'm going to talk about this
almost through every workflow.
It's when your code is somewhere
else and it might be different from
your current work, you know, fetch
and merge changes on the remote
server to your working directory.
Again, I'm going to talk
about this command a lot.
It really helps keep you up to
date with what other people are
working on much, like Git status.
I almost do a Git poll with everything.
And here's a shot of that.
Git client, you know, while we're
cloning, it's a very intuitive interface.
I'm not going to say easy because
easy is a relative term, but
it's pretty straightforward.
Um, you enter the URL where the code
base lives and you push a button.
And most of our repositories online
that we share with each other, have
this information readily available
in their dashboard or in their read
me files of how to set it up locally.
So let's talk about branching.
Um, we don't want to make
changes to the shared code base.
So we want to create branches that
mirror the code and, and we want
to work on those other branches.
So we don't corrupt others work.
So here's some commands around branching.
We have Git branch when we enter that into
our terminal or in her Git client again,
this lists all of the branches in your
repository, and it also tells you what
branch you're currently on Git checkout.
And you can amend that with Git
checkout in your branch name.
This command is used to switch
from one branch to another.
Git checkout dash B.
It actually creates a new
branch right then and there
for you and you switched to it.
So you would say Git checkout dash B
and then the name of your new branch.
And then you'll be deposited right
on that new branch Git branch dash D
deletes your current feature branch.
And back to that client, you know,
press a button and you can name
and create a branch in a matter
of seconds, you name the brand.
What you, how you name the
branch is really up to you.
But when we work together, we want
to make sure that we're consistent
with what everyone else is doing.
Sometimes agencies and organizations
might have parameters on naming
conventions, like the task or
the ticket number and the name.
Um, sometimes when you're working on, uh,
you know, contributing back to WordPress,
you put the ticket, um, as your branch
name, you know, what, what ticket you're
working on in the, in the track queue.
Okay.
So we're going to push it
now, push it real good.
Right.
Um, pushing refers to working with
others remotely, you know, at some point
you want to share your modifications
or your additions that you made.
With the team and to do this,
you have to push it upstream.
Uh, you want to make
sure your branches ready.
So first you do Git add that's
where you add one or more to
staging one or more files to stay.
Um, if you want to add all of them,
you do Git, add with a star or Git
I'm sorry, Git ad with a period.
And that adds all of your, all
of the files, but you can also
add files one by one by saying,
Git, add, and then the file name.
So say you're working on four
or five files, but you're
not ready to add all of them.
You can add them one by one.
Uh, Git commit, uh, commit
changes to your local branch.
Um, we have Git comat, uh, Git commit
dash M and then you put a message there,
you know, that your commit message.
Um, again, you know, um,
Use your messaging wisely.
Sometimes agencies will want you to maybe
start with your ticket number or the, or
the feature branch name, you know, so,
so really work with your team on commit
messages as well, and then Git pull, you
know, fetch and Birch changes on that
remote server to your working directory.
Again, like I said, I referenced
this a lot because that's really
important to make sure your.
Current with others.
Sometimes communication
is less than perfect.
And a few people are working on the
same lines of code at the same time.
You know, maybe someone's pushed theirs
up since the last time you checked,
this really helps with conflicts.
Um, and I talk about conflicts in the
next couple of slides and then Git pushed.
You know, you send your changes
back to that main branch of
the, of the remote repository.
Here's another screenshot, you
know, and this one's highlighting,
uh, the button in the user
interface for pushing and pulling.
Uh, the dropdowns next to them allow for
more choices and gives useful information.
I really recommend becoming familiar with
the tool tips and the information windows
when you're first learning the process and
familiarizing yourself with the workflow.
Often these tool tips show the
relevant, Git terminal commands to.
So remember how I said that basic
knowledge you can gain some of that.
More advanced knowledge by, you
know, hovering and dropping down
and finding out those, uh, relevant,
Git, uh, terminal commands.
So we're going to talk about merging.
Before applying outside changes,
you should Git your own work in
good shape and committed locally.
So you're not, so it won't be
clobbered if there's any conflicts.
So let's bring in all of
our work flow together.
You know, it's more than just
pushing your code to a clean branch.
Um, maybe your team is working
on the same code all at once.
You know, it all needs to
come together and be merged.
Um, so this Git remote command,
you know, the command is used to
connect your local repository.
Git pull.
Remember I talk about that one a lot.
We fetch and merger changes to the
remote server, you know, to our
working directory and then Git merge.
This command merges, the
specified branch history into
the current branch and a client.
You can look at logs and compare the
two instances in time of the same file.
You know, it's color coded
green is for additions.
Red is for taken out.
You can compare different
branches in different instances
in time with your client.
Um, here's merging, you know,
there's a button for merging.
It does magic behind the scenes
and pulls the code together.
Um, while it can do some magic, it
doesn't want to make assumptions
if there's a lot of conflict.
And so you have to kind of work
through those conflicts yourself.
So what do we do about
conflicts and commotion?
I love this Twitter space.
I am developer, and this is so true.
We've been there.
We just think it's going to
take a minute to clean up.
You know, we've all said this before.
They're famous.
Last words.
It will be a quick fix.
But conflicts happen, you know, even
with the most senior developers, the
most direct way to resolve a merge
conflict is to edit the conflicted file.
Um, Git status.
Remember that's my favorite one.
You know, you list the files and
you've changed, and those that
still need to be added or committed.
Um, we use the Git diff command.
Dif helps us find differences between the
states of the repository or the files.
And this is useful in predicting
and preventing merge conflicts.
We have Git logged dash dash merge where
we can view all of the merge conflicts
and then Git push that's where we send
our changes back to the main branch
of our lo of our remote repository.
So.
Here's a screenshot of the Git client.
Again, you can see there's three versions
of the same code compared to each other.
And this is the time to review and check.
There are really two things you
can do with this information.
You can decide not to merge,
or you can fix the conflicts.
So when the decision is made not to
merge in the code, um, say your code
just isn't playing nice together.
Too many people have made
too many changes at once.
So.
We'll use a command, Git fetch
origin, this fetches the latest
history from the server and it
points your local main branch.
Git reset.
And then, um, the commit, this command
undo all of the commits after the
specified commit and preserves the
changes locally, Git reset dash hard
with, um, the commit number, this
command discards all of the history
and goes back to the specified.
Then there are buttons to help you
with the nuclear option to, you
know, push a button, but what's nice
is Git, clients are really polite.
Um, they make sure we really want
to blow up or dissolve our work.
So you can see in this screenshot,
you know, are you sure you want to do.
Um, and it gives you that warning.
So it's really easy to see.
So, um, even if you're like really
comfortable on the command line, sometimes
it's nice to Git back into that, Git
client on some of these more, uh, uh,
with the merge conflicts and stuff,
web based version control platforms.
These are things like.
Uh, GitHub bit bucket, Git lab.
These are platforms that provide us
with a rad visual interface, which also
can really help us track and manage
our version control projects locally.
Um, you know, the workflow is kind
of the same, you know, you create
a branch, you work in a space
away from that production site.
You add commits, revise the
code and add them to branch.
You create pull requests.
This starts the process of code review
and an interface for everyone to see,
um, and then code reviews where we
discuss and collaborate everything, you
know, because maybe I made a change.
Um, but when made a different change
and we need to talk about those things.
And then merging is where we move
our code into the main branch.
Uh, here is a screenshot of a GitHub
repository, you know, um, this is
mine cause I like to be polite.
Uh, you can see that the files are listed.
You can see, um, some of the things
that I've changed over time, you
know, there's buttons across the top.
It's that interface for
my code repository online.
And this is a pull request.
Someone looked at my report and said,
oh, something's not quite right.
So they put in a pull request, which
is like, kind of like a merge request.
Um, and with the click of a button,
I'm able to do that, uh, online.
A local server plays a
vital role for developers.
The purpose of a development environment
is to have a place that allows development
and testing on a local machine without
the concerns of losing internet
connection or accidentally creating
temporary security holes or constantly
uploading files, a local environment
is really a place for developers or
designers to test everything they want.
Without worrying about it affecting any
end users or content editors working
on the live website and much like Git
there some prerequisites that go involved
with, you know, uh, setting up your
local host environment at a minimum.
Uh, you need a PHP server.
This is for WordPress PHP
server, a database server,
um, and PHP for WordPress.
You also need a computer that's
equipped for the task, you know?
Some of us are still on older
machines, not on our M ones.
You know, if you're using a Mac, you
want to make sure, you know, some
of the minimum requirements might
be something like, you know, a two
core 86 compact press processor with
maybe four gigabytes of memory or
gigabytes of Ram, and then, you know,
25 gigabytes of available disc space.
But all these local hosts, when you set
them up will tell you what they prefer.
Um, some of the more
complex agents might be.
To work at an optimum.
Um, you might need an
eight core processor.
So do your research when selecting
which service you want to use,
and then a local server plays a
pivotal part for most of all offers.
It really allows.
And I like to iterate this, reiterate
it, it allows development and testing
on a local machine without the
concerns of an internet connection.
I've listed some options for
setting up local servers.
Uh, you can have, you know, Linux, you
can use Mac iOS, windows development.
You can use a virtual machine
development of virtual machines.
Sometimes you'll hear
the, uh, them called VMs.
It's a full self-contained
server running in its own
environment and operating system.
On your machine kind of separate
from your machine and then
Docker development environments.
Docker's a great tool, um, for local
development environments as well because
of the small print, a small footprint
it has, and the fast startup times.
So this is like, you might hear
it called containerized develop.
So why have a local server?
You know, there are a few reasons
that pretty much require you to
build your web stuff locally.
Um, you might have limited
access to the client server.
You know, you're building a website
or an app for someone else, and you
don't have access to their web server.
You don't have access to
their private repository.
Uh, If you're building a new version of an
existing website or application, you know,
which means that you don't want to mess
around with production, um, while you're
tinkering and experimenting and possibly
making mistakes with the new code.
So it really allows for more
experimentation without the
risk of blowing up the library.
And then no local internet
connection is required.
You don't need a web hosting service,
or even an internet connection.
You know, everything runs
conveniently on your computer.
You can concentrate on coding
and leaving the deployment of
the site until you're ready.
You know, you can work while you're
waiting for your kids at gymnastics.
While you're waiting in line for the gym
membership, you know, things like that.
And you can really customize
your setup, you know, test your
development before going live.
It really takes away that risk
of building new features and
makes development less stressful.
And then there's the idea
of just having more control.
And you can tell I'm excited about this.
Um, particularly when you're debugging,
you know, say you're new and you don't
know what you're doing, you know, It's
sometimes helpful to have more control
over your environment, you know, um,
and have special tools in place that
you don't want on your production site.
Cause it might bog bog it
down, but the good news is,
you know, those requirements.
We mentioned a couple of slides
back, you know, the web server, a
database server and the PHP part.
There are a lot of local hosts that
can do all of that work for us.
And we don't have to set it up ourselves.
You know, usually some of these hosts will
come with a web server, a data management
system to run on the web server.
They have server side
programming languages.
Um, they often have interfaces
for controlling the web server,
you know, starting stopping.
Pausing, and then an interface
for accessing and manipulating
the database, which we don't
always have a more working online.
And this is new.
Uh, I work in the Drupal space
a lot and we work with, uh, Git
pod and I spun up a WordPress
site, uh, yesterday using Git pod.
It's a new browser based environment
that allows for collaboration.
It's Git pod.
It's really straightforward to spin up an
automated dev environment in the cloud.
And it doesn't take very much time.
It's integrated with vs code, or you
can use a JetBrains IDE within its
environment, and it's very customizable.
And what's super nice about this.
Git pod is you can share the URL with
somebody and you can see them working
in the code online at the same time.
And that is the end of the presentation.
So I want to thank everybody again.
Um, and Volkswagen Chick across
all of the media and that's spelled
V O L K S W A G E N C H I C K.
It's really long, but you can do it.
And then, um, when I share that
slide deck, I do have some really
good information on, uh, resources
on Git, and I'll actually put more
resources up there because I want to
put that, Git pawed link of there.
Cause it's very exciting
local environment.
And with that, I'll stop sharing.
And I'm not sure if we're
going to do questions.
Matt Graham: Um, well, I mean,
I have a few questions for you.
Um, so first of all, I think you need to
be in charge of karaoke if that's ever
a thing for, for WordFest, because then
you could be like a combination of like
a tech version of Weird Al with your,
your, with your eighties references.
Cause I started grooving to those songs.
AmyJune Hineline: I actually
do another presentation in the
accessibility community where I
talk about alternative texts and I
use eighties imagery for that too.
Super fun.
Matt Graham: So, um, one of the questions
that, uh, I mean, just from the title
of, of your, of your talk, I do a lot
of, well, I'm a freelancer, but I also
work with agencies as a freelancer.
So do you have any kind of maybe like
tips or tricks for those of us who
kind of straddle the line a little bit?
AmyJune Hineline: Well, no.
'cause you should know, like,
you know, you might have your own
workflow, but again, like working with
agencies is different, you know, and
every agency is a little different.
So learning their workflow, you know,
uh, I think could be more complicated
as a freelancer working with different
organizations, because some people
might name their branches different or
there might be using different local
hosts or they might be using different
version control systems, you know?
So.
I, I think that complicates
being a freelancer when you work
with agencies, because you have
to learn everyone's workflow.
So I don't have any tips
for you except for okay.
Matt Graham: Well, that's fair.
That's fair.
I, you know, I figure
I'd take a shot at it.
Um, yeah.
Cause it's, it's true.
Like you're, you're
you're right on the money.
It's it is the wild west.
And I mean, depending on.
Uh, as a freelancer, depending on how
much time you're given you might be
doing it by the book as, as an agency
would, or you might just be like, oh,
I've got to code this as fast as I can.
So yeah, I mean, it's, it's, uh.
AmyJune Hineline: I think part of it.
That's hard, especially if you've been
a freelancer for so long as you don't
have that accountability with the team.
Right.
So you're like, take those shortcuts
or you name the branch, this
is a branch, or this is a fix.
And I, you know, instead of
like doing your commit messages.
Right.
So, um, there's definitely like
more accountability, you know, when
you're working with a team, I think.
Matt Graham: Yeah, absolutely.
Well, and it's funny too, cause like I've
also been the only developer in an agency.
Uh, and that's almost as much a wild
west as it, uh, as being a freelancer.
So it's kind of a, again, straddling
the line, but, you know, and you
still Git the same kind of thing.
Am I going to do this right?
Or if this do you know, six
days before actually before
I can physically Git it done.
So, um, I think, um, yeah, uh,
yeah, it doesn't seem like we're
Gitting any meeting, any questions.
Um,
Rachel Winchester: Well, I guess I
have a follow-up question to what
you just asked Matt I'm AmyJune.
Do you have any experience, I guess,
uh, consulting and, and helping people
transition from, uh, freelance development
into working for a larger agency?
AmyJune Hineline: No, but I
have experience contributing
back to open source, which is
sort of that same workflow.
You know, we work with others, you
know, of most of the time, when we think
about like contributing back to work,
uh, WordPress, we have the track queue,
which kind of mirrors, agency workflow.
We all work together.
We submit tickets, we're collaborative.
We do merge requests.
We make patches.
So I do have that kind of experience, but,
um, I don't typically, uh, uh, That's like
everyone has their own skills and roles.
Right.
And that's the role of the
technical manager or the technical
project manager, which I am not.
Matt Graham: All right.
Um, well, I guess we'll wrap this up.
Um, I want to thank our sponsors,
uh, for this, for WordFest.
It's Bluehost, Cloudways, GoDaddy
Pro, Nexcess, Yoast, and weglot,
please be sure to visit their
tents and chat with them there.
You might even win a prize.
So don't forget to get your photo
snapped in the photo booth and tweet
it out with the hashtag WordFest Live.
Also thank you to our media
partners and our micro sponsor.
So in the community tent for the next,
uh, 53 minutes, uh, we have Cloudways,
uh, they're delivering launch with words,
tent takeover with Bridget Willard.
Um, so there is a one hour break in
the stage two sec schedule right now.
So head over to the community tent,
we'll be back on the hour at 01:00 UTC.
You make all our Big Orange Hearts full.