Nexcess: Oh, great.
My website crashed again.
I give up, don't give up on your
dreams, Jordan, who are you?
It's me.
You from the future.
Your professional website
is not out of reach.
You just need Nexcess.
With Nexcess managed hosting, you
get lightening pass load times
built-in performance monitoring and
updates, and always awesome support.
24 7 365.
For all your plans.
Whoa.
Yeah.
Weglot: Discover Weglot the simple
translation solution for your website.
All you have to do is add Weglot to
your website, select the languages
that you need, and that's it.
Your website is now available
in multiple languages.
Yoast: Do you know, the Yoast SEO,
plugin, they're red, orange, and
green feedback bullets that help
you optimize your posts for the web.
It runs on millions of websites.
We try to make SEO understandable
and accessible to everyone.
Bluehost: Who says building
an online store has to be hard
with Bluehost website builder.
It's more than just easy.
It's tell us your thing in smart AI.
We'll take it from there.
Easy it's WooCommerce friendly.
So you can add one of these
or swap this for that easy.
It's set up shop in minutes
with unlimited products.
Easy.
Whether you sell boots, books
or bowls, it's create an online
store with Bluehost, easy build
beyond boundaries with Bluehost.
Matt Graham: Hey, when, uh, what do
you get when a Canadian and an American
walk into an Australian themed bar?
Rachel Winchester: Hi, I'm not sure.
Matt Graham: Well, I don't either,
but our next speaker is Amanda Gorman
and she's going to be presenting
chair yoga for remote work.
Amanda helps nonprofits and
wellness based businesses build
thriving online communities as a
customer success manager at GiveWP.
She works diligently each day to assist
nonprofits in growing their communities
and receiving more donations online
to make a bigger impact in the world.
Amanda Gorman: Hello.
Matt Graham: Hello.
Amanda Gorman: How are you?
Matt Graham: Good, you?.
Amanda Gorman: I'm doing well.
Happy to be here.
Matt Graham: Awesome, well take it away.
Amanda Gorman: Awesome.
Sounds good.
Welcome everyone.
I thank you for joining me wherever
you are in the world for a little
bit of time to just slow down.
So that's going to be the
theme for this session today.
Just kind of taking some
time to just be here.
And see what's going on in our bodies,
explore how we're feeling and truly
just take a pause if you're anything
like me, uh, I'm kind of going all the
time, just with all the projects, the
work, the family, all the things, right?
So making pausing and slowing down
a priority can be a challenge.
And that's where for me, my
yoga practice comes into play.
So thank you again for being.
First to get set up.
Uh, you can be in any arrangement
in any form of a chair.
I, it can be a wheelie chair.
It doesn't need to be a chair like mine.
Um, just find a place where
you're going to feel comfortable.
That's the goal.
And I have a blanket underneath my seats.
So if you do have something nearby that
you can prop yourself up a little bit
higher, I find that that helps to allow
yourself to grow tall through the spine.
As you do, come into a seat.
Sometimes our comfortable chairs
tend to let us round in the
low back, uh, which just puts a
little unnecessary pressure here.
So start to find yourself grounding
in your seats, find your feet
on your floor in front of you.
Maybe you scooch forward a little bit in
your chair to really feel yourself not
feeling the temptation of leaning back.
And you're really trying
to activate the muscles.
In the abdomen and the whole
trunk of the body to sit up
as tall as you possibly can.
So the first is bringing awareness
to that height in your spine.
Thinking about maybe a string
from the very top of your
head, pulling yourself up.
Can you find even just a little
bit more space, maybe from the
vertebra in the back of the neck?
To where it meets the base of your neck.
Maybe the shoulders can
relax down into the back.
The hands can find a nice,
comfortable spot to rest.
I'm kind of following that down the
spine where maybe that tricky spot right
between the shoulder blades might find
a little bit more space and into the.
Low back.
I'm just feeling the pelvis resting
firmly on your chair, the legs on
the chair and the feet on the floor.
Stay with that height, that
length that you've created.
Notice where you might be
holding tension in your jaw,
in the space between your eyes.
Maybe take a nice, big exhale out
through the mouth here can make it
really loud and make it audible.
Let the jaw on hinge on the way out.
Let's do that another two times.
Really let the shoulders drop one more.
Allow yourself to just sit in this
space here for a moment to truly
pause, physically stopping our body.
To hopefully allow our mind to catch up
to the pace that we're entering in these
few moments that we'll have together.
I can notice the sounds in your
environment, the temperature of your room.
Tell your close feel against your skin
and the breath moving in your body.
Stay with your breath here.
And then just starting to move some
fingers and toes again, noticing the
sounds in the room that you're in.
And if your eyes were closed, go
ahead and blink them back open.
You can choose to keep your eyes closed.
If you just would like to listen to
my prompts, whatever works for you.
We're just going to start
moving through the neck first.
So we're going to drop our chin
to the chest and not change
anything else about our posture.
We're going to try to keep that
length and not the chin as close
as we can get to the chest.
And we're just going to make little
circles drawing or kind of half circles
rather drawing the chin over to one
shoulder so that you're kind of looking
over that shoulder and bring the
chin back to center and draw it over.
The other shoulder can be really
small movements, especially if the
neck is feeling particularly tight.
Let's do that another
time when you decide,
and as you come to that second side,
pause there and keep turning to look over
that shoulder as if you could line up
your chin and the tip of your shoulder.
Good.
And we're going to come back through
the middle, down, back to the
chest over to that other side and
just pausing as you bring the chin
right over top of the shoulder.
Not trying to hype that
shoulder up higher.
I'm trying to keep it level and
bring the chin back down to send you.
At bringing the chin back
up to neutral and just kinda
shake the shoulders out there.
Might've been some tension growing in
there in between the shoulder blades.
Maybe you hear some nice sounds coming
from moving the shoulders this way.
That's all good.
Go the other direction.
Moving those shoulders and bigs.
Notice which way feels maybe a little
more comfortable than the other.
Good start to let that settle here.
We're going to come back to the neck
here, bringing the chin down to the chest.
And bringing the chin
up towards the ceiling.
And again, trying to keep
your torso, not moving.
We're keeping everything
really stable in our spine.
If you think about drawing the rib
cage in, without talking the tailbone,
drop the chin back down to the chest.
Let's bring the chin back up towards
the ceiling again, and I'm holding
my rib cage here because it kind
of allows me to have a cue to keep
everything in and not back bend here.
Cause that's when I opened my neck,
our lumbar and our cervical spine
are connected and a lot of ways there
are secondary curves that develop.
When we start to walk when we're
just babies and they're supportive
systems for us and they are deeply
connected and we have to uncouple
that connection to really create
segmentation in our spine to physically
slow down the way our body moves.
Let's do just one more like that.
Maybe you go a little bit more deeply in
either direction to see if your range can
expand, then come back, chin to chest.
Once again, this time we're
going to put it all together.
So starting with the chin.
Bringing your chin over to one shoulder.
Like we did originally looking over
that shoulder and then sort of tipping
the head back in that direction to
bring the ear over the shoulder.
But again, trying not to keep
that shoulder from creeping up,
keep it down and slowly, let it
tilt back until it circles all
the way over to the other side.
Where you have your ear kind of
encroaching over that shoulder, as best as
you can turning to look over that shoulder
and bringing the chin back down, let's
go one more direction or one more time.
That direction go slow.
Notice your sticky parts, the spots
that are just kind of like, Ooh,
that doesn't feel normal or familiar.
And if there's a painful spot, you
can certainly skip anything that,
but there's a difference
between discomfort and pain.
As you come, bring that
chin back to the chest.
Go the other direction, drawing
with your chin over the shoulder.
First, looking over the shoulder,
turning the head to bring the ear over
the shoulder, leaning back with the
head, rolling around to the other side.
Have you lost the integrity
of your spine check.
Check-in stay tall.
We're doing two rounds of this.
So maybe you're on your second round.
Finishing up here.
No rush.
Bring it back to center.
And again, I let go of that tension.
You might've been holding
the, keep the torso up.
Just kinda let it go.
Shake the shoulders out, let the
arms be loose with the torso.
Be loose now.
All right.
So just moving the legs around a bit,
we haven't been moving the lower part
of our body a bit yet, so it's kind
of bringing some awareness to the
legs, bring the knees in and out,
and then reground through your feet.
Maybe check in with your seats.
See if you need to readjust.
Find that length through the spine.
Once again, that string pulling you
up as tall as you can be noticing.
If you tend to back then in this position
in draw the front of the rib cage of
these bony sections here in the rib
cage, draw them in towards the back of
the body without talking the tailbone
under, keep a nice curve in your low back.
And then we're going to start to
play with what it feels like to
move this section of the body,
which is notoriously challenging.
So we're going to bring our hands
as best we can to our sides.
Maybe you can reach up to your
rib cage and really feel that
section, or just bring your hands
to your hips or to your waist.
Whatever feels accessible.
We're just going to try to feel
this rib cage reaching over the edge
of your chair and back to center.
And again, over one edge and back,
let's do this a couple times.
It's okay.
If we're not quite feeling it right away,
we're just playing, moving the body.
Check-in that you're breathing,
not holding the breath,
focusing on the movement,
but being in your body in this moment
and exactly what your body needs to
sustain this activity, which is breathing.
Don't stop breathing.
Come back to center and such to
just kind of bring yourself forward.
Now we can kind of bring our hands to
our legs and just feel a little bit of
a back then the chest coming forward.
Right.
And then the opposite action is rounding
through the upper back, trying to
feel like you can collapse through
the collarbones, the chest, maybe the
head even drops tailbone curls under.
And go the opposite action chest
leans forward, maybe chin, chin
lifts, tailbone reaches back again.
Find your range here.
Let's do one more on each director.
And come back to center, we're
going to put it all together.
So open the legs up a little bit wider,
maybe come to the edge of your chair.
So you have a little bit more
room behind you and around you.
So we're gonna start to lean forward in,
start to shimmy our way over to one side
round lean over that chair come forward.
So we're stirring the pot.
I imagine the pot is our pelvis
and the spine is kind of that
ladle in the pot and moving around,
touching every corner of the pot.
Hopefully you're feeling some
things here, waking some things up.
Certainly go the other direction when
you're ready using the hands on the
legs for support and kind of this
resistance tension that you can build
to really just move through the torso.
Keep the lower half in mobile.
Really stationary,
start to finish.
And come back and slow yourself down and
come back to that original position again.
Readjust.
All right.
Now here, bring your hands to your hips
and just start to feel a little tilt
tucking under an untucking of the pelvis.
So tucking under means you're
curling your tailbone underneath
you rounding through the local.
Untucking means we're really
sticking our bottom out.
Kind of feeling that back then,
sensation in the low back.
See if you can come find that position
back and forth and bonus points.
If you can keep your rib cage from
moving very much, can you keep your
upper body still as you move your pelvis?
Not so easy.
But that's what I mean when we talk
about segmentation of the spine,
trying to isolate movement and
every part, every vertebra can move
individually instead of in sections.
All right.
Come back to a more neutral
position in your pelvis.
Notice what that's like and
reground through your feet here.
So what I'm going to start doing with
my feet is coming up onto my toes.
You might not be able to see my toes
quite, but I'm lifting up to lift my
heels up off the floor, coming up onto
my toes, and then coming back down,
flexing my toes up towards the ceiling.
And then again, coming up onto the
toes, lift the heels up, bring the
heels down and lift the toes up.
Really flex them.
Good.
Couple of times like that.
Notice that the whole foot wants to lift
up off the floor when you're trying to
lift your toes to see if you can lift
only your toes when you're flexing
good, come back.
And we're gonna hold here
with our feet on the floor.
Heels on the floor.
Toes lifted.
Keep lifting the toes.
And now can you start to bring your
toes down one at a time from the pinky
side first in, can you do one at a time?
Try that a couple times, trying
to find segmentation in your feet.
It's hard to do both at the
same time, but do your best.
And now try from the big toe.
See if you can put just your big
toe down, lift the other toes up.
And then can the second toe come down
and then the third and so on down
to the pinkies, that's pretty much
impossible for me, but I can pretend,
and it works some serious muscles in
the feet to try to make that happen.
Maybe one day when you're at
the kitchen sink practice.
Good.
All right, let go of
that tension in the feet.
Roll the ankles, roll the
knees around a little bit.
Let that go.
If you want to take a moment to
take a sip of water or anything
that you might need right now,
I'm just going to check our time.
Perfect.
All right.
So kind of moving our
way back up the body.
Now we're going to start to extend one
leg out and flex and point the foot.
Roll the ankle
roll the ankle the other way.
Good.
And then if we would like a little
extra here, we're going to start
to lift the knee up off the floor.
No matter what foot is lifted.
We're just going to try to grab it,
grab the leg, rather, grab the knee.
See if you can hug that knee
in towards your chest while
keeping your spine nice and long.
Like we have been, can you flex the foot?
Spread the toes.
Good.
Hold that.
And I'm going to ask you to press
down through the other foot from.
And imagine you're going to let go of
this leg, but it's not going to going
where this leg is going to stay lifted.
Imagine that that's a reality.
Okay.
So in 3, 2, 1, we're going to let go
see if we're going to hold the leg
up, squeeze it in for another three,
two, and one, go ahead and let it go.
Let the legs come in and
out here for a moment.
All right, we're going to try
the other sides of readjust.
If you need to extend the other
leg and roll or I'm sorry, flexing
point first and roll the foot.
Roll the ankle
rule the other direction.
And then we're going to start to flex
that foot, bring the knee in towards the
chest and hold onto the outside of that.
Like, if that's accessible for
you today, you might also just
pull if that feels better for you.
It's okay.
If we can't grab it and you know where
we're headed, we're going to be pressing
down through that other leg, firmly
lifting through our chest, trying to
stay nice and tall through the spine.
And we're going to imagine we're going
to let go of this leg in three, two,
and actually let go in one, hold it up.
See if you can keep that leg lifted.
See if you can even lift it a little
higher and hold for three, two,
and one, go ahead and let that go.
Shake it out.
Do whatever feels good
to release that tension.
Good ground down through the feet.
Once again.
We're going to start to bring our arms up
towards the back of our head, lifting the
elbows up, interlace the hands in the back
of the head and kind of let the head rest
up against the back of the hands a bit.
Find that length in your spine once more.
And this time we're going to start to
bring one elbow down towards the floor.
And really focusing on opening
up the other side, ribcage.
So not back bending here, but
instead, really side bending,
opening up through the waist,
keep grounded through both feet.
And so to bring it back with control.
And we'll go do the other side.
So dipping that other elbow
down, trying to point the other
elbow up towards the ceiling.
Any amount
notice if your back bending instead of
side bending, keep this in the side.
Good.
Such as slowly come back with.
Dip to the other side, the original side.
Once again, and this time we're going
to point the top elbow forward as if
we're pointing our chest to the floor.
And that top elbow now starts
to become the bottom elbow.
As we rule over to the other side.
Now we're on the opposite side.
Good.
So to pull yourself all the way back up.
Now we're going to drop the
opposite side first, where we just
were go back in that direction.
Doesn't really matter which direction
you're going at the end of the day here.
Just moving the body again, whichever
elbow is on top is now going to start
to point forward in front of you.
So the chest starts to
level out with the ground.
That top elbow is going to start
to become the bottom elbow.
As you got to roll over to the other
side and lift back up, go ahead and
release the arms down and take a moment.
Check in how that's feeling.
I'm finding that height in your spine.
Once more noticing the heartbeat,
the warmth in your body,
if it feels good to you
here, close your eyes.
Really start to tap back into
the pace of your breath without
needing to change it at all.
And even if thoughts arise and take
you somewhere else, just for these last
few moments, stay with your breath.
Choosing to come back again.
And again,
thoughts don't go away.
We just become a little
bit better at observing.
Again, just starting to notice
the sounds in your room,
not as how it feels to be in your body.
When you feel ready to start to move some
fingers and toes eventually blinking your
eyes and coming back into your space.
Just giving yourself a moment to
be grateful for taking a pause for
intentionally taking space in your day.
To be with your body, to be with
your mind and to slow down and
thank you for being at WordFest.
Thank you for being here with me
and I hope to see you again soon.
Thank you.