Yoast: Do you know, the Yoast SEO,
plugin, they're red, orange, and
green feedback bullets that help
you optimize your posts for the web.
It runs on millions of websites.
We tried to make SEO understandable
and accessible to everyone.
Bluehost: Who says building
an online store has to be hard
with Bluehost website builder.
It's more than just easy.
It's tell us your thing in smart AI.
We'll take it from there.
Easy it's WooCommerce friendly.
So you can add one of these
or swap this for that.
It's set up shop in minutes
with unlimited products.
Easy.
Whether you sell boots, books
or bowls, it's create an online
store with Bluehost, easy build
beyond boundaries with Bluehost.
Nexcess: Oh, great.
My website crashed again.
I give up, don't give up on your
dreams, Jordan, who are you?
It's me.
You from the future.
Your professional website
is not out of reach.
You just need the Nexcess.
With Nexcess managed hosting, you
get lightning Paslode times built
and performance monitoring and
updates, and always awesome support.
24 7 365.
For all your props.
Whoa.
Yeah.
Weglot: Discover Weglot the simple
translation solution for your website.
All you have to do is add
Weglot to your website, select
the languages that you need.
And that's it.
Your website is now available
in multiple languages.
Matt Graham: Welcome back
to WordFest, stage two.
Uh, they say that lightning
does not strike twice.
Well, I beg to differ because we have two
lightning talks that are coming up next.
Uh, so we're going to watch them both
and then we'll do a live Q and A with
the presenters after we've watched them.
But first up is Rick Alday, uh,
with dealing with the emotional
impact of customer facing roles.
So Rick has been a graphic designer and
a photographer, but for the past decade,
he's worked in customer service roles
for different companies in the WordPress
industry and is currently with GiveWP.
So we'll see that video in a few seconds.
Rick Alday: My name is Rick Alday.
I'm a support technician at GiveWP.
For those of you who don't know what
GiveWP is, is just one of the best, uh,
WordPress donation plug-ins out there.
That's my bias opinion.
And for the last 12 years or so, I have
been doing either tech support or customer
service, uh, roles in the WordPress
ecosystem for different companies.
Before that I did freelance
photography and graphic design.
So for the, a good 20 years of my
life, I've been doing, uh, dealing with
customers, uh, in one way or another.
And I know from experience,
this can take an emotional and
mental and physical toll on you.
So I'm going to be sharing some of the
tips and tricks and procedures that I
use and learn throughout my, my career to
deal with some of that and minimize the
impact that it will have on your life.
Um, Stress is a part of our daily life.
You know, a certain amount of stress
is helpful for us to accomplish
our goals, uh, get through everyday
challenges, but just like cholesterol,
there's, there's good and bad stress.
And the bad stress is really
harmful or your body or your health
or your mental health and job
related stress is not different.
All jobs are inherently stressful.
One way to.
But some more than others.
And I believe, uh, dealing with
customers is on the top level, right
there, you know, most stressful jobs.
And, um, as customer service
agents, we are often under extreme
pressure to, um, you know, deliver
and deal with complex issues.
We are usually the first point of contact
of customers with, uh, with the company.
So.
And customers don't usually reach out to
the company and that they have a problem.
And again, that sets the, the precedents
or the, uh, tone of the interaction
you're going to have with that customer.
And it's our job to turn that around.
There are plenty of great customers,
service agents out there, and no
matter how many years you've done this,
it's still can be a bit stressful.
How do we deal with this?
The approach we need to take to deal
with job related stress has, uh, two
components, uh, things that you do at
work and things that you do out of work.
That's first start reviewing
your work area, check your desk.
Is it comfortable?
Do you have pictures that cheer you up
pictures of your family, of your pet?
Can you look out the
window and see nature?
You know, is it organized
or do you have a big.
Is your chair comfortable?
Do you have good lightning?
Uh, do you have a plant maybe, uh,
you know, you need to work on your
work environment, your desk, your
office, it has to be comfortable.
This is where you're going to spend a good
chunk of your day over your reward days.
So make sure it has a nice atmosphere
and that's something you can control at
some point, you know, if you work for.
You can set up a small space where you
are, it's your space, you know, it's
your workspace, it's your dedicated
space for work as nothing else, you
know, just your computer, maybe,
you know, printer, if you need it.
And just the basic stuff that
you need to work and things that,
you know, make it look nice, make
it, makes it comfortable for you.
Um, I know this is difficult.
If you live in a small apartment or
if you share your, your house or your
apartment with other people you have,
if you have family or pets, it can be
a challenge, but it's not impossible.
So make sure your, your work
environment is as comfortable as it
can possibly be for you to spend,
you know, eight hours a day there.
Next, when you do start work, um, start.
Easier.
And what I mean, my dad is, uh,
start with things that required a
little mental energy and GiveWP.
We have something called a mental
energy kickoff or Mico acronym, M E K O.
And basically what this means is that
we start the day with a task that
requires a little mental need, mental
energy from our part, you know, it can
be answering, um, emails, um, Uh, taking
notes, um, reviewing your documentation,
et cetera, something that, you know,
you, you, you know, it's not gonna
take a long time and it's not going
to stress you out and start with that.
And then you can jump right into
the fire next stick, small breaks
every hour or every 40 minutes.
Step away from your computer.
Go, go for a.
Go for a glass of water, you know,
stretch out, do some breathing exercises.
You can find some great breathing
exercises on YouTube that will only
take one or two minutes and breathing
exercises will help you regulate your
heart rate to if you are person who
suffers from anxiety or, you know yeah.
It'll help you calm down and just.
Relax, what a bit, eh, you need
to do that throughout the day.
You know, it helps you also clear
your mind and kind of reset your,
your mental energy a bit, so
you can continue your Workday.
It's very important
that you do that again.
Just five minutes, 10 minutes stops
and you go back to work refresh.
It really helps.
Next thing you want to
do is avoid multitasking.
You know, I know this is, uh, some people
consider this an asset, but not, I'm not
going to agree with that in my experience.
Multitasking just wears you out really
quickly and physically and mentally.
I know, I know every job has
a different tasks that you
need to accomplish every day.
That's.
What I mean is that you need to
break those tasks into chunks.
For example, I'm going to set up,
uh, I'm going to work on email
for 20 minutes and just email.
I'm not going to do every, anything else.
Uh, and after that, I'm
going to spend 30 minutes.
I don't know, writing that documentation.
All right.
So I'm just going to
concentrate on that and then.
You know, and the next 40 minutes
I'll do something else, but
you know, just that one task.
And that way I can cover all the tasks
that I need to cover throughout the
day, but I have to do them all at once.
Now, again, do this as much as possibly,
you know, you can, I know that if you
work from home, there are distractions.
If you have family in small kids,
it's almost, you know, you're going
to get interrupted quite a bit.
I know from experience that.
And just the job.
Sometimes you need to like, stop
doing what you're doing and you need
to take care of something that's,
uh, you know, origin or really
important and it needs to be done.
So I understand that sometimes you
cannot avoid multitasking 100%, but
try to do that as much as you can.
And, you know, uh, this apply,
it goes to your breaks to.
when you go, take your lunch break.
You're taking your lunch break Dawn,
you know, don't check your notification
from work, uh, try to put your phone
away and just enjoy your lunch.
And if you're, you know, taking a lunch
with a friend or family, just spend some
time with them, concentrate on that, you
know, don't check your phone, doesn't
wander off, you know, or think about work.
Just turn off your work
mode and enjoy your life.
When I rude customer comes along
and they often do, they come with
insults, they come with complaints.
They're really frustrated.
And what you need to do first
is don't take it personally.
I know from experience by
instinct, we take it personally.
We take it very, you know,
to heart, any insults or.
Whatever, um, problem is the, the
client comes with, but just agree time
to step away a minute or two breeth
you know, calm down, never reply
it to a customer when you're mad.
Never do that.
It's just that, you know, they, they
would, the good book says on Proverbs
says a gentle answer, turns away
wrath, but a harsh word stirs up anger.
For any situation you don't
fight, fight fire with fire.
You want to calm down and be the,
the better person and try to ignore
any insults, trying to ignore any
put downs, just work through your
way around, uh, trying to figure
out what's really behind that anger.
What's frustrating to the customer.
Try to put yourself in their shoes.
What are they experiencing?
That's got them so frustrated
and what you do about it.
Can you solve it in your hands?
Not, you know, be as polite as
possible and just let them know that.
And if you need to, you can scale
that, escalate that to a supervisor.
Sometimes you don't need to deal with,
uh, customers, you know, supervisors have
the authority to maybe fire the customers.
They are, they're being really rude.
So yeah.
Talk to a supervisor to talk
to our coworkers, don't handle
angry customers yourself.
You don't need to ask for help.
There's nothing wrong with that.
No snacks.
Uh, another tip that you know, really
works right, is listening to music.
I know this is cliche.
Everyone says, you know,
you're going to listen to.
Calm music or whatever, but, you
know, whatever music suits you, you
feel like, you know, heavy metal
and head back to what you're doing.
That's fine.
Just be mindful.
Your coworkers, you, you know, working
at share office, you know, put your
headphones on and, and jam away, you
know, if you like jazz or whatever,
something that really helps you, uh, hypes
you up and doesn't interfere with the.
Go ahead and do that, uh, on a tip,
do not procrastinate on difficult
tasks or tests that you don't like.
We all have that one thing that
we don't like to do at work.
You know, we don't like it as much.
It's not our favorite thing,
but it has to be done.
And our tendency is to put it off,
you know, kick the can down the road
every day until the deadline of.
And now we're really stressed out because
we get to do it and it has to be done.
And, and we haven't even started yet.
So try to set up a time, you know,
uh, small, uh, time chunks of 10 to
15 minutes every day to tackle that,
uh, tasks that you are trying to
avoid that way, you know, 10 minutes
a day, by the end of the week, you
will have worked on it almost an hour.
And that's pretty good, you know?
But if you can do that, you know, can
set up more time to do that, go ahead
and do that, but do not procrastinate.
You know, eventually all tasks
will accumulate and that's
in the back of your mind.
You're thinking about that and
you're stressing out and you're
stressing out and that's not good.
Um, and another thing similar to
mental energy kickoff, you want to
decompress at the end of the day.
Uh, it's similar to, you know,
starting your day with a task that
requires a little mental energy.
Try to end your day with,
uh, doing similar tasks.
Uh, it could be just, you know,
10, 15 minutes before your shift,
just, you know, stop doing the hard
things and do the easier things.
You know, you can maybe write
up some notes, um, write some
more emails that require.
No research, um, read your docs again.
I don't know, thinks that, you know, you
know that your job will require a little
mental energy and finally end your day.
When you log off from
work, really do that.
You know, don't have a work
email installed on your phone.
Uh, don't have slack related,
uh, work groups in, in your
fall and things like that.
Um, just take time for you, you
know, you out of work, you've done
a great job and you know, you're
excellent, but now it's your time.
It's your family time.
It's time to do something else on a
personal level, you have to disconnect.
Um, again, set up a time to
really disconnect from internet,
really social media, uh, Do not
look at a screen for a good hour.
So if you have a hobby,
go ahead and do that.
If you work out, go ahead and do that.
You know, spend time with your family,
read a book, something that gets you away
from any screen really helps you out with
your mental energy and your mental health.
You know, especially at night, you don't
want to be checking your pond, you know,
on your bet before you go to sleep.
Um, It will helps you out.
You know, you have to step
away from any screen because
it also affects your vision.
It affects your, um, mental health
and, um, it'll eventually add up
to the next day and the next day.
So take an hour or so every
day to just disconnect from
everything and enjoy nature.
Can.
And you, your family and your hobbies
and, and your, your life, it's your time.
Another thing I want to point out
is that you need to encourage a work
stress discussion at the workplace.
And, um, I don't know if
your award allows for this.
You have, if you slack, or
if you use email or whatever,
but be able to communicate.
With your coworkers, with their
supervisors, um, about stressful
situations at job at your job
and how you can deal with that.
Uh, what can you do to minimize,
you know, stressful situations?
Because it, it, it doesn't, it, it
doesn't just help be you as an employee.
It helps them as an employer, you know,
um, according to study in the UK, Uh,
businesses are important to lose around
37 billion pounds, British pounds
every year and poor customer service.
And based on their, in that research,
uh, 73% of consumers are reported
to select a company or product
based on friendly employees or
customer service representatives.
So this is where a happy employee
can make a big difference in
terms of, or of sales and revenue.
You know, like I said, in the
beginning, all jobs are somewhat
stressful and people are different.
We all handle stress differently.
We'll have personal, uh, issues
that we have to deal with every day.
And that, you know, it's
another variable movie.
Our employers cannot control
that, but there are things that
can be, you know, minimize.
Done differently at work
that could minimize just
general stress for all of us.
So I'll be sure to talk to your
supervisors, your higher ups
and, um, if your company is not
open to that, maybe it's time to
look somewhere else, you know?
Um, sadly, uh, but it is
your health after all.
So be sure to take care of it and.
That's pretty much it.
And, you know, uh, just wanted to
share that as a side note, that I also,
uh, dealt with depression and anxiety
for many years of my life, and I've
applied these dips to my personal life
and they've really helped me out, you
know, um, at the end of the day, you
need to take care of yourself too.
You need to eat healthy.
You need to get out.
I sleep in that's really important.
Take care of your physical health too,
because that will also affect your mental
health obviously, and ticket one day
at a time, you know, don't quit smoking
culture keyed on, you know, stopping
carbs, cold Turkey that doesn't work.
It's one step at a time.
You are not alone.
If you need help, definitely
reach out friends, family, um,
open to, uh, messages, Sue.
Um, I don't tweet much, but I, you
know, you can reach out to me and
share your experiences, say hi or
prayer request and you know, whatever.
Uh, I'm good.
Uh, and I'll be happy to share
on a more personal level.
My experiences.
Uh, things that I do on everyday
basis to deal with that again, it's
your mental health take care of it.
Take care.
Bye.
Matt Graham: Welcome back.
So we have, uh, both Nate and Rick
here to answer your questions.
Nate Finch: Hello.
Matt Graham: Awesome talks.
If they hit, they hit a chord,
obviously different courts with meaning.
Um, the last, uh, last eight months,
I've been kind of going through a tough
time with, uh, with my mental health,
but I was playing around with headless
WordPress, probably I wanna say six years.
I actually did it.
I actually did a talk, uh, in,
um, we're, uh, WordCamp Hamilton
about, uh, about doing a.
Um, using WordPress as like an
app development, uh, framework.
So yeah, what you're talking
about is really cool.
Yeah.
Nate Finch: That's fun, man.
That's a bit about too in that, uh,
uh, we're using WordPress for web apps
book came out, actually, I'm trying to
remember the guys at WebDev Studioes
Matt Graham: I haven't actually had
a chance to read that one over yet.
Rachel Winchester: I have a
question about how you first, uh,
I guess, got into JAMstack and
building static WordPress sites.
And really like when that
moment for you, when it clicked
that this is the way to build.
Nate Finch: Yeah, that's a great question.
Um, I think for me, at least I think
it's different for everybody, but when
you see, I think like, I don't know, I
grabbed a Gatsby theme first starter.
It wasn't a few, it was,
it started as before.
And it's like, you know, you, I think
you've just come out of, and they had
like the, uh, WordPress course, it
was really just like plug and go and
how easy it was to like get started.
Kind of get it going well, I don't know.
Easiest relative term.
Absolutely.
Um, so back it up a little bit
there, but like Netlify had their
free hosting still does, like
my personal site is still there.
And so you just like deploy it
and you're like, oh, that's there.
And it's just pulling all
this information from my site.
Well, that's cool.
And so the tools are there, you know, so I
think it was just like, kind of the right
moment when Gatsby kind of came along
and, uh, Netlify came along to really
have, uh, an easy way to get that up.
So I know there's other solutions now,
uh, through Vercel, through Strattic,
through all sorts of like headless options
and stuff like that and static options.
And everything's.
Yeah, but I think for me, it was
just like seeing the speed and, you
know, Gatsby has the, um, what is it
called where you hover over a link
and it like, pre-loads the page.
So it was just like, just so fast
and the images look so crisp and
clean and there's just so little
that you have to do or whatever.
So, yeah, I was like, this is cool.
That was great.
Rachel Winchester: Nice.
I been getting into
JAMstack about a year now.
Um, but not as a developer WordPress,
um, and while getting into it, I've
been listening to so much heavy metal.
So I like how Rick.
To heavy metal and that people can
listen to whatever music that you like.
So I'm curious, what kind of music
do you listen to throughout your day?
What do you like to work to?
Rick Alday: Oh man, like my music
taste is really all over the place
and um, you know, I, I can share
some way in my playlist and some
of them I'd rather than that, but
yeah, I mean, I just listened to.
Well, I'm working at drink to loosen,
to like some like low-fi music.
Uh, but again, it depends on
my mood and what I'm doing.
Uh, I definitely, you know, head
bang sometimes, and I have my
kid like working next to me.
She's taking a homeschool at moments,
or I cannot put out my music too loud.
I use my headphones and, but, um,
yeah, I mean, It depends on my mood.
So it varies quite a bit.
Matt Graham: Yeah.
So I guess speaking of variability,
what is that one thing that
you need to do every day to.
Yourself, like I want to stay sane,
but really the, the thing is focused.
What is that one thing
that you always need to do?
Rick Alday: Okay.
Um, what works for me is
taking a lot of breaks.
Like a lot of five minute breaks,
every 40 minutes every hour.
I need to just step out of the office and.
I just, just go, ah, what
are my plants and our yard?
And that's like, what I like to do.
I like to do gardening on my time
off and that just like completely,
completely just takes me away.
Any, uh, anything I'm working on online?
So, uh, one of my coworkers,
he lives in the near the woods.
He has like a large
property in South Carolina.
So, you know, he, he almost with the,
like coming to slack, I'm going to take
a walk in the woods and that was for him.
And so, yeah, but that's
something I need to do.
I need to go outside and look at
green style, look at plants, look
a flower, you know, But I do.
Rachel Winchester: Yeah.
I definitely understand that.
I think, uh, well, I don't know where,
where everyone's located in the world,
but where I am in the winter, you can't
get too much sunlight during the day.
So I have to leave and go outside
during lunch to even, get some sunlight.
Um, so yeah, I definitely, I definitely
feel that, um, going outside during
your work day and making a point of it.
Rick Alday: And just because I dunno, I
guess most of us work, you know, we're
sitting down all day, you know, working.
So just getting up, even getting,
you know, grabbing a cup of coffee
or just walking around like five
minutes, it really, you know, helps
you out with your back pain and,
you know, physically, mentally, it
just kind of resets you a little.
Rachel Winchester: Yeah, unless
you're too excited about the
develops develop the WordPress
static site that you're developing.
Nate Finch: I was actually the,
Matt Graham: yeah, that's the
question I wanted to ask you, Nate.
So I I'm a developer.
And I ha I feel like it could, I
don't know what it is, but I have this
rollercoaster of this is so cool too.
I hate this.
How do you go into that?
Nate Finch: Oh man.
Well, yeah.
And it's, it's also, you know, a
thing of like, oh, this is only
going to take me five more minutes.
I know.
And then five hours later,
you didn't go outside.
You didn't take your walk.
You didn't, you know, like say hi
to your family or something, working
at home or whatever and all that.
Um, yeah.
I don't know.
I'm still trying to figure that out
sometimes because I know that I'll,
you know, if I could I'd work like
all day and all night, and I just love
figuring all this stuff out is one of the
things I love about development, right.
Is that you're solving problems, like
figuring out puzzles and stuff like that.
So, um, yeah.
How do you deal with that?
I think like part of it is like, You know,
setting a timer for things, for sure.
Kind of like Rick was talking about,
you know, um, I think the other side
of it too, is to have multiple things
that you're trying to figure out, um,
that you're, or that, and if you have
other tasks you need to be doing that,
you're like, okay, I can only spend
like 30 more minutes on this before
I have to move on to something else.
And for me to like part, I was a
freelancer for, you know, six, seven
years or whatever, and joining a team,
uh, whether it's at a design agency
or now like Strattic where we're a
hosting company, um, You know, having
other people around you that have
those like have skills or can be your
rubber duck or, um, give you insight
and stuff like that to all that.
Like, if you can just like talk to
the people, like again, requisites
so much great advice, Rick,
that, uh, uh, it's super helpful.
Just feel like, figure those things
out and get unblocked and move forward.
You know, team like the sum, the total is
greater than the sum of its parts, right?
Yeah.
Matt Graham: Um, no, actually, uh,
AmyJune, which was one of the, uh, one of
the speakers earlier, uh, posted the, um,
the, from the developer Twitter account.
It's like, this'll just
be the five minutes fix.
Nate Finch: Yeah.
Five minute fixes every day.
Matt Graham: Yeah.
Right, exactly.
Right, right.
Exactly.
That's that's well, that's the limit
because if you go above that, then you
know, it ends up being an eight hour fix.
Rachel Winchester: Well, I, I
guess I have one more question.
Um, I'm curious, uh, w w with who
you deal with that at your job, um,
do people come to you excited about
static or do you have to convince them.
Nate Finch: Yeah.
So a lot of the folks that come to
Strattic are, you know, mid-size or
enterprise level folks that have been
running WordPress for years, and they
have worked on other hosting platforms
with their hosting companies and they
there's like this kind of sweet spot
sweet spotat Strattic where we can
take your WordPress site as it is and
make it static and then put that out.
And we also like build in these
serverless integrations, like for gravity
forms or contact form seven, or need
WordPress search or the list goes on.
Right.
Um, but they have been.
I told that if they want to do
something static, something fast and
scalable and secure that they need
to rebuild their site and stuff.
Well, you know, they've spent years on
this or, you know, tens of thousands
of dollars or hundreds of thousands of
people, hours or whatever on the site that
they have in the set up that they have.
And their marketers love it.
Their SEO, few people love it.
Their content writers love it.
They don't want to switch.
You know, a non WordPress
platform or whatever.
Uh, and they don't want to have like a
deployment, like a, uh, a build process
necessarily where they have everything
he coupled where there's like, you
know, next she has her Gatsby on the
front end and WordPress on the backend.
And they're still dealing with that
security then too, because they
still have their WordPress site
up and it could still be taxed.
The folks that come to us are
basically saying like, Hey, when
you shut down WordPress, that means
that our WordPress can't be hacked.
That's great.
And then you have all these awesome
integrations and stuff that other hosting
static hosting platforms or a static kind
of integrations don't have out of the box.
Like I said to the PML for like one
multinational site and stuff like that.
So those are the kinds of things
that are like really important and
like the headache, like we were
just talking with somebody else who
was like, you know, you all have.
Not to say that we cost somebody
their job or whatever, but it's like,
you know, if we were doing what we
were doing before we came to strata,
we'd still have another person and a
half or something like that on staff.
That's just, just watching our site.
Right.
Like they're not doing anything
productive or whatever, they're just
trying to help us with the thing.
So, yeah.
So yeah, it's, it's cool.
That's kind of the same story,
uh, you know, two dozen different
ways and stuff like that.
Uh, come on.
Rachel Winchester: Yeah.
Yeah.
I'm very interested in, in, in,
um, how people are transitioning,
because I know it's, it's, it's
kind of new or it's coming back.
Um, but it keeps trying to, uh,
to, to, you know, get even more
popular, which is really interesting.
Nate Finch: Yeah.
Right.
Yeah.
Everything's uh, that was old is
new again or something like that.
Right.
So.
Matt Graham: All right.
Well, thank you gentlemen, for, uh,
for being able to be part of our
Q and A I'd like to also thank our
sponsors, Bluehost, Cloudways, GoDaddy
Pro, Nexcess, Yoast and Weglot.
Please be sure to visit their
tents and chat with them and
you might even win some prizes.
So don't forget to get your photo snapped
in photo booth as well, and tweet it out
with the hashtag word, WordFest Live.
Also thank you to our media
partners and our micro sponsor.
Uh, right now in the community
tent, uh Cloudways or sorry,
that's in the next hour.
Cloudways is, will have
their hourly giveaway.
There is a, uh, well, it's
probably only about a nine minute
break in the schedule right now.
Uh, so head on over to the community tent
and we will be back in nine minutes with,
uh, starting off at the Asian continent.
You all make our Big Orange Hearts full.