Yoast: Do you know, the Yoast SEO,
plugin, they're red, orange, and
green feedback bullets that help
you optimize your posts for the web.
It runs on millions of websites.
We tried to make SEO understandable
and accessible to everyone.
Nexcess: Oh great.
My website crashed.
I give up.
Don't give up on your dreams.
Jordan, who are you?
It's me.
You from the future.
Your professional website
is not at a reach.
You just need Nexcess.
With Nexcess managed hosting, you
get lightening fast load times
built-in performance monitoring and
updates, and always awesome support.
24 7 365 for all your projects.
Whoa.
Yeah.
Weglot: Discover Weglot the simple
translation solution for your website.
All you have to do is add Weglot to
your website, select the languages
that you need, and that's it.
Your website is now available
in multiple languages
Bluehost: Who says building
an online store has to be
hard with Bluehost website.
It's more than just easy.
It's tell us your thing and smart AI.
We'll take it from there.
Easy it's WooCommerce friendly.
So you can add one of these,
or swap this for that easy.
It's set up shop in minutes
with unlimited products.
Easy.
Whether you sell boots, books
or bowls, it's create an online
store with Bluehost, easy build
beyond boundaries with Bluehost.
Matt Graham: Welcome back
to WordFest, stage two.
Uh, they say that lightening
does not strike twice.
Well, I beg to differ because we have two
lightning talks that are coming up next.
Uh, so we're going to watch both and
then we'll do a live Q and A with the
presenters after we've watched them both
Rachel Winchester: So next you'll
see Nate Finch with, Wait, wuuut?
Where did my CMS go?.
Nate has been working
on the web since 2011.
He loves web development because
the perfect mix of problem solving,
helping people and lifelong learning
as a senior WordPress engineer
https://strata.com, he helps build
serverless serverless integrations for
WordPress prior to joining Strattic.
Nate worked as VP of development at
thedigitalring.com where he spent
his time, uh, between where he
split his time between developing
websites and developing developers.
He spent the bulk of his career,
freelancing working with hundreds
of clients through platforms like
top tout, top tile and codeable,
and has even completed a brief
stint as a web engineer with 10up.
Nate collects master's degrees has
traveled to six continents, lived on
four, speak Spanish and outside of
work, family, friends, food, coffee,
and cooking are his favorite activities.
He lives in Wisconsin with his
wonderful wife and two daughters.
Nate Finch: Okay, welcome to Wait, wuuut?
Where did my CMS go?
This is about adventures in
building a WordPress experience.
Even when WordPress isn't available.
You know, your clients or your customers
have gone jammy, let's say when you
hear things like we sell products,
why isn't our checkout working?
We use admin Ajax.
Why doesn't that work?
My search box, just
redirects to the homepage.
Our forms don't submit anymore.
My regex redirects.
Aren't redirecting our SEO tanked.
What's going on.
I thought all of this JAMstack
stuff was supposed to help.
Wait, why can't we fill in the blank?
Why can't we do this?
So, what are we talking about?
We're talking about static, WordPress,
headless, WordPress, decoupled, WordPress
JAMstack, WordPress, serverless,
WordPress hexagonal, and content
mesh and all of this other stuff.
Why do we even do this to ourselves?
Right.
Why do our customers ask for this?
Why do our clients ask for this?
Basically, we all want simplicity.
We all want speed.
We all want security and scalability
and probably a lot of other S words.
The way that we can get a lot
of this is through things like
decoupled or static or JAMstack.
WordPress or websites or web
application implementations.
Right.
They just want to know that
their site basically, isn't
going to fall over, get hacked.
They want to keep things
simple on their end.
They just, they just want
all of these us words.
Right?
How do we get these things?
There's, there's a lot of talk
about where we want to go static,
or we want to go head less or we
want to implement a jam stack.
Solution.
What, what are, what
are the solutions here?
So some folks so that some
providers are going to tell you,
Hey, don't worry about any of that.
You can just go static or
decoupled, headless real easily.
All you have to do is replace
all your plugins, your theme, et
cetera, with their party services.
And we'll start it guys, your
site, your contact forums, probably
aren't going to work your search.
Isn't going to work.
You're going to have to implement a
third party comment solution, et cetera.
But you know, it'll be fine.
Or somebody is going to say,
Hey, don't even worry about it.
Just hire yourself a modern Java.
Okay, probably react developer
team to build you a headless
JAMstack decoupled, static, cool
application set up a CICT process.
Get yourself multiple environments.
Use our proprietary thingamajig
use, get for version control and
deployments and refactor your
WordPress beyond recognition.
So what the heck?
These aren't great options necessarily.
And I'm not saying that these are
bad solutions, but they just might
not be for every customer or client.
So when you're thinking about your
clients and your customers, what
are some good solutions for them?
In this whole JAMstack'y world.
Right?
So let's define some terms, right?
Let's look at headless decoupled,
static, and serverless and
see what this is all about.
Okay.
So what are we even talking about here?
This is a massive diagram that just
shows a bunch of overlap of all
these JAMstack terms that we're
talking about and throwing around.
Right.
So why are we.
Kind of presenting this
high level overview, right?
This is a quote.
I really like your problem.
Isn't the problem.
Your problem is how to
think about the problem.
What we're doing here is just
getting ourselves a vocabulary,
getting ourselves a mental image
of what we're talking about here.
So hopefully this will all just help
you think about how you can implement
these solutions and when, and what
are the best solutions for you and
your clients to be implementing.
So let's define some terms.
Static is anything that can
be served from the CDN, right?
So you got your HTML and
your CSS and your JavaScript.
These types of files can
be served from a CDN.
The headless approach is something
that uses WordPress as a CMS,
but has a custom front end.
So it's probably JavaScript
and it's not a classic theme.
Like we think of in the sense of
like the template hierarchy, right.
And all of these PHP files.
Decoupled is going to be
something like the content mesh.
This is a term that gets be coined
and that uses multiple services,
multiple API APIs, and it takes
the idea and the approach of
using the best tool for the job.
Serverless is custom on demand,
scalable functions and services
that provide a dynamic experience.
So this is where, you know, the
whole that the, there is no cloud.
It's somebody else's computer.
This is where you're using.
On-demand kind of ad hoc functions as you
need them for as long as you need them.
This is something that
can be very scalable.
Be ready to go in an instant for you.
And then finally, JAMstack this term is
basically in my view, a philosophy and
approach to building sites and apps.
It's not an actual stack.
Like we think of the LAMP or the
LIMP stack or the MEAN stack or the
MERN stack or whatever other stack.
It's definitely more of an idea of how
to approach building websites, right?
With JavaScript, API and markup.
What are your options?
Let's go through and look at
a few different options here
for each of these, right?
So if.
Talking about static.
Basically the idea there is that
there is no WordPress, right.
There is no spoon WordPress isn't there.
You're just serving up HTML,
CSS and JavaScript files.
So WordPress could be used to load and
scrape the content, but it's not going
to be available for you to use on like an
admin Ajax query or something like that.
So you might also be able to use
classic plugins and themes with this,
but they may not work in a static
environment if they require real-time
PHP in real time, server and database.
Interactivity.
So things like search forums WooCommerce,
uh, learning management systems,
membership sites are probably not
going to work out of the box like
they would with regular WordPress.
And you could see these kinds of things,
uh, with like WP Static or Shifter or
some, some other providers or services
that make your WordPress sites static.
So with headless, you're going to
be using something probably like
Gatsby or Next or Frontity, something
maybe like Grid Some, Eleventy,
anything like that on your front end.
And WordPress is still probably
available for the front end to access.
So that means something like your
front end is going to live at something
like example.com, but your WordPress,
your actual WordPress install is gonna
be let's say at wp.example.com or
somewhere else completely different.
So you still get a lot of speed and
scalability without the theme or plugin
load if your WordPress site, or if
your WordPress, I should say is still
available to the public though, uh,
people can follow those API requests
that a headless site is making and still
try to get into your WordPress site.
That's okay though.
Uh, we'll talk about other
solutions for that later.
So this might require a build and that
could be a very short process, or it
could be a very long process, or you could
have an incremental build system set up.
You're also going to be able to
model data from things like custom
post types are built in post types,
advanced custom fields, and even
blocks plugins may still work as well.
That actually load things into your HTML
or that you are calling an end point for.
And then even a rest API end points.
WordPress and WP GraphQL
could also work for you there.
Examples would be the Rudy's dot com site.
That there's been a couple
of case studies on that.
And then as far as I understand that
WP Engine's Atlas, the idea of Atlas
is built on this kind of idea as
well as like a headless implement.
Now we have decoupled.
So what is decoupled?
So the idea here is, like I was saying,
you're combining a lot of different
API APIs with this content mesh idea.
So there's other structured
content or other data coming
in besides just WordPress data
or just coming from WordPress.
Right.
So you can use other services for forms.
Uh, e-commerce and stuff like that.
You can use a CRM or anything like that.
You might already be doing something like
this, honestly, with things like MailChimp
or HubSpot, Shopify, uh, et cetera.
That's the idea is like you are using
these best of breed services for
your, uh, for your website, right?
So you might be pulling in like
this whole mesh of things already.
So examples of this, sometimes we don't
actually know what they are, especially
if they have a decoupled front end.
So things like NPM js.org, which
were, it was a human-made project.
Couldn't pull in things from WordPress,
but also things from the NPM repository.
And you can see that these decoupled
architectures allow for a lot of
different, uh, poll and stuff.
And this is just a, the visual,
there is just a list of a bunch of.
Decoupled CMS says that you could use.
So last thing to talk about is serverless
and it's probably serverless plus static,
but you also see serverless services that
include a traditional WordPress site.
So let's look at that.
So you use WordPress in this sense
for content management and then maybe.
The site static and shut down WordPress.
This is actually what we
do on Strattic, right?
So you can use these serverless
services to make your WordPress sites
static and then shut down WordPress.
Then on top of that, because
you have access to all of these
serverless services, things like
AWS Lambda or Google, Google cloud
functions and stuff like that.
Um, and then also real time databases
available, uh, to these that are kind
of serverless and scale really well.
You can create services
to maintain as much.
WordPress functionality as possible.
So you can build services for forms,
submissions, search, SEO, media, and
email offloads, multiple language stuff,
like, you know, WPML to where you can
actually support that kind of thing.
You can also run a lot of optimizations,
like minifying code cache, optimizing.
Running things on a CDN, et cetera.
So examples of this are any site
that's run on static.com and plugins
like delicious brains offload suite.
So they're Offload S3
in their offload emails.
And then also things like
using Netlify functions.
Right?
So if you have a site on Netlify,
you're also potentially using
their Netlify functions to.
You know, handle API keys
or something like that.
So that's actually, like I said, what we
do at Strattic, where we build out static
first serverless WordPress integration.
So you don't actually have to
completely rebuild your site.
Of course, if you want
to, uh, you can do that.
Definitely get some advice.
And if you have any questions about
doing that, feel free to hit me up.
So what should I do?
What should you do?
What should we do for ourselves
when we're building our own personal
projects and which we do for clients
and customers and enterprise level
customers and everything like that?
The first thing that we want
to do is really have a mind
shift in paradigm shift, right?
We want to change the thought process
around building for WordPress and what's
possible for clients and everything.
The expansion of what's
possible is really, really cool.
We've talked about a lot of tools
that are just getting better.
A lot of frameworks, a lot of services
that are just getting better for
what we can build for ourselves
and for clients and customers.
This also creates a virtuous cycle, right?
Uh, basically one of the things that
I like to say is the more WordPress
experience we support, the more we're able
to support other WordPress experiences.
Right?
So for example, if you build.
Um, you know, a demo site or something
like that, a proof of concept, and
you've got your headless site running
a, an XJS, you know, app, and then
it's hosted on Netlify and then you
have to figure out how to implement,
uh, gravity forms for a decoupled or
headless WordPress implementation.
Once you figure that.
You are thinking, probably going to think
to yourself, holy cow, I can do this for
a bunch of other services, a bunch of
other types of plugins that, you know,
we can go ahead and use these kinds of
processes and serverless functions for.
So what we also see here is that
we ended up building more resilient
platforms when we start to employ these
kinds of tools at our disposal, right?
Whether we are building something
that's headless or static or.
Decoupled or kind of full
on serverless, right?
We have a more resilient platform
and charity majors have this great
quote on a podcast recently that
resiliency and reliability is not
about making your systems never fail.
It's about making them resilient
to lots of failures, right?
I usually like to say like, Hey,
we were on the internet and like,
nothing is a hundred percent.
So as we build things out and make
things more resilient and we offer
and cover more WordPress experience
right on these different, you know,
decoupled or serverless, uh, instances
or, uh, platforms and stuff like
that, then we're able to make sure
that the sites and applications
that we run don't fall over as much.
Right.
We're able to scale.
Uh, further, we're able to be
more secure, less vulnerable to
attacks and things like that.
So, uh, the more that we do this
kind of stuff, the more resilient
our platforms and our sites become.
So you might be saying, hold on,
just, just wait a second here.
This all sounds really great and
everything, and we could do all of this.
Right.
Um, but should we do that?
The good old Jeff Goldbloom
quote from Jurassic park, right?
We're so preoccupied with whether
or not you could, you didn't stop to
think if you should, again, before.
Take any of these approaches,
think about your clients.
Think about yourself, what
do you want to be managing?
What do you think they
want to be managing?
And especially this question here, if
you're hosting websites and managing
all this infrastructure for them,
what happens if they want to leave?
Right.
If they don't have you anymore,
they don't have your team anymore.
And this is just the story that when I was
working at a local agency, A few years,
I got super into this headless and jam
stack and implementing WordPress this way.
And I thought it was great.
Cause you got the speed.
You got the scalability,
you got the security there.
All of these things were fantastic, but
I sat down with one of the owners of the
agency and he's looked at me and he said,
but what happens when they want to leave?
And instead of staying
with us to where we host.
You know, WordPress and that whole
infrastructure and that we're doing
all the maintenance and stuff.
What happens when they want to leave?
Because they're not seeing
the value there anymore.
And they want to host on, you know, a $5
a month hosting, what do we do for them?
Then they don't have a
WordPress theme anymore.
They don't have maybe all the plugins
that they could use in like a regular
classic WordPress environment.
Now, what do we do?
Do we have to have a whole offloading.
Feed that they're going to pay
just to get their sight back,
that they spend all this money on.
Let's take care of them.
Right.
So whenever you know, you're thinking
about this, it's really great to
think about all the possibilities
and stuff, but it's also okay
to stick with classic WordPress.
There are a lot of big sites that do that.
CSS tricks.com, white house.gov,
and a lot more all still running
classic WordPress and still doing.
So you can be wanting to implement all
this great, cool new stuff, but you
know, think about your clients and your
customers as well, and that you are your
marketing agency or your company you're
going to have to manage all this stuff.
I would end by saying that I
think this is so much fun, you
know, when you are dealing.
Uh, headless or a decoupled or a static
implementation of WordPress where
WordPress isn't even there anymore.
It can be hard and frustrating and
challenging, but it's also very rewarding.
It's really all the emotions.
And I would just say like, it's
really fun to build support for
something that in the end isn't even
actually there, I look forward to
answering any questions you have and
love talking about all that stuff.
Cause I think it's super exciting.
Thanks.
Matt Graham: Welcome back.
So we have, uh, both Nate and Rick
here to answer your questions.
Nate Finch: Hello.
Matt Graham: Awesome talks.
If they hit, they hit a chord,
obviously different courts with meaning.
Um, the last, uh, last eight months,
I've been kind of going through a tough
time with, uh, with my mental health,
but I was playing around with headless
WordPress, probably I wanna say six years.
I actually did it.
I actually did a talk, uh, in,
um, we're, uh, WordCamp Hamilton
about, uh, about doing a.
Um, using WordPress as like an
app development, uh, framework.
So yeah, what you're talking
about is really cool.
Yeah.
Nate Finch: That's fun, man.
That's a bit about too in that, uh,
uh, we're using WordPress for web apps
book came out, actually, I'm trying to
remember the guys at WebDev Studioes
Matt Graham: I haven't actually had
a chance to read that one over yet.
Rachel Winchester: I have a
question about how you first, uh,
I guess, got into JAMstack and
building static WordPress sites.
And really like when that
moment for you, when it clicked
that this is the way to build.
Nate Finch: Yeah, that's a great question.
Um, I think for me, at least I think
it's different for everybody, but when
you see, I think like, I don't know, I
grabbed a Gatsby theme first starter.
It wasn't a few, it was,
it started as before.
And it's like, you know, you, I think
you've just come out of, and they had
like the, uh, WordPress course, it
was really just like plug and go and
how easy it was to like get started.
Kind of get it going well, I don't know.
Easiest relative term.
Absolutely.
Um, so back it up a little bit
there, but like Netlify had their
free hosting still does, like
my personal site is still there.
And so you just like deploy it
and you're like, oh, that's there.
And it's just pulling all
this information from my site.
Well, that's cool.
And so the tools are there, you know, so I
think it was just like, kind of the right
moment when Gatsby kind of came along
and, uh, Netlify came along to really
have, uh, an easy way to get that up.
So I know there's other solutions now,
uh, through Vercel, through Strattic,
through all sorts of like headless options
and stuff like that and static options.
And everything's.
Yeah, but I think for me, it was
just like seeing the speed and, you
know, Gatsby has the, um, what is it
called where you hover over a link
and it like, pre-loads the page.
So it was just like, just so fast
and the images look so crisp and
clean and there's just so little
that you have to do or whatever.
So, yeah, I was like, this is cool.
That was great.
Rachel Winchester: Nice.
I been getting into
JAMstack about a year now.
Um, but not as a developer WordPress,
um, and while getting into it, I've
been listening to so much heavy metal.
So I like how Rick.
To heavy metal and that people can
listen to whatever music that you like.
So I'm curious, what kind of music
do you listen to throughout your day?
What do you like to work to?
Rick Alday: Oh man, like my music
taste is really all over the place
and um, you know, I, I can share
some way in my playlist and some
of them I'd rather than that, but
yeah, I mean, I just listened to.
Well, I'm working at drink to loosen,
to like some like low-fi music.
Uh, but again, it depends on
my mood and what I'm doing.
Uh, I definitely, you know, head
bang sometimes, and I have my
kid like working next to me.
She's taking a homeschool at moments,
or I cannot put out my music too loud.
I use my headphones and, but, um,
yeah, I mean, It depends on my mood.
So it varies quite a bit.
Matt Graham: Yeah.
So I guess speaking of variability,
what is that one thing that
you need to do every day to.
Yourself, like I want to stay sane,
but really the, the thing is focused.
What is that one thing
that you always need to do?
Rick Alday: Okay.
Um, what works for me is
taking a lot of breaks.
Like a lot of five minute breaks,
every 40 minutes every hour.
I need to just step out of the office and.
I just, just go, ah, what
are my plants and our yard?
And that's like, what I like to do.
I like to do gardening on my time
off and that just like completely,
completely just takes me away.
Any, uh, anything I'm working on online?
So, uh, one of my coworkers,
he lives in the near the woods.
He has like a large
property in South Carolina.
So, you know, he, he almost with the,
like coming to slack, I'm going to take
a walk in the woods and that was for him.
And so, yeah, but that's
something I need to do.
I need to go outside and look at
green style, look at plants, look
a flower, you know, But I do.
Rachel Winchester: Yeah.
I definitely understand that.
I think, uh, well, I don't know where,
where everyone's located in the world,
but where I am in the winter, you can't
get too much sunlight during the day.
So I have to leave and go outside
during lunch to even, get some sunlight.
Um, so yeah, I definitely, I definitely
feel that, um, going outside during
your work day and making a point of it.
Rick Alday: And just because I dunno, I
guess most of us work, you know, we're
sitting down all day, you know, working.
So just getting up, even getting,
you know, grabbing a cup of coffee
or just walking around like five
minutes, it really, you know, helps
you out with your back pain and,
you know, physically, mentally, it
just kind of resets you a little.
Rachel Winchester: Yeah, unless
you're too excited about the
develops develop the WordPress
static site that you're developing.
Nate Finch: I was actually the,
Matt Graham: yeah, that's the
question I wanted to ask you, Nate.
So I I'm a developer.
And I ha I feel like it could, I
don't know what it is, but I have this
rollercoaster of this is so cool too.
I hate this.
How do you go into that?
Nate Finch: Oh man.
Well, yeah.
And it's, it's also, you know, a
thing of like, oh, this is only
going to take me five more minutes.
I know.
And then five hours later,
you didn't go outside.
You didn't take your walk.
You didn't, you know, like say hi
to your family or something, working
at home or whatever and all that.
Um, yeah.
I don't know.
I'm still trying to figure that out
sometimes because I know that I'll,
you know, if I could I'd work like
all day and all night, and I just love
figuring all this stuff out is one of the
things I love about development, right.
Is that you're solving problems, like
figuring out puzzles and stuff like that.
So, um, yeah.
How do you deal with that?
I think like part of it is like, You know,
setting a timer for things, for sure.
Kind of like Rick was talking about,
you know, um, I think the other side
of it too, is to have multiple things
that you're trying to figure out, um,
that you're, or that, and if you have
other tasks you need to be doing that,
you're like, okay, I can only spend
like 30 more minutes on this before
I have to move on to something else.
And for me to like part, I was a
freelancer for, you know, six, seven
years or whatever, and joining a team,
uh, whether it's at a design agency
or now like Strattic where we're a
hosting company, um, You know, having
other people around you that have
those like have skills or can be your
rubber duck or, um, give you insight
and stuff like that to all that.
Like, if you can just like talk to
the people, like again, requisites
so much great advice, Rick,
that, uh, uh, it's super helpful.
Just feel like, figure those things
out and get unblocked and move forward.
You know, team like the sum, the total is
greater than the sum of its parts, right?
Yeah.
Matt Graham: Um, no, actually, uh,
AmyJune, which was one of the, uh, one of
the speakers earlier, uh, posted the, um,
the, from the developer Twitter account.
It's like, this'll just
be the five minutes fix.
Nate Finch: Yeah.
Five minute fixes every day.
Matt Graham: Yeah.
Right, exactly.
Right, right.
Exactly.
That's that's well, that's the limit
because if you go above that, then you
know, it ends up being an eight hour fix.
Rachel Winchester: Well, I, I
guess I have one more question.
Um, I'm curious, uh, w w with who
you deal with that at your job, um,
do people come to you excited about
static or do you have to convince them.
Nate Finch: Yeah.
So a lot of the folks that come to
Strattic are, you know, mid-size or
enterprise level folks that have been
running WordPress for years, and they
have worked on other hosting platforms
with their hosting companies and they
there's like this kind of sweet spot
sweet spotat Strattic where we can
take your WordPress site as it is and
make it static and then put that out.
And we also like build in these
serverless integrations, like for gravity
forms or contact form seven, or need
WordPress search or the list goes on.
Right.
Um, but they have been.
I told that if they want to do
something static, something fast and
scalable and secure that they need
to rebuild their site and stuff.
Well, you know, they've spent years on
this or, you know, tens of thousands
of dollars or hundreds of thousands of
people, hours or whatever on the site that
they have in the set up that they have.
And their marketers love it.
Their SEO, few people love it.
Their content writers love it.
They don't want to switch.
You know, a non WordPress
platform or whatever.
Uh, and they don't want to have like a
deployment, like a, uh, a build process
necessarily where they have everything
he coupled where there's like, you
know, next she has her Gatsby on the
front end and WordPress on the backend.
And they're still dealing with that
security then too, because they
still have their WordPress site
up and it could still be taxed.
The folks that come to us are
basically saying like, Hey, when
you shut down WordPress, that means
that our WordPress can't be hacked.
That's great.
And then you have all these awesome
integrations and stuff that other hosting
static hosting platforms or a static kind
of integrations don't have out of the box.
Like I said to the PML for like one
multinational site and stuff like that.
So those are the kinds of things
that are like really important and
like the headache, like we were
just talking with somebody else who
was like, you know, you all have.
Not to say that we cost somebody
their job or whatever, but it's like,
you know, if we were doing what we
were doing before we came to strata,
we'd still have another person and a
half or something like that on staff.
That's just, just watching our site.
Right.
Like they're not doing anything
productive or whatever, they're just
trying to help us with the thing.
So, yeah.
So yeah, it's, it's cool.
That's kind of the same story,
uh, you know, two dozen different
ways and stuff like that.
Uh, come on.
Rachel Winchester: Yeah.
Yeah.
I'm very interested in, in, in,
um, how people are transitioning,
because I know it's, it's, it's
kind of new or it's coming back.
Um, but it keeps trying to, uh,
to, to, you know, get even more
popular, which is really interesting.
Nate Finch: Yeah.
Right.
Yeah.
Everything's uh, that was old is
new again or something like that.
Right.
So.
Matt Graham: All right.
Well, thank you gentlemen, for, uh,
for being able to be part of our
Q and A I'd like to also thank our
sponsors, Bluehost, Cloudways, GoDaddy
Pro, Nexcess, Yoast and Weglot.
Please be sure to visit their
tents and chat with them and
you might even win some prizes.
So don't forget to get your photo snapped
in photo booth as well, and tweet it out
with the hashtag word, WordFest Live.
Also thank you to our media
partners and our micro sponsor.
Uh, right now in the community
tent, uh Cloudways or sorry,
that's in the next hour.
Cloudways is, will have
their hourly giveaway.
There is a, uh, well, it's
probably only about a nine minute
break in the schedule right now.
Uh, so head on over to the community tent
and we will be back in nine minutes with,
uh, starting off at the Asian continent.
You all make our Big Orange Hearts full.