Nexcess: Oh, great.
My website crashed again, I give up.
Don't give up on your dreams, Jordan!
Who are you?
It's me.
You from the future.
Your professional website
is not out of reach.
You just need Nexcess.
With Nexcess managed hosting, you get
lightening fast load times built-in
performance monitoring and updates,
and always awesome support, 24 7 365.
For all your projects.
Whoa.
Yeah.
Weglot: Discover Weglot the simple
translation solution for your website.
All you have to do is add Weglot to
your website, select the languages
that you need, and that's it.
Your website is now available
in multiple languages.
Yoast: Do you know, the Yoast SEO,
plugin, the red, orange, and green
feedback bullets that help you
optimize your posts for the web.
It runs on millions of websites.
We try to make SEO understandable
and accessible to everyone.
Bluehost: Who says building
an online store has to be hard
with Bluehost website builder.
It's more than just easy.
It's tell us your thing and smart
AI will take it from there easy.
It's WooCommerce friendly.
So you can add one of these
or swap this for that easy.
It's set up shop in minutes
with unlimited products, easy.
Whether you sell boots, books
or bowls, it's create an online
store with Bluehost, easy build
beyond boundaries with Bluehost.
Olamide Egbayelo: Welcome to WordFest!
We're in Asia now, and as part of our
24 hours of celebrating the people,
the technology and the Big Orange
Heart of WordPress, WordFest Live, not
only delivers a festival educational
content, wellness sessions and
networking opportunities, but it is
also a fundraiser for Big Orange Heart.
Please visit that donate link
at any time to support the
mission of our organization.
WordFest Live is a 24 hour opportunity for
the WordPress community to come together,
to feel less isolated, learn from one
another and be present with each other.
Our first speaker in this region is
Cory Dodd with five quick designs
tips with five quick design tips
to level up your web designs.
Corey's a 20 plus year design veteran
and the agency owner and agency
owner based in Geelong, Australia.
He has built, designed team.
And directed large scale projects,
mentored designers and developers in
both one-on-one and group settings, and
works with a huge number of national
and local brands across the country.
Corey helps designers, improve
the skills and teaches them how to
build more profitable businesses
using the power of design.
So let's welcome, Corey!
Corey Dodd: Hello?
I hope you're enjoying WordFest.
Thanks for taking some time out
to listen to me talk about design.
This is my presentation called the five
quick tips to level up your design.
And in this presentation, I
want to walk through what it
means to do better design work.
I believe when we do better
work, we can charge more and we
get to work with better clients.
Design has been extremely valuable for me.
It has paid for my entire life.
So who am I?
My name is Corey.
I've been doing this for over
20 years, nearly 25 years.
I've worked for all sorts of
places, small agencies, large
agencies, national agencies, and
I run my own agency, Elk Creative.
I have been teaching other designers, I've
mentored other designers and I've recently
completed a course teaching designers, how
to build websites with no code in Oxygen.
I'm taking a bit of a turn here and
giving away some of my design tips.
So buckle in, because we
have a lot to get through.
All right.
Let's not mess around.
Let's get into tip number one, creating
layouts, that command attention.
Now the best place to start, or
the easiest place to start with.
This is through the use of
hierarchy in our layouts.
Now, what is hierarchy and why is it in.
Both very good questions, which
we're going to answer now.
So hierarchy is essentially a design
principle that draws from a lot of
different areas or elements of design,
things like color, scale, contrast,
alignment, position, proximity, and also
things like patterns and repetition.
Now these can be used
individually or together.
To bring attention to
certain areas of our website.
Now hierarchy, isn't actually about
what appears first in a design, but
what commands the most attention or
where we want to draw the users are.
And a really good real world
example of this is something
like a podium at the Olympics.
Now this is a great example because, well,
when we look at this, we can see that it
goes from second, to first, to third and
naturally the logic would say that we
go first, second, third, or maybe third,
second, first up to the first place.
But what they've done with a podium
is put the first person in the middle,
the winner in the middle, and then
giving them an elevated stance.
This means that even if you don't know,
or you've never seen a podium before,
it becomes pretty obvious who the most
important person on that podium is.
We can really clearly see through
the hierarchy there what's going.
Now in page layouts, this is
going to look something like this.
Now of course, these are just examples.
Um, but you can see on the left here that
if we're giving everything the same amount
of work, It becomes almost impossible
to pull out anything of any importance.
It all just looks the same.
Whereas if we look at the layout on the
right, what we're seeing is through the
use of highlighting different things
with different sizes, highlighting
things with color, using space, repeating
the same sorts of elements, grouping
things together where told a story, and
we can focus on one thing at a time.
Okay.
Now, what does this look
like in the real world?
I'm going to open up a real
world example of a site that
I'm working on at the moment.
Now this isn't the full redesign.
This is actually just re-imagining this
page without actually changing anything.
So I want to stress here that, um,
that this is just an example only.
So let's take it.
Now you can see here,
there is a lot going on.
It's probably more problems than actually
just simple hierarchy here, but a lot
of this can be fixed just by focusing on
some of those areas, areas of hierarchy.
Just to get some focus back now,
overall, there's a lot of strength
on the, on the fonts there.
I want to pull all this stuff back.
Um, and generally I want to
just pull back, um, of the focus
and make it a bit more softer.
Um, and then focus on
some of the hierarchy.
So some of the key things that
I can see is the navigation is
absolutely huge for no reason.
We've got headings that are basically
bunting up against each other,
that we can't tell if they're
their headings or their buttons.
Um, we've also got some things.
Uh, drawing too much attention rather
than not getting enough, like this
green background behind the water
biodiversity and land projects.
For some reason, this is brighter
than the other sections there.
Those four key sections.
And so actually is demanding
a bit more attention.
Okay, I'm going to fix
these three key areas.
I'm going to go through
these step by step.
So the first thing I look at is just
reducing the type of graphy I've
pulled out that background there, and
you can already say this is so much
cleaner, but, and a lot more focused.
I've given it a little bit
of padding around the low.
And I've still got this issue with
the contact and the portal buttons.
I really believed that the functionality
of these is probably similar in the fact
that our user isn't going to use them
like the rest of the navigation, that
almost like bouncing kind of sections.
Someone's going to land on the
site and either click contact and
then leave, or they're going to
bounce and head off to this portal.
So we might as well group these together.
So the person isn't actually jumping
from left to right left to right there's
attention is poured into one area.
Now looking at these right
now, they are probably too big.
I've just done this in the CSS
for this example, just to get us
an idea of what we're trying to
do, but they do feel a little big.
So probably in the real world would scare.
Back.
Um, but you can see that it is giving
that navigation a lot more focus.
It becomes a lot more functionable.
All right.
The next thing we tackle here is these
four primary sections on the homepage.
What I've done is reduced that
color, the brightness behind the
water biodiversity section, you
can see that already more balanced.
I've increased the sizes of the images,
added a bit more padding around the
headings, and we can see this is
now taking up about half the page.
And it's clear that these are kind of
the primary things on the home page.
Now it's to help the user
understand there's four key
areas, and there's a guess four
journeys that people can head down.
If they're looking for permit type
information, or if they're looking
at about how to get involved, for
example, it becomes a lot clearer
that these are headings and their
sections within those headings.
Now, lastly, I've just added a lot and I'm
in a lot of space around these buttons.
They were being lost again.
If I was, if this was a real
project, I may be trying to,
re-imagine how they look.
But really essentially what I was trying
to do with this example is show how much
impact we can make without changing.
Well, the design itself.
So you can see here
with the left or right.
What's really happening here
is we've we've I guess, got
some more focus in the design.
It's a lot more calmer and it's
a lot easier for the person, the
user to know what they should be
doing at any one point in time.
Now.
Yes, we've lost some real estate.
And most of that is through the space that
I've added around those three buttons down
the bottom, but overall, we're getting
a lot more professional, a lot more,
um, you know, user friendly, our layout.
Now this design, now isn't going to win
any awards, but it's certainly a lot
cleaner and a lot more professional.
And because it's a lot easier for the
customer to use, we're going to see
that there's more value for our clients.
So this really is a leveling up our
design without really doing anything.
There's been no changes in the order.
Apart from those buttons,
it's just changing the focus.
All right, now let's
get into tip number two.
Choosing colors that don't suck.
Now this is some color tips
or maybe it's a rant, but it's
colors come up quite a lot.
People ask how do I find colors or how
do I work with colors of the difficult.
Often, what I see happening is
people linking to things that are
color generators or their favorite
color palettes, which is all well
and good, but this isn't the best
way to tackle this situation.
Now I'm not talking about
situations where clients don't
have existing assets, like low.
If this happens and you're creating
some, a website, it's going to be
difficult to know where to start.
And it's kind of a bit of a branding
exercise to create colors for them.
But in situations where clients have
colors, maybe they've got a style guide
and maybe they've got an existing logo.
Maybe they have some already
existing marketing material.
These are the places we
need to get our colors.
We need to work with the colors that
they have, if not, we're actually
doing that client and that brand
a bit of a disservice, we're kind
of removing some of that brand
equity that they have developed.
Now it's all very good to think
about things like color theory.
And I'm not going to stop anyone
from going down that path, educating
themselves on how color works is great.
There are six basic color
schemes, or there is a seventh,
we've got monochromatic,
complimentary split complimentary.
And now I guess, triad triadic.
And there is a seventh one, which is a
square a, which is very much like the
triadic, uh, color scheme, right there.
That's great to know about
these things and how they work.
But as I've said, if a client
has an existing color scheme,
we should be working with this.
Even if we do not feel that this
color scheme is right now, one
of the best ways to work with
this is to lean into the color.
Now a lot of people actually back
away from color and they think if I
use less of it, then this will help.
Now I'm going to show a couple of
real world examples where I've worked
with colors that, uh, almost seemed
against the proposition of the brand
or what someone was trying to achieve.
Now let's take a look
at this first one here.
This project, this was a childcare
center and they wanted something that
was light and bright and energetic.
And this was the logo and
identity that they had.
Now, this was being used
in signage and on vehicles.
It wasn't something that
was going to be changed.
We want it to work with this color and
this well, this logo, and really grab
the things in it and still trying to
achieve that bright looking website.
Now this is what they already have,
and this is what a perfect example of
someone pulling away, um, rather than
sort of really grabbing those dark colors.
Those.
Bright oranges and the
yellows, you haven't even used.
The black of condom pulled away from this
and used colors that were, um, like white.
And even in some examples, there
were stuff like sands in, et cetera.
Um, in the other pages now that's the
only screenshot I have left of this site.
Um, there is another example
of how they were using this on
their marketing material and the
stuff that we've done with them.
So this is the actual site.
This is what we've produced for them.
And you can see I'm really
actually embracing that dark color.
Um, now there are four sections in this
where the colors like the orange and
the reds take over the whole screen.
They really become a key feature,
but this is still light and bright,
have introduced a few graphical
elements, um, a few playful things
to sort of add to that tone.
But all up, even with the use of
strong colors, light blacks, and
reds, we're still able to make
something that is really bright and
vibrant, which is a part of the brief.
Again, let's have a quick look
at how this was used before
and after in their marketing.
He can see again on that left side
there, that they were almost probably
scared to embrace that black.
So that views this sort of
like a wood grain in the
background and these white areas.
Whereas we've now embraced that
black as a part of it and using those
colors to sort of punch through and
really give some bright vibrancy.
Now it may have felt wrong to
have worked with the black.
Kind of embracing that and embracing
that dark color really come up with
something that's A unique, B on brand,
and C still fits the brief of creating
something that's brought energetic and
well suitable for a childcare center.
Now I do have another example
where a similar thing happened.
Now again, I've just got the
left and the right examples here.
Now this is another children's charity
or it's another child based, um,
client, but it's a children's charity.
Now their logo literally has
like seven or eight colors in it.
And the old website and the
old marketing material didn't
really embrace the current.
They kind of just use a little bits of
the colors as highlights here and there.
Um, you can see that donate
button isn't even the right color.
So there we go.
Now, what we did when we started
working with them was we actually
embrace that color a lot more.
A core thing that we did was we chose a
one color as the hero, which was the blue.
And then we using all these other colors
as highlights and we're using them
quite often, actually every single color
is represented in the site, even for
blog categories and things like that.
But the real important thing here
was the, we embraced that color now.
They've actually gone on to use this as
their marketing material and their, and
their base for their marketing material.
They've even had vehicle wraps,
et cetera, done with this.
So you can see what happens
when we actually embrace some.
Now working with color is actually a lot
of fun and it can be challenging, but if
you change your beliefs around stuff that
you don't like, and actually really lean
into the color, you can look for solutions
in there that still fulfill the brief.
And again, this can really elevate
your work and make it stand out.
And so it looks better in your
portfolio and it's very appealing.
You deliver more value to your customer.
So that's the last point
on to make about color?
All right.
On to tip number three,
getting your spacing.
Perfect.
Now this is all about white the
space, and you may be thinking
with white space of something that
looks out a little bit like this.
Now, this is a project I'm working
on at the moment, and yes, it's uses
a lot of white space, but I want
to point out that white space has
nothing to do with the color white.
You have a white space on any
color background or with any image
background, but it's essentially
just the space that we have between
elements that gives it room to breathe.
Now it's a great tool to master.
And it can actually really change
the tone of a business's website,
make it look a lot more professional
or cheap, depending on the amount
of space that you want to use now.
Yes, not every single website we
work on is an expensive product.
And so we can change the amount
of white space, but there are
still some simple things that
we can look out for with spaces.
But if I'm going to give one tip around
white space, it's that we should be giving
it more white space than we normally do.
I very rarely see websites where
there's too much space and I always see
websites where there's not enough space.
So again, let's have a look at
a couple of quick examples here.
This is a website that I have
with a client, and this is the.
I want to show you the after and there's
a lot going on here, but you can already
see the amount of white space that's been
added to actually change how this looks.
The design has changed a lot overall.
So I'm going to focus in on a few
elements on the actual page and just
break down where some of the white
space has been used to add a little
bit more of, um, a little bit more
class and a little bit more focus.
So here, we've got
essentially the same content.
We've got your local acknowledgeable
global opportunities and our vision.
Now what I've done here is actually
allowed more space, um, between eight
elements of the stuff isn't so crammed in.
If you look on the left-hand side,
we've got a few spacing issues where
our, our vision has a strange gap
between the text and the image.
But then the space top and bottom
between where the text is and in the
gray box, it's all really, really tight.
Um, and this just makes it feel kind
of cluttered and almost claustrophobic
and contrast what I've got here on
the right hand side is something that
really breathes as a little bit less
content on the actual page, but it has
a lot more focus and a lot more class.
Again, let's have a look
at another element here.
We've got four projects and
we are saying, take a look at
some of our latest projects.
And there's a few key elements here.
There's a few differences
I'm using rollovers.
So when they roll over, they see
that additional information rather
than trying to ram it all in.
But if you look on the left-hand side,
there's some examples where the text gets
crazily close to the buttons, and this
just makes it look really really cheap or
that it hasn't been planned out very well.
So this is just something to keep
an eye on to, to pay attention to
where spacing really, it matters.
Now you can just see the difference.
I've used a logo and the image
is just adding so much stuff.
So by reducing some of those things,
um, we're actually making it easier for
the person to understand what it is.
All they need to know is
that these are projects.
These ones have been sold out, and if
they want to click the view project and
they can find out that information, they
don't need to know all of that stuff
upfront or were making that assumption.
All right now, this is the last part.
This is just looking at something
that's really, really obvious here.
This is a part of their
footer in their about page.
Um, and we've got some core values.
Now I've used up a lot
of space around this.
Um, I've got that information centered.
There's a lot of space above and beside
these values and it really just makes
these things feel like they're important.
Now, this is actually the values
of the businesses are the things
that they're meant to stand for.
This.
Shouldn't be like cluttered and an an
end note that hasn't really been thought
through in the website design itself.
So it's really important with our
white space, what we're saying
and what we're trying to achieve.
And that's really important.
The way that we use space actually
tells a story and just like hierarchy
it, they kind of go hand in hand.
It gives us some room to breathe when
we're looking at content and it just adds
a level of class to the work that we do.
So pay attention to white space,
make friends with white space
and now on to tip number four.
Why keeping things consistent is the key.
And yes, this is all about consistency.
And this might be an angle that
you've taken with clients yourself.
So why is consistency important?
Well, when things are
consistent, they are familiar.
When they're familiar, we
are comfortable with them.
We want to learn things like where
the navigation is, and we don't
want to relearn those things.
When we jump from page to page, we want
to feel like we're in the same place.
Yes, we want a little bit of variety,
but we don't want to feel distracted
or uncomfortable because the
opposite is true with consistency.
When things are inconsistent, they
lead to people feeling uncomfortable.
They lead to them, subconsciously
questioning other things like the
quality of the actual supplies.
That's a really big deal.
And that's why consistency
is so important.
Now I'm going to try and show here
the balance between getting things
consistent and having things as
well, quite various at the same time.
And that is a bit of a balancing act.
Now there are a few things that you can
do, and that is setting like global ideas.
Having global colors and having
the same amount of spacing, getting
those things right, is really
going to keep things consistent.
But let's take a look at a bit of
a project and we'll just go through
some of the difference between
the old site where things are
consistent and then the new one.
So you can see here, this is a
site I've worked on for content
snare, and this is the oldest site.
If we go through each
page, what you'll see.
Is that there starts to get some
inconsistency in consistencies,
around the colors that are used, the
amount of space for areas, the sizing
of fonts, the types of backgrounds
that are being used, the lack of
backgrounds and even the height of areas.
So if we look at those exact same
pages where we've got the home page
here, now, this is the rate is on.
It's a totally different brand.
I understand that we're just actually
looking at the space here, not
the brand that I've created here.
Um, and this is a totally different
design, but you can see, there
are some things we've got here.
Like if we jump from page to
page, we can see that these all
have the same sort of height.
Um, for the, the actual header.
We've got a similar thing where we've
got a little blue heading the white,
heading blue, heading white heading.
We've got this large text.
And we've got large texts used here.
These things are kept the same size, but
even when we jump from this templates
page here and our home page, this goes
from a dark purple to a light purple.
But the spacing here where this.is,
and though that bright goes from
the purple and on this one where
it goes to the white is the same.
We're keeping all of that
spacing feeling very consistent.
Now the reason why this is so important
is because we're really showing
the users that they're in the same
place, getting things consistent was
actually a really important part of
this project was something that people
had pointed out to them and they
knew that consistency was an issue.
Now, one of the things that really
helped with this was to actually
design everything upfront and not
to design in the browser as we go.
This meant that we had a total
overarching idea of what the site
was and what elements we had.
And then beyond actually just
creating a few core pages rather
than designing a page by page.
We actually created a pattern library.
So what our call to actions would
look like what our cards would look
like, custom layout, our heroes, our
signers, various things like that.
We created a library for this, and
that meant that we kept the zone, the
design itself, and the website really
consistent, but also vibrant and energetic
at the same time, it gave it a really
polished look and an amazing end result.
So keep working on consistency
because it is the key.
All right now on to the last point, point
number five, using typography to say more.
Now, obviously this is about
typography, which is a big topic.
If I was going to pick a one thing
to talk about with typography,
it is the personality of type
choosing the right typeface.
It really is important.
A lot of people have their go to typeface
and Montserrat won't fix every problem.
So what we need to consider.
When we choose a typeface
is what we're trying to say.
Look at the topography and see what
it says, how it makes you feel.
It becomes pretty obvious when a font
is elegant or when a font is fun.
Now, I'm going to show a couple
of examples and I'm going to
actually point out my website and
I'm going to show that we've the
actual type just quickly messed up.
So you can see here that I've
just used a default font and.
Totally totally changes the actual
personality of the type there.
And you can see, this is what
I actually have led with.
This is the type that I do use, and
this is sort of friendly type, and
that's a really, really important
let's put them side by side and
you can see the difference here.
So yes, there's one that has a
separate weight, but it's more
than the way it's actually the
letter shapes that actually change.
Feel of the design itself.
It changes the message that
we're trying to communicate.
And I'm going to move on and I'm
going to show you another example.
I'm using my site again here, and I'm
going to compare this to my agency site.
So this is the site for
the agency that I run.
And this also has a typeface that I
would say is a little bit of fun as well.
It's got some personality, but it's
clearly a little bit more considered.
It's trying to position me as.
Uh, a conscious and authority person.
Who's thinking about design and
that's really important, but it
still has a fun and casual element.
If we put them side by side, we can
see the difference between them.
The left hand.
One is well.
Childish, but it really,
really is inviting.
And it really is trying to say that
I'm a friend, that's literally what the
word says, but the typeface as well,
I'm trying to actually be really, really
casual, but really, really friendly.
Now on the right hand side, I'm still
trying to show that I have personality,
but it's just a lot more serious.
So the important thing that I want to
point out with type is how much personal.
Actually conveys.
So should think about the typefaces that
we use because when we choose the wrong
type face, we can send the wrong message
and the wrong type face or bad typography
can really let a design down on the whole.
Now, if we get it right, we can
actually elevate how designs and come
up with something that is far superior.
And that wraps up the presentation.
Thank you very much
for spending your time.
I know we covered a lot and
it was a bit of a whirlwind.
So hopefully you can see that just by
applying a few basic design principles,
how much you can level up your design.
Now, if this is something that is of
interest to you, I will be sticking
around and answering questions,
which will be super exciting.
But also I'd love to hear your feedback.
Email me corey@coreydodd.com.
And now that I've finished my Oxygen
course, I am considering putting
together a course about this.
So visit the site, https://coreydodd.com.
Look for the course design masters,
and sign up to express your interest.
I'd love to see if other people are
interested in learning about this.
All right, let's get
these questions going.
Olamide Egbayelo: Thank you Corey,
that was a really awesome session.
Um, I learned so much about, um,
designing and all of that, but yeah.
Welcome to welcome everyone to
the question and answer session.
If you have questions, please do
not hesitate to share with us.
Okay.
So I have quite a number
of questions here.
So you talked a lot about consistency,
so how do designers stay consistent?
I mean, you have to think about tools
you need to use and getting the best out,
and then you still need to be consistent.
So can you tell us more about that?
Corey Dodd: Yeah.
So consistency really is one
of the most important things.
I think when you're working
within specifically a website,
it shouldn't be so hard.
It gets harder when you're
walking, working across multiple.
Multiple projects or multiple mediums.
So if you're working on a print
document, for example, um, as a
designer, my job is generally to create
style guides for brands, and that
helps with keeping that consistent.
It gives people an idea.
Um, you know exactly what type of graffiti
they're using, um, you know, how they're
meant to talk even in their, in their
language, um, and how design elements
should look and how they should feel.
Um, but when you're working on your
own projects, it's really about, um,
creating I guess, a group of rules that
you want to, to, to have as, as your, um,
I guess to structure the website around,
um, and a really good way to do that
is to design one part of the website.
First, maybe you're designing up the
homepage and then try and look at
ways that you can reuse elements.
And then rather than sort of starting from
scratch, using the exact same elements
and just slightly changing them, you know,
to suit the content you've got right,
rather than re-imagining them every time.
So I use really like, um,
well-defined color palettes.
So the color palettes I use
are often quite small and I'll
stick to them quite rigidly.
I won't add the new colors just because
I, um, I want to, and I think that's
another thing about consistency.
It's about, it's about working
with the things that you've got and
sometimes you feel like you want to
do something just because you want
to, because it feels final because you
think I need to draw some attention.
And it's trying to get away from just
doing the things that are, that you
desire to do, just because it seems
like fun and just sticking to the,
to the rules, which sounds boring.
But if you work within it, you
actually get a lot better work,
a lot more consistant work.
Olamide Egbayelo: Oh, great.
Thank you for the wonderful answer.
So, um, before I go to the
audience questions, um, I also
have one other question for you.
So, uh, talk about planning.
Um, planning is actually one of
the most important part of design.
And, um, so what, how
many hours do you think.
What duration do you think that
the designers should focus on
planning the design process?
So how long should the
design process go in?
How long should you plan?
Corey Dodd: Yeah, that's a tough one.
It depends on the size of the project,
obviously, but if you're talking about
something that's, you know, I don't know,
let's say you're talking about something.
That's got five or six screens
that you're trying to design.
Um, look, I'm easily be
sinking 20, 30, 40 hours into.
Which seems like a lot of time.
Um, and some people, they, they
don't want to spend that time.
Um, but it really is important for me
to get the work again consistent, um,
to get it to the best out of that I
can and I'm charging for that time.
Um, and that's really important as well.
Like.
Th th the better work you can do that.
The more attention to detail you can
give you design, um, the more you can
charge for it, the more you'll stand out.
So that's sort of the whole point of
this talk really to make you work better,
um, and make yourself more attractive to
clients to make your work more valuable.
Um, but yeah, look, I do take
the design side seriously.
I'm not the fastest worker either,
and that's, I have to allow for that.
Um, but I think it's important.
It's not a sort of explaining.
Um, you know, there are some people that,
that kind of, um, try and rush the design
process, or don't have a design process
and now, you know, designers, they go.
Um, but even if you're, if you started to
add some design time into your process,
now the time that it saves you is huge.
So if I'm working on a, on a large project
or I do design for someone else, um, the
amount of time that that's saving them by
having all of the decisions, um, already
made up, like all the decisions made.
In the design process really is.
Um, yeah, it really is saves
a lot of time in the long run.
Olamide Egbayelo: Alright, thank you.
So, uh, we'll have a
question from the audience.
We'll have a question from Jenna.
So Jenna is asking, do you have
any go-to resource resources for
things like padding others, struggle
to know how much space to put.
Corey Dodd: Ooh.
So the short answer is no, I don't have
any resources that I use if this is all
done by, um, training and, and, um, from
years of experience, uh, as far as things
like padding, it's generally more than
what people people allow for currently.
I think a lot of people, um, the
common mistake is real estate.
We always think about real estate and
you know, I've been in the industry.
Uh, a long time.
And that used to be something that
people would talk about, like how
fitting stuff above the fold and
fitting more stuff on the page.
Um, but we're used to
scrolling around on websites.
We use that stuff all day that, you
know, Instagram and Facebook and all
of these apps that just scroll forever.
So it's about using the
right amount of space.
So I wouldn't allow more space.
It's just about allowing the amount
of space that gives the user a chance
to focus on the most important thing
or one, one or two things at a time.
You don't want them distracted.
Um, so that's really important.
So I don't have any go-to resources.
I do treat this on a, um, You
know, project by project basis
when I'm, when I'm working on it.
So, um, yeah, the only tip I can give
specifically there is to, um, you
know, specifically around space is to
give yourself a little bit more space
than, than what you probably think.
Olamide Egbayelo: Okay.
Um, thank you, Jenna.
I hope, um, Corey has
answered your questions.
Uh, remember you can still drop
your questions in the live chat,
Corey is here for, to engage.
So, uh, I mean, I have
another question for you.
Um, so you, you said you don't
have any go-to or resources.
I mean, as, as a designer, you
should have, um, most have tools
that every designer should have or
should be able to use very well.
It could be planning tools,
it could be designed tools.
It could be tools that help
you to stay consistent.
It could be productivity tools.
So can you share some of your,
really, go-to tools with us?
Corey Dodd: This is my favorite tool.
A bit of paper and some pencil.
It sounds really stupid, but,
um, yeah, it's my go to thing.
I'd start.
Yeah, it doesn't matter if I'm
doing branding or I'm doing,
you know, um, website design.
Uh, I can just sketch ideas out
really quickly and often move
to all just really rough ideas.
I'm not drawing what a website design
would look like, but I might sort of try
and map out the hierarchy of the content.
So what content I want to go first.
And it's just an easy tool for me.
Um, but as far as the main tools that
I use, uh, I'm a creative cloud person.
I've always been using Adobe.
I don't think that the
tool really matters.
It's about the attention to detail
and sort of spending some time.
Um, one thing that I do believe
with Adobe though, as it is
kind of an industry standard.
So if you're looking for employment
opportunities and stuff like that, if you,
if you're just going to work for yourself,
it doesn't, it doesn't matter so much.
But if you're going to
want to get employed.
So sort of standard tools that you
want to know about these days are
obviously the Adobe creative cloud suite.
Um, things like Figma and Sketch are
also pretty important for, um, you
know, the web design industry, but
there's a lot of other tools out there
that I know people use all the time,
like Canva and that sort of stuff.
Um, at the end of the day, whatever
helps you get your ideas out.
It's totally fine, but I am
all of my web design is done in
XD, so I'll use creative cloud.
Um, and I like XD purely because it
is a Adobe product and I can move
between the programs pretty easily.
So if I need to do some illustration work,
I can quickly open up, um, illustrator
and start, you know, making up some, some
ideas and then copy that into an XD file.
If you're using.
Figma or Sketch you, you
know, it's harder to open up.
Um, th th that's just my personal
preference, but I found it harder to
work without the other creative cloud
pro programs, but I noticed so well.
Olamide Egbayelo: All right.
Great.
Thanks for sharing.
We have another question from my audience.
Um, Fernando Eiella is asking
redesigning in the context of keeping
a client sites performant, performant.
How does one deal with clients
that want, or need homogeneous
videos or pictures on the on page?
Corey Dodd: Um, that's a tough question.
So I think that as far as like, you know,
optimization and what you're trying to
achieve in this design, if something needs
to be fast loading, for instance, That's
a conversation to have pretty early,
um, and really try and address that.
And I know there is the school of
thought that the client's always right.
Um, but then there is the
school of thought that the
client is hiring an expert.
So, if you can kind of position
yourself as someone who, um, is an
expert and takes less orders, so you
sort of diagnose problems and, and
that's the best way to start with that.
So rather than starting relationship
with a client where they're dictating,
what you do, you essentially
say that, what are you going.
You're trying to work
out what those goals are.
And then when you present design ideas
back to them, you explain how those,
um, those design ideas have helped
help the client meet those goals.
And then when I have ideas that are
actually not going to help them, that
are, that are, that are, I don't want to
say bad ideas, but let's say bad ideas.
Um, I explained to them that it
doesn't help them achieve their goals.
It's so it's really not about my
personal taste versus the clients.
At the end of the day, I don't, I'm
not to design things that I like.
I'm designing things that are going
to work for their customers and
help my clients achieve their goals.
So if you start with someone's goals,
what they're trying to achieve, um,
that's probably the best way to tackle.
Olamide Egbayelo: Oh, awesome.
Um, I hope that's Fernando.
I hope that Corey has been
able to answer your question.
So I know that, um, I still have
another question for you while we
wait for more audience questions.
So I know that, um, this session is
what's clearly for designers, people
who are already professional designers
or intermediate or expert designers.
So, um, um, I just want to
put you on the spot here.
What teams do you have for beginners?
Because I know that there are
people who are just taxing or
about study design journey and,
um, they have listened to you.
They've watched you speak
about this teams and all that.
So can you tell us, can you list about
four to five things that it began
as designers should look, you know,
Corey Dodd: I was actually
toying with the idea of speaking
about developing your eye.
And I think that's one of the most
important things with getting better
at design or I'm doing good design
is actually, um, one being interested
in design and, and seeing seeing
it in the world, you know, noticing
what things do you like noticing what
things other people like, and then
trying to work out why they liked them.
And that doesn't need to
be websites all the time.
You know how someone likes a pair of
shoes or someone likes a certain car.
It's not to your taste, trying to
understand what it is about those
things that, that are appealing
because, because design isn't just
about, um, the visual elements.
It's it's about how things
work and how they function.
So yeah, developing your
eyes is really important.
So keeping up with trends, working
out what stuff looks good to you.
And, and so that's number one.
Um, another thing is.
You working out your vocabulary, so
you can actually talk about design
and it's, it's a tough thing to do.
And, um, it's a skill that a lot
of people, uh, lack, being able
to explain their designs in a way
that isn't talking about nonsense.
That's all the fluffy stuff about design.
Um, so it's really important.
Like I said, in the other
point about having goals.
And so our tip here is to when
you're taking a design brief with
a client, or you're taking that,
you're doing a discovery session.
For example, if you're asking them
about the things that they like,
um, really keep your ear open and
listen out for the language they use.
So if someone's saying the words, you
know, fun or bold or bright, um, you
might want to slow that down and work
out what that means to them because
someone's idea of fun might be.
More conservative than yours.
So it's working out what they
actually mean because they're
subjective terms, but then also
remember the words that they've used.
And then when you talk about.
Use the same language.
So you presented design back to someone
and say, look, this is really bright.
It's really bold and fun.
And they go, oh, that's
exactly what I wanted.
And it's just through the language abuse.
So that's another tip or what's
another tip for beginners.
Um, just to, just to design for fun.
Like when I first started
designing, I would design for fun.
I'm not talking about designing for free.
I don't think people should
design for free, but I think
they should design for, for fun.
So I think, I think if you can design
stuff, um, you know, Play around
in the space, even now I'll, I'll
still, you know, I try ideas out.
I've been doing this for too long, 20,
over 20 years and I still just try out
new ideas just to see where they take me.
Um, and also look at things.
And if you see things that are
cool, that's another, that's
probably the last thing.
If you see things that are really cool,
just create, uh, a memory bank or some
sort of way of capturing images of.
Keep it in a folder of things that you
like, things that you think are fun.
Um, I know there's stuff around stealing
ideas, but as far as the idea of, um,
stealing versus inspiration, to me,
the idea of where that crosses the
line is if you look at something and
you're directly copying it, um, versus
getting inspired by where that line is.
There's a, there's a thing where if you
steal from one, if you take it from one
source, it's stealing and if you take
from many it's being inspired by it.
So if you have lots of things, if
you're getting, um, your colors from
over here and then you're getting, you
know, the topography ideas are from here
and you're getting spacing ideas from.
Then you really just being influenced
by a whole lot of stuff, rather
than directly seeing something
you love and trying to copy it.
So keep things that you think are cool.
Keep them in a file.
And just, you know, when you've got a
new project to start and it seems like
something that's fun, maybe you look
at the things that you think are fun.
If you've got something that's meant to
be corporate, look at the things that you
think are corporate that are really cool
and try and try and get some inspiration.
Olamide Egbayelo: All right.
Thank you so much.
Those are really wonderful tips
and talking about inspiration.
We have a question on inspiration.
Okay.
So, um, Jenna is asking, where do
you find you find your inspiration?
Corey Dodd: Yeah, that's
a really good question.
So I try to be pretty mindful.
My job has designed and that's what I do.
That's essentially all I get paid to do.
Um, and that's branding websites.
It's all sorts of stuff.
Um, where are trying to get my
inspiration is generally not
from the job that I'm working on.
So if I'm doing a website, I try not to
go look at websites to get inspiration.
I'll try and look in magazines
at, um, you know, brochure,
layouts and stuff like that.
Um, and when I'm doing branding, I like
to look into stuff in the real world.
Like if you go out and know.
You know, notice things
on buildings and stuff.
For example, that's always really good.
I'm not the sort of person that opens up
Pinterest and then types in, you know,
whale logo, if I've got a client that
needs, you know, a whale for for a logo.
That's I think that leads
me to a very specific place.
Um, so I try to look at things
that aren't literally what I'm
working on, stuff for me to do.
So I'm not gonna sit around and
look up website inspiration.
I don't think there's.
Wrong with doing that, but that's not
where I get my inspiration myself.
Um, and we've finding inspiration
specifically, if you've got a website to
do, and let's say it's a fashion website,
you know, there's nothing wrong with
opening up Pinterest and topping and
fashion websites and finding cool ideas.
Um, but I would go back to that constant
concept that I said before, grab, grab
50 ideas that you like, put them in a
folder, look at them, absorb them and
then try and come up with something.
But look at the things that you like
to understand why you like them.
If it's about big type of
graphy, then you know, you want
to work with big topography.
If it's about full-size images, et cetera.
So rather than grabbing one thing that
you like and copying it, um, yeah.
Take a few ideas from a few places.
Olamide Egbayelo: So powerful.
That's so powerful.
Thank you so much.
Corey.
It's been nice having you, you know,
sharing your design tips with us.
And most importantly, it's been really
nice having you join us at WordFest Live.
Um, in Asia, we were at
a time and all of us.
So do you have one last word
just to say bye to our audience?
Corey Dodd: All I want to say
is well done for taking the
time out and coming to WordFest.
I think I, hopefully
you're learning a lot.
Hopefully it was valuable for you
to suspend some time with me, um,
and just go enjoy WordFest Live,
share it and tell everyone about it.
They might be able to be catching
sessions that are coming up.
Thank you everyone.
Olamide Egbayelo: So thank
you everyone for joining us.
Uh, We appreciate you and thanks to
our sponsors, Bluehost, Cloudways,
GoDaddy Pro, Nexcess, Yoast, and
Weglot please, um, be sure to visits
their tents and chat with them.
You might even win some prizes.
So don't miss out on that, but also
don't forget to get your photos
snapped in the photo booth and tweet
it out with the WordFest Live hashtag.
And thank you so much to our media
partners and micro sponsors in the
community, in the community tent, um,
in the community tent in the next hour.
Cloudways have their hourly giveaway
with a special guest activity.
So there's also what our break
in the, um, here at stage two.
So make sure you add over to the community
tent and we'll be back on the hour.
So please make sure that our Big Orange
Heart is full go onto the community
center now, and we'll see you right
after there might be giveaways for you.
Don't miss out on that.
I'm adding to the
community tent right now.
So I'll see you there.