Yoast: Do you know, the Yoast SEO,
plugin, they're red, orange, and
green feedback bullets that help
you optimize your posts for the web.
It runs on millions of websites.
We tried to make SEO understandable
and accessible to everyone.
Bluehost: Who says building
an online store has to be hard
with Bluehost website builder.
It's more than just easy.
It's tell us your thing in smart AI.
We'll take it from there.
Easy it's WooCommerce friendly.
So you can add one of these
or swap this for that.
It's set up shop in minutes
with unlimited products.
Easy.
Whether you sell boots, books
or bowls, it's create an online
store with Bluehost, easy build
beyond boundaries with Bluehost.
Nexcess: Oh, great.
My website crashed again.
I give up, don't give up on your
dreams, Jordan, who are you?
It's me.
You from the future.
Your professional website
is not at a breach.
You just need Nexcess with Nexcess managed
hosting, you get lightning fast load
times built-in performance monitoring
and updates, and always awesome support.
24 7 365.
For all your props.
Whoa.
Yeah.
Discover Weglot the simple
translation solution for your website.
All you have to do is add
Weglot to your website, select
the languages that you need.
And that's it.
Your website is now available
in multiple languages.
Michelle: Well Hello?
Olamideyelo: Hello, Michelle.
Michelle: How are you?
Olamideyelo: I'm very well, thank you.
The second session that I'm very excited.
Michelle: Very good.
Well O'Neil is having
all kinds of problems.
The internet is, um, given trouble
right now in the Philippines.
So I jumped in and said, I would be more
than happy to co-host with you this time.
How are you doing?
Olamideyelo: I'm very well,
thank you for joining in.
Michelle: Oh, of course.
Do you mind if I introduce
our next speaker?
Olamideyelo: Okay.
Yeah, that's good.
Okay.
Michelle: Great.
Um, so our next speaker is
Néstor Angulo de Ugarte.
I hope I said that, right?
Presenting Breathe in, breathe out the
checklist and guide to recover your
site and reputation after a hack, Néstor
is a technology enthusiasts, computer
science engineer, and web security geek.
He loves to travel and although he's
based in Spain, you can find him learning
from other cultures and meeting people
wherever and internet connection is
available Néstor has been with security
and GoDaddy web security since 2015,
and learns a ton about hackers, malware,
and strange cases to study kind of
like a CSI for security analysts.
So we will listen to Néstor
and then go back and we'll be
asking him a ton of questions.
Olamideyelo: Yeah.
Looking forward to this session.
Me too.
Néstor Angulo de Ugarte: Hey.
Hi.
How are you guys?
Thank you very much for the
presentation for introductions.
Sorry, Michelle and Ola.
Um, here we are so sorry,
because it's really early here.
It's 6am am in the morning,
so let's do our best.
Um, okay.
Let's talk about hacking, security and
so on and how to recover after a hack.
Um,
I hope that you guys were up up already.
Um, but, uh, one of the
questions, uh, important here
is have you been hacked already?
Uh, just please raise your hand.
Oh, yeah, I see a lot of hands there.
No, I was kidding.
We are digital.
This isn't possible, but probably, a lot
of you guys has, uh, suffer a hack, uh,
in one moment or another, uh, in your
digital world and your digital life.
And if not, you will.
So this guy is important.
Let me share with you so on my
impression, because I suffered in that.
And um, uh, in first person,
uh, this kind of hack, uh, and I
feel, I felt all the answer to the
older, all the, what I have to do.
And so on just before, before I
came, I joined, uh, security and
GoDaddy, eh, and it was just a.
It was an er it was a nightmare
because, uh, you know, uh,
you don't know what to do.
You don't know where to go.
You don't  know what to find.
And the customers are yes.
Uh, ringing you and so on.
So then let me share with you some tricks.
You can do some, uh, uh,
again, a little guide.
To help you with, uh, you know,
to help you with your anxiety and
your, or your feelings, uh, with
the power of action right now.
So let's just, uh, let's just put in the
situation that you have being hacked.
For example, you have been defaced
with a skin like this one, uh, yeah.
Or, or you get all your
files encrypted and so-on.
Yeah.
I know.
It's pretty tough.
Okay.
So let's scream.
You can, yes.
Let's your feel out?
Um, um, this, and is accepted also
to be down a little bit, uh, but the
important part is after that, when you
get all your feelings out, let's act.
Okay.
So this is the guide of the things
that should you should do before that.
Uh, normally I am, uh, share some kind of
concepts because we should put some care.
Uh, things clear before, um,
uh, troubleshooting these
kind of scenarios, right?
So those of you that, uh, has, uh, seen
any of my presentation, you will see
that this slide is appearing in all
of them, this guy is a CIA, a C E O of
Cisco, which is a very big company of
global communications around the world.
And he says that there are two
types of companies, those who has
been hacked and those who don't
yet know they have been hacked.
So, you know, dealing with, uh, cyber
security or with the internet could
be a little bit of stress, right.
They used to have a lot of,
um, uh, threats are out there.
There is a lot of terms and
there is a lot of things to know.
Um, yeah, it could be a
little bit of a warning.
So, let me put some things clear.
For example, I normally talk about
hackers, the difference between
hackers and cyber terrorists
hackers, a curious person who will
be your limits and convention.
I always say that, um, if you
are a little bit sleepy and you
just, take a coffee, you are just
hacking yourself.
You are, uh, what we call bio-hacking.
Right.
Um, even if you use a part of a
bottle for all the thing or something
like that, you are hacking as well.
So it's important to not.
Uh, take wrong this, this term, right?
So as cyber terrorist is a one kind of
hackers, a computer hacker, which is, um,
whose mission is to enrich himself, right?
Yes.
Uh, we always say that the bad
guy, right or the bad hacker.
Also it's important to understand
that security is not a whole list
is component of the layers, right?
Is, um, uh, this is a simplified
model in, in the web security part,
but the, you know, Cyber security.
There has a lot of fields and we
are talking right now about, uh,
WordPress sites or web security.
So let me just pull it up in the
screen, the layers more or less.
I mean, it's, I mean, this is a
simplified model, uh, the layers we
have to take care on just to, uh,
decrease the risk of being hacked.
Right?
So at the end, we are users.
It doesn't matter if you are
the admin, you are the customer
or you are a hosting provider.
Uh, uh, Operator or whatever,
there's a person, you know, we
can be, eh, eh, can be cheated.
Right?
So we are, we always say that
the, that the persons, the
human being is weakest today.
Right?
So there is a device we use to connect.
We use the connection, things just goes
through, uh, We have, you know, the
traffic that hits your website, there
is the use of credentials, password
for authorization, for the different
tasks you will like to do in a website.
There's a, some kind of layer of
where security website security.
There is some kind of layer in the
server security and also the database.
Keep in mind that the web model has also.
separated, the presentation part and
the information part information in
the database and the presentation
is all the files, design and so on.
So the counter measures or, um, the,
the things we have to, uh, work in for
protecting these layers of course in
the, in the part of persons of, of human
beings, uh, isn't knowledge, we should.
Learn things.
So we should just attend to
this kind of lectures and so
on to know what is going on.
I where to, uh, where to look, right.
And again, if you are using a
device, you can start antivirus
or you're using a connection.
Keep also keep in mind to use a
SSL certificate so you can use.
Eh, S no, it's the HTTP protocol
is the HTTPS, the secure one.
So if you're talking about
traffic, you can install a WAF,
for me is the best protection.
So it's a web application firewall.
Yeah.
So then outside of there, um, in
the kind of  authorisation and so
on, you got to use strong passwords,
second factor authentication on in
the part of the website, both side
on the server and the database.
The important is just
to monitor it closely.
And install the updates,
but there's another layer.
This is important.
This is not a once in lifetime checklist.
This is something we have to
check continuously, continuously.
That's why I put another layer,
which is the maintenance.
So we have to do this.
and check this every time.
So this is important.
Other part importantly,
how WordPress is infected.
So we have.
Yeah.
If we get infected, these are the
parts of the infection, right?
So to get a WordPress infected, there
should be a vulnerability somewhere
when there is a piece of software
that, uh, exploits that vulnerability
and then happens to the injection.
The injection could be just final code.
They just put the spam, I guess, the
deface, your website, I just, put it
down and remove the fires or whatever.
Or the worst scenario if we brought the
up backdoor, which is a piece of software
that allows me to access to the website,
even if the vulnerability is  black.
Right?
So when you have a backdoor inside, you
can do all the final code things also.
Uh, but whenever you want, not
only when they went brevity, sorry.
So facts, I would love also to share
with you guys, normally, uh, hacking
is not easily is not client oriented.
So if you, when you get hack,
normally the first question is why me?
Why me?
I half a kitty, uh, feed the shop online.
So why they attack me normally they are.
don't care, what you are, what
you are a using you WordPress, how
you are using the word purpose.
If you are using this state, just enroll.
There were the website using the
vulnerabilities in their, uh,
vulnerable sites so they can hack
whatever they need something.
It always, almost always happens
because of that lack of maintenance.
Right.
So that's why it's important.
Uh, keeping also keep in mind
also that SSL certificate is
not an anti-hacking shield.
So you should, uh, understand that
having SSL certificate is not going
to protect you from getting hack.
It's going to protect the
communications between that entity
or user your wherever and the server.
So the communications
here is a secure channel.
If you hope put here as an
entity, . an, er, bad hacker, which
is trying to hack your website.
So there's a certificate when I made
this hacking attempts secure, right?
So it's, it's a  important part,
but it's not an anti-hacking shield.
Also keep in mind, this is very important
that patches and security updates
appear, uh, after an exploit discover.
So if you find that you see there is
an update, like with a security patch.
Be sure or almost sure that there is
an exploited, uh, being used on the
wild out there also, but hackers or
bad guys, uh, are always checking them
their patches because when they say
that there is a patch of the security,
uh, That's a good patch inside.
Uh, they try to figure it out.
The why has been, uh, uh, deployed
so they can leverage all of the older
sites that haven't been updated.
So that's why it's important to
update, uh, Very quickly, right.
And the other part is er, assuming
that we are human we've failed.
So that's why it's a security
is never, nor will never is.
And nor will be in the
future 100% effective.
We have to reduce the
risk of being hacked.
So going into, into the, into
the mother, if you get hacked.
Well, uh, what's um, what are the steps?
Right.
So let me put here the agents in
bold, if that happens, it's you at
your site, but also your customers.
So if you are, uh, under.
Uh, country, which has data, privacy,
law, uh, law, or something like that.
You have to be aware of that.
So if there is a leak of information
of sensitive information from your
website, you have to know the law that
is applied to you and to your customer,
because maybe you have to, uh, mega
worry that the authorities about that.
And we were going to
talk about this later.
There's another layer, which
is the hosting providers.
After these parts of this taking
care of this part, we can't
just contact hosting providers.
Majority of securities can be, uh, can
be solved digitally with the by, the
hosting providers support department.
And also you can apply as a backup or
something like that with their help.
And if those agents are not able and not
able to solve the security issue, This
is the moment when you have to hire, or
you have to get in touch with security
expert, that can be internal, your hosting
provider or external services, but this
talk, going to be in this part, right?
So what can you do if you get
a hack on what are the first
aids you will, er should do.
So it's important that mission,
we can take our two kind
of measures fire up fair.
The first of one is the reactive one.
Whereas this is when
something already happened.
Something bad already happened.
It's a pain, mitigation
or damage mitigation.
And this is what we
call incident response.
And there is a proactive, uh, set
of, uh, actions we can take before.
Anything bad happens, but this still
going up, but going to center, we're
going to focus in the react part
because we put in this scenario
that you have been hacked already.
So The response.
Here's the response is the effort
to quickly identify, minimize the
effects and contain the damage,
uh, or the, these adverse events.
Right?
So reactive measure, as we
normally  as interim response, it
starts with it's scan of your site.
So the first of the fault is.
Don't do a blind hits.
Just let's try to figure
out what happened.
Right?
So scan your site.
We'll be keeping in mind that
normally with separate sites in
two, in two ways, in three ways.
Really the first one is the
front end is what they use
or receive in their browsers.
The second one is the backend
is what happened in the server.
You are, you have higher.
And the third one is we're
happening the database, right?
The last two is difficult to
scan if you are not skilled,
but the front end is easy.
You can use, for example, site check,
uh,  from Securi, free a scanner that
you're going to take a snapshot of.
What is the scene in your website and
analyze it, the checking for patterns.
And so on.
Also you have, uh, uh,
plugins in your website.
Some of them yesterday
includes some scanners.
Uh, I normally, I normally, I
assume that we are talking the, we
are, we are assuming he has will
have a big budget of security.
So that's why I recommend the
free tail free trial plugins
scanners, like the Wordfence one.
Okay.
So update everything, including service.
Are we going to get to this
point later is this is just a.
Yes, uh, uh, quickly checklist
and then the CRC check remove or
change, which is the most boring
part, but this is important as well.
And if any of these is not working,
or, you need to restore a backup.
Keep in mind that after
restoring a backup, we'll have
to back to the first part.
Okay.
So scanning as a, as a.
Uh, told before is yes.
Let's, uh, figure it out  what happened?
Uh, the site check, we don't
have talking about that.
And eh, the use of any
file plugins can answer.
And if you have, uh, access to the
server and you have skill enough, you
can use  ClamAV or something like that.
So these kinds of things going to give
some information, for example, this is
a screenshot for, from a site check.
And in this case, are
you going to see here?
There's a jQuery.js uh, infected, right?
So yeah, we can, in this way,
we can know that there is
something in the BP includes,
which is a core file or a folder.
Sorry.
So this is a file infected is infected
inside of the core files of WordPress.
And this is invaluable information.
So the update, why I say that to update
we should today, everything right.
And keep in mind that this patches a
security world is, but the most important
part for me in this talk is study.
When you update, you will override
compromised and corrupt code with a
trustworthy code from official repository,
which means that if you are, they were,
for example, they be being closed on.
VPN in, all the files that are needed is
get over-written with the, uh, good ones.
Right?
So if there is malware, as we saw,
so in the previous example, inside of
the core file of  of folders, uh, in
this way, you just get rid of them.
It is a very easy way, eh, to
troubleshoot this kind of thing.
So as I mentioned, just go to
wordpress.org  download the
WordPress, eh, uh, separate
file the exact version you have.
And then just remove, uh, when,
when you extract, uh, what is
inside of this secret file, remove
the  wp-content, wp-config.PHP
file because those are important
for our website and we don't want.
Uh, you know, uh,
accidentally overwrite them.
So removing those are highlighted, the
wp-content folder and wp-config.php.
We can just go and.
Uh, take all these files and folder
and just over-writ, override what
we have in our website, doing this.
We just get a fresh and updated  WordPress
version that we know that the all, all
the core files and folders are clean.
The most more important, which is check,
remove, and change, which is yeah.
Check for undeeded  admin users,
plugins that we don't need themes
that are themes that we don't need.
Keep in mind that themes should
be only two always in your list.
There should be only two themes.
The theme that you are actually using
and at the default one only one default
one, because it's going to, uh, you
got to work as a fail over themes.
If something bad happened
with the other theme.
You're going to start with a default
one, remove  with any updated backups,
uh, any defin, uh, under development or
test sites in your brochure and started.
But you should understand that, um,
a website secure, uh, mostly secured
website in internet should have.
The finest WordPress final version in our
production server are all the experiments,
all the tests, all under-development
themes  in a separate server.
Okay.
This is boredom.
Change all the password of the admin
users, all the password, including the
database, including the cPanel FTP, SSH
because if a hacker a bad
hacker gets into your website.
Reading the BB config PHP you
have, for example, the password
to expose your database.
So it's important to review all
of the, and also it's a good
habit to periodically change.
them.
So this is an example that
you can see in the left.
Do we have a lot of
default themes in style?
They shouldn't be like this.
Just keep one and update it.
And in the right, you can see
a lot of means, which maybe
they add mean for a user.
And the janitor on the levy, the docent
in the red tapes, uh, are probably
legit, but the admin is not one.
Let's see the email and the
other ones could be just, you
know, leftovers or, uh, outdated.
So check this from time to time.
And that's the last
option restore a backup.
Keep in mind, as you restore a backup,
it shouldn't be the first option
because you can lose information.
And with us always, we don't
always know what, sorry.
When will the infection began?
We can restart then the malware.
About backups is important to check
that we have a good backup strategy.
Uh, if you you don't know how to
do this, It's better if you just
rely in the hosting provider ones.
So invest in a good hosting,
which has, uh, backups, a good
backup strategy, never restore the
backups in the production server.
As I mentioned before, we
can, we can infect the backup.
And then from there we can infect
from inside the real sites.
So, eh, any, any security rule
you may have going to be useless
if the infection comes from.
That's it.
That's why also way we recommend all
to have the approach and server to
have there only there the production,
the final WordPress in that server
check that their backup is functional.
Okay.
So let me remain functional.
So sometimes we just do backups, but
the, they don't work or they are not
completed or something like that.
So check their backups are
complete in a separate environment.
So something like that is a good habit.
So remember  scan, there was updates CRC.
And if you had to restore a
backup, just go back to one.
I understand again.
So this is the checklist.
So what happens with reputation, uh, is
important that, uh, we should understand
that internet is constantly being crawled
by boats, not only searching giants
bots, we know, you know, for example,
Google ones and so on, but also bots for.
Uh, other entities are
just crawling internet.
So certain, certain Jina
and security vendors have
normally have their block list.
Right?
So those are minds that they
don't re they don't trust on them.
So the blocks is hard, hard linkage
with the reputation because eh, the
most, the far most block list, the more
widely accepted and the more actions
take  uh, So where's your post or your
domain, or is your customer so on if
you are, uh, under their, their network?
Right?
So as what they mean is if you are, for
example, posting something in Facebook
and Google or Facebook, Facebook, I don't
think if they will have a block-list,
but the, for example, Google has a
block list, block list at your domain.
Uh, Uh, Facebook is just going to put that
your domain,  has been blacklisted, so
they don't allow you to post or they going
to add something like, okay, decide maybe,
uh, having hack or something like that.
So you're going to affect your
reputation, but keep in mind that the
reputation link to the, uh, To their
black list is not an immediate process.
Okay.
So the inclusions in the
black list takes time.
So if you are in a black list is because
your infection hasn't been a detected.
And there's time that it
has been in your  website.
So that's why it's important to
detect faster, uh, any intrusion and
the de-listing also, it takes time.
So normally there are reconsiderations
is a manual process normally, so it
could take three to five business days.
So it's important.
Even more, if you are talking
about ads companies, um, some
normally they don't give you
information why they had your site.
well have been is included
in our block list.
Well, sometimes not always, but
sometimes just for giving you an
example, I remember social networks
block or worry about your post.
If you are in a.
In a blocked company, but ads
company can block a whole campaigns.
And this is very interesting because for
example, I know the example of Google
ads, because it's pretty, pretty funny.
Even if Google says it clear every
blacklist vendor out there says
it's clear, eh, they normally
take a lot of time to, to.
To allow your campaigns
going and going live again.
So they talk normally around two
weeks or sometimes even a month.
So don't delay.
That's why it's important to
not get into any block lists.
And that's why it's important
to get, uh, uh, to get to detect
faster, your intrusion and your
site before this hits this step.
Oh, so if someone's search
giants remove some of you results
and some of them also just to
remove or resets your ranking,
so it could be very damage.
There's another important thing
to mention, I mentioned it before.
It's, according to data protection it
might be mandatory to report the personnel
data breached to supervisory authorities.
For example, in Europe, GDPR, give 70
72 hours after a breach is detected.
So check the law.
Uh, which can be applied to the
person who is affected for a breach.
I say, know, there are some
laws and not from ASIA.
Uh, I'm not sure about that, but there
is some examples I collected for you.
There's a, you know, the New Zealand
privacy act 2020, the APPI for in Japan.
So it's called a P IPA, eh, PA
uh, Thailand PDPA, and so on.
So.
Just be aware of this
is not only your site.
It's also, uh, the applicable
law in the country.
You are operating on the country of
your customers who suffer a leak.
So the troubleshooting you know, now
what happened with the reputation
and the, these kind of things.
Uh, so once the site is
cleared, Go to VirusTotal.
total.com puts your URL of your
domain there, and you can get
a huge list,, a huge list of
black list of vendors out there.
So every one of these points
that says anything else done
clear that clean, sorry.
You have to submit individually
to them for a reconsideration,
but only once the site is clean.
Because if not, they're
going to just say something.
I don't get your, your
domain from the black list.
And maybe you can put yourself
in a . Uh, More, uh, time
list, right on the last part.
Then the reputation part is just to give
a post-mortem report is hard because
sometime exposes your management, but.
It should be something like, okay guys, I
have, uh, I have, um, suffer a hack attack
and this is more or less what's happening.
How I did discover when I covered
this is the lessons learned one
where you have what I going to
apply to not letting this happen.
Again, this is important because
you can learn from these situations.
You can recover users
trust because at the end.
You going to take all of us,
uh, in one moment and also shows
your company has a transparency.
Advocated.
This is something I recommend is not
mandatory, but I recommend that is
you suffer a major leak or a hack.
Especially, if you have density formation,
do a post mortem sensitive public.
Okay.
So not that it's not important
to, to give, uh, you know, secrets
in this post-mortem, but just to
transmit to people that, Hey, okay,
we have this, we have suffered these
transparency abrogated, so, okay.
So at this moment we have.
Covered the checklist cover the reputation
point and you know, I always talk
house out loud practice measure what
we can do to avoid that this happens.
And anytime again, so just the
CRC applied the same yesterday.
This admins, plugins and themes
apply the least privileged.
Use password manager check
periodically strong ones back ups.
Validate them.
Please updates apply.
Always, as I said is important because
it overrides any, eh, malware in the
core files,  folders, monitor your site.
You can use WPSane.com for example.
your site or use a file integrity scanner.
Normally the final stage, the scanner
is included in any security plugin, like
Wordfence or Securi  or all in one themes.
Themes.
. But install a WAF, this
is important as well.
WAF is probably the
best proactive measures.
You can start in your website.
It's something like if you go out and it's
raining, you're going to take a umbrella.
That's why I put the red icon there.
So the WAF is the same as you go online,
put that in front of your website.
So you can , it's going
to act as an umbrella.
And remember to invest
in hosting as security.
So, uh, we should have this in our mind
when we design a site that we have to
invest some money in hosting of security,
always by default in the beginning, so
I was saying, see everybody in a hacker.
I think hackers just improve
the curiosity of the human
being and they are obligated to.
make things always better in the, in the
world is not a lift the same as a bad
hacker  person, curious, which will help
a lot in the progress of the human being.
That's all guys.
Thanks a lot.
Hope, uh, this, uh, has of, up to
you guys and I open to questions.
Michelle: Yeah.
Néstor Angulo de Ugarte: Okay.
Well, thank you very much.
Michelle: It's a good to have you.
Yeah, your presentation was wonderful.
Uh, I'm not seeing a ton of questions.
I'm seeing everybody agreeing
with you, which was wonderful.
I think lots of people are saying yes,
functional backups, functional backups.
Néstor Angulo de Ugarte:
I have faced this.
I have faced this that lots of times
the customers say no, I have a backup.
Okay.
Share with me when I check it is
corrupt that, oh, it's only one half.
This is a pain, is a pain.
Michelle: I have it on
a thumb drive somewhere.
Néstor Angulo de Ugarte: Yeah.
That happened.
That happened to me as well, a customer
I would say something like, Hey, I have
a memory flash with a backup somewhere.
Yes.
Give me some days to
look at it and say, okay,
Michelle: I was speaking at WordCamp
Montreal one year, maybe five years ago.
And I was free.
This was back in my freelance days.
When I didn't know better
and made so many mistakes.
And as I'm driving to Montreal, I'm
getting all of these phone calls from
customers because I was using the
same hosting space for everybody.
So one customer got hacked and
it bled into 23 other websites.
And I'm in the middle of a six hour
drive and can do nothing, nothing to
like, and I didn't know what to do.
And so I, I went through and cleaned
up like 1300 files overnight.
And by the next day it was hacked
again, because I had no idea that
they just created their own users.
And I had to go in and delete the, oh
my gosh, it was the worst experience.
And I wish that on nobody.
Néstor Angulo de Ugarte: I
will there that will bear this.
Uh, that's what we call
cross site contamination.
That's why I mentioned the
two to remove all the backups.
And if you can also get all the
websites, separating insulate in your,
in your own server is the best way to
avoid this cross' site contamination.
Because even as you have a WAF, you
have, uh, any security thing or whatever.
It er it into her in a cross
site contamination situation.
They, they are useless because
they contamination goes from in.
So it's, it's impossible to stop
that, that you can guess monitor.
And you can just see the, the, you
know, the reports, if you have a file
triggered the scanner or something like
that saying, oh, there's a lot of files
that has been changed in the last hour.
Why then that's the only part that you
can just only expect that be a spectator.
Michelle: And they usually wait until
after 30 days until it fires so that
you don't have the backups on the host.
So you have to look for backups someplace
else, which is never, never fun.
And for this case, it was the CGI bin.
Like nobody looks in their CGI bin.
Right?
So like, it was, that's where
the, the original file was.
It's like I went through
and deleted all of that.
It was terrible.
Néstor Angulo de Ugarte: So
I was saying, damn not.world.
When the SSL certificates gets in, but
inside of that folder, there is a lot
of malware sometimes as well, because
it's a typical one that you don't know,
you don't check, but also because in
their file managers, you don't have
activated the dot visability files.
So the dot well known folder
is not visible, visible, so you
don't check it and get infected.
Michelle: It's not fun when that happens
and your customers do not like it.
Néstor Angulo de Ugarte: And especially
if you are in the middle, right.
and so on something like, oh, come
on, I have to deal with my anxiety
with the customer anxiety, and
then you have to deal with any,
any security team or something like
that to recover your, your status.
Michelle: But, but only a
person who works at a place like
Securi ends their presentation
with everybody needs a hacker.
Néstor Angulo de Ugarte: Yeah.
It's, it's something like, uh, you
know, personal campaign I would
like to, to doing, to encourage
people to these  curious right.
To, to go beyond, but the problem is, are
they going to beyond the laws is not the,
is not the point I'm trying to force.
Right.
That's why I made a distinction,
but the yes, I don't know.
I don't know.
I super fan of this kind of video of
five minutes of hackings something
and you know, they, they, they take
the cap of the bottles to do some
funny stuffs or they're using another.
totally blow your mind, uh,
situations, uh, something like that.
That for me, that's hacking as well and,
and I don't know, it's something personal
Michelle: having a good, um, a
good security plugin is good, but
you also have to make sure the
security plugin stays up to date.
So if you're not updating your
plugins and things like that,
you're running those risks as well.
Yeah.
Néstor Angulo de Ugarte: And the
people listen, understand why?
Because the, you know, Brian's updates
because they, they get new signature
Neo techniques discovered just
recently discovered to hack websites
or the most updated, the plugin you
have, uh, more able to get there.
The, you know, the, the intrusion
and faster to avoid that.
For example, the reputational harm.
Michelle: Yeah.
It's like shutting all the windows,
but leaving the front door open.
Néstor Angulo de Ugarte: I always
say that you can close everything in
your and yours and your house, but if
you leave her one, one window open?
It's useless.
Michelle: It doesn't matter.
That's right.
Ola, do you have any questions for
Néstor before I let let him go.
Olamideyelo: All right.
Just the mean, I think my favorite
part of the favorite part of the
session was, um, what you said about.
You know, there are two types
of companies, those who have
been hacked, and those who don't
know they have been hacked.
I mean, how will you not know
that you have been hacked?
So I, my question will be, I mean, you
you've said you you've said so much about,
um, updating plugins and all of that.
What, how often should.
The company, I mean, maybe small
organizations who can't really afford
the retainer services or the hackers.
How do they check?
You know, so is that, is that
a checklist or a timeline they
should check, um, security of dates
or functions of their websites?
Néstor Angulo de Ugarte: It depends.
There are some people that just check
it daily, some say you can use, for
example, this, site check to to check,
uh, if there's something wrong or you
have a hosting provider that makes these.
Performed these daily scans in your
website and so on, but it's nothing fixed.
It's something that's depending on you.
For me, it's important to
have a good maintenance and
a good maintenance includes.
For example, how to
have scan your website.
Eh, very often.
The faster, you, you, the detect,
these kind of things, the faster you
recover and the less harms, what I
always say, but, uh, for small companies
just using, for example,  site check
scanner, a have a Wordfence plugin
um, something like that.
If you are a skill enough, has
the WPSCAN running in your server?
It's  with that part, you, uh, Ready?
High, you have higher possibilities
to get the infection or intrusion,
or vulnerability a faster enough.
Michelle: Uh, Jenna had a question for
you from the  or from the, um, from the
chat there she says, would you recommend
storing a copy of the latest backup, both
in the cloud and on a physical device.
Néstor Angulo de Ugarte: I think from
my point of view, this is a little bit,
uh, uh, depending on the person, right?
Of the need, that's the
needs of the company.
Uh, I recommend having it in the cloud,
not the physical device, uh, because
the, the physical device can just, uh,
You know, can get damaged, can get lost
or whatever on the end, if you get lost,
for example, you are sharing with others.
Uh, what happened even if you
have, for example, a NAS network
access, storage or something like
that in your, in your network.
If it got, if it get hacked, it gets
all information as well of the backups.
So I normally recommend, I prefer
to rely in a cloud services and
this is my, my, from my part.
Truly, it's very redundant to have to
do this kind of backups, but it depends.
If you have a big company,
you have a lot of access.
It's very, very costly.
Uh, your needs to do assure
that they are working and.
So on you have in both places.
It's okay.
Michelle: Not too long ago.
I actually found one of the first
websites that I built on three
and a half inch floppy disks.
What do you think of that?
Néstor Angulo de Ugarte:
Floppy disks, come on?
How many, how many floppy disks?
Michelle: This for like four or five?
Néstor Angulo de Ugarte: Well, I
would say not to put your mobile phone
near to them, something like that
because the end is magnetized, right?
Michelle: Yeah.
Three and a half inch floppy.
It was I, yes, I'm old,
but also very funny.
It was from my classes 20 years ago.
Yeah,
Néstor Angulo de Ugarte: Probably, if
we know about that, there are probably
people in the, in the audience that
they don't know actually, but the
floppy disks is what the problems
we had with those floppy disks.
Michelle: And you don't
know what they are.
Go Google.
We're not going to explain any more.
Néstor Angulo de Ugarte: Yeah, for sure.
I remember the big ones.
The 3.5, not the dead second, 2.5.
Yeah.
Michelle: The five inch, five and
a half inch or five and a quarter.
Oh, that's so funny.
Well, thank you so much for being with us.
It was wonderful, especially to
hear you talk live and to have
the great conversation with you.
Um, Ola you want to read
our thanks for our sponsors.
Olamideyelo: Um, thank you.
Thank you.
So thank you, please make
sure that I'm well, thanks.
Well, thank all.
Thanks to our sponsors.
Bluehost, Cloudways, GoDaddy
Pro, Nexcess, Yoast , Weglot.
Please be sure to visit their
tents and chat with them.
We might event have have
some giveaways, some prizes.
Yeah.
I'm all for the prizes.
But also don't forget to get photo
snapped, I just shared mine on Twitter.
So make sure you engage, get your photo
snaps in the portal booth and share tweet
it at us with the WordFest live, hashtag.
And also thank you to our media
partners and our micro sponsors.
We're grateful to everyone of
you and also in the community.
The community tent is
up for the next hour.
So make sure you go there,
network, meet other people, check
sites and news and cloudways
have their hourly giveaway would
associate with a special guest activity.
You don't want to miss that.
So we're right back, Michelle, is there
anything you want to add or is there that,
Michelle: yeah.
And so on the next hour, so as we hit
the next, at the top of the next hour,
we're going to be into our lightning
talks for this round, with Imran Sayed.
And Suresha N, and, and so he
will see you back here on a
stage two at that point in time.